<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
                         "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="admin_guide">
    <title>Administration Guide</title>
    <abstract>
        <para>This chapter describes the phpBB 3.0 admin controls.</para>
    </abstract>
    <section id="admin_control_panel">
        <sectioninfo>
            <authorgroup>
                <author>
                    <othername>dhn</othername>
                </author>
            </authorgroup>
        </sectioninfo>
        <title>The Administration Control Panel</title>
        <para>Even more so than its predecessor phpBB 3.0 Olympus is highly configurable. You can
            tune, adjust, or turn off almost all features. To make this load of settings as
            accessible as possible, we redesigned the Administration Control Panel (ACP) completely. </para>
        <para>Click on the "Administration Control Panel" link on the bottom of the default forum
            style to visit the ACP. TODO: Screenshot</para>
        <para>The Admin Control Panel has seven different sections by default with each containing a
            number of subsections. We will discuss each section in this Admin Guide. </para>
        <para>TODO: Screenshot and explanation of the layout</para>
    </section>
    <section id="acp_general">
        <sectioninfo>
            <authorgroup>
                <author>
                    <othername>dhn</othername>
                </author>
            </authorgroup>
        </sectioninfo>
        <title>General Configuration and Front Page</title>
        <para>The General section is the first screen you see each time you log into the Admin
            Control Panel. It contains some basic statistics and information about your forum. It
            also has a subsection called "Quick Access". It provides a quick access to some of the
            more often visited admin pages like <link linkend="acp_usergroups">User
            Management</link> or <link linkend="acp_maintenance">Moderator Logs</link>. We will
            discuss its items later in their specific sections.</para>
        <para>We will concentrate on the other three subsections: Board Configuration, Client
            Communication, and Server Configuration.</para>
        <section id="acp_general_board">
            <sectioninfo>
                <authorgroup>
                    <author>
                        <othername>dhn</othername>
                    </author>
                </authorgroup>
            </sectioninfo>
            <title>Board Configuration</title>
            <para>This subsection contains items to adjust the overall features and settings of the
                forum. </para>
            <section id="acp_general_settings">
                <sectioninfo>
                    <authorgroup>
                        <author>
                            <othername>dhn</othername>
                        </author>
                    </authorgroup>
                </sectioninfo>
                <title>Board Settings</title>
                <para>The <guimenuitem>Board Settings</guimenuitem> allow you to change the most
                    important setting of your forum installation: the name of your forum. Put the
                    name on your site into the <guilabel>Site Name</guilabel> text field and it will
                    be shown on the header of the default style and will be the prefix to the window
                    title of your browser.</para>
                <para>The <guilabel>Site Description</guilabel> is the slogan or tag line of your
                    forum. It will appear below the <guilabel>Site Name</guilabel> on the default
                    style's header.</para>
                <para>If you need to close your whole forum to do maintenance work, for instance,
                    you can do it by using the <guilabel>Disable Board</guilabel> switch. This will
                    keep any members of your forum that are not Administrators or Moderators unable
                    from accessing the board. They will either see a default message instead of the
                    forum or you can add your own one in the text field below the check boxes.
                    Administrators and Moderators will still be able to browse forums and use their
                    specific control panels.</para>
                <para>You need to set the <guilabel>Default Language</guilabel> of your board. This
                    is the language guests will see when they visit the board. You can allow users
                    to choose other languages. By default there is only <guilabel>English
                    [UK]</guilabel> installed but you can <ulink
                        url="http://www.phpbb.com/languages">download more languages on the phpBB
                        website</ulink>. Find out more about working with languages in the <link
                        linkend="acp_system">Language Pack configuration</link>.</para>
                <para>TODO: Write about date format and timezone, may change, so leaving this out
                    for now.</para>
                <para>The board will appear to your guests and members in the <guilabel>Default
                        Style</guilabel>. In the standard phpBB installtion two Styles are available
                    (TODO: write more about them?). You can either allow users to select another
                    Style than the default by selecting <guilabel>No</guilabel> in the
                        <guilabel>Override User Style</guilabel> setting or disallow it. Please
                    visit the <link linkend="acp_styles">Styles section</link> to find out how to
                    add new Styles and where to find them.</para>
                <para>Moderators can send warnings to users that break the forum rules. The value of
                        <guilabel>Warning Duration</guilabel> defines the number of days a warning
                    is valid until it expires. Read more about warnings in the Moderator Control
                    Panel. TODO: Add link to this section.</para>
            </section>
            <section id="acp_board_features">
                <sectioninfo>
                    <authorgroup>
                        <author>
                            <othername>dhn</othername>
                        </author>
                    </authorgroup>
                </sectioninfo>
                <title>Board Features</title>
                <para>Through the <guimenuitem>Board Features</guimenuitem> section you can enable
                    or disable several features board-wide. Note that any feature you disable here
                    will not be available on your forum, even if you give your users permissions to
                    use them.</para>
            </section>
            <section id="acp_board_attachments">
                <sectioninfo>
                    <authorgroup>
                        <author>
                            <othername>dhn</othername>
                        </author>
                    </authorgroup>
                </sectioninfo>
                <title>Attachment Settings</title>
                <para>TODO: Write about attachment settings.</para>
            </section>
            <section id="acp_board_avatars">
                <sectioninfo>
                    <authorgroup>
                        <author>
                            <othername>dhn</othername>
                        </author>
                    </authorgroup>
                </sectioninfo>
                <title>Avatar Settings</title>
                <para>Avatars are generally small, unique images a user can associate with
                    themselves. Depending on the style they are usually displayed below the user
                    name when viewing topics. Here you can determine how users can define their
                    avatars.</para>
                <para>There are three different ways a user can add an avatar to their profile. The
                    first way is through an avatar gallery you provide. Note, that there is no
                    avatar gallery available in a default phpBB installation. The <guilabel>Avatar
                        Gallery Path</guilabel> is the path to the gallery images. The default path
                    is <guilabel>images/avatars/gallery</guilabel>. The gallery folder does not
                    exist in the default installation so you have to add it manually if you want to
                    use it.</para>
                <para>The images you want to use for your gallery need to be in a folder inside the
                    gallery path. Images directly in the gallery path won't be recognised. There is
                    also no support for sub folders inside the gallery folder. </para>
                <para>The second approach to avatars is through <guilabel>Remote Avatars</guilabel>.
                    This are simply images linked from another website. Your members can add a link
                    to the image they want to use in their profile. To give you some control over
                    the size of the avatars you can define the minimum and maximum size of the
                    images. The disadvantage of <guilabel>Remote Avatars</guilabel> is that you are
                    not able to control the file size.</para>
                <para>The third approach to avatars is through <guilabel>Avatar
                    Uploading</guilabel>. Your members can upload an image form their local system
                    which will be stored on your server. They will be uploaded into the
                        <guilabel>Avatar Storage Path</guilabel> you can define. The default path is
                        <guilabel>images/avatars/upload</guilabel> abd does already exist after
                    installation. You have to make sure that it is server writeable (TODO: a link to
                    a FAQ that explains this). The file format of the images has to be either gif,
                    jpeg, or png, and the avatars will be automatically checked for their file and
                    image size after the upload. You can adjust the <guilabel>Maximum Avatar File
                        Size</guilabel> and images that are bigger than the allowed value will be
                    discarded.</para>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>

    <section id="acp_forums">
        <sectioninfo>
            <authorgroup>
                <author>
                    <othername>dhn</othername>
                </author>
            </authorgroup>
        </sectioninfo>
        <title>Forum Admin</title>
        <para>TODO: Stuff about forum admin</para>
    </section>

    <section id="acp_posting">
        <sectioninfo>
            <authorgroup>
                <author>
                    <othername>dhn</othername>
                </author>
            </authorgroup>
        </sectioninfo>
        <title>Posting Settings</title>
        <para>TODO: Stuff about the posting settings</para>
    </section>

    <section id="acp_usergroups">
        <sectioninfo>
            <authorgroup>
                <author>
                    <othername>dhn</othername>
                </author>
            </authorgroup>
        </sectioninfo>
        <title>Users and Groups Management</title>
        <para>TODO: Stuff about users and groups</para>
    </section>

    <section id="acp_permissions">
        <sectioninfo>
            <authorgroup>
                <author>
                    <othername>dhn</othername>
                </author>
            </authorgroup>
        </sectioninfo>
        <title>Permission Overload</title>
        <para>TODO: Stuff about permissions</para>
    </section>

    <section id="acp_styles">
        <sectioninfo>
            <authorgroup>
                <author>
                    <othername>dhn</othername>
                </author>
            </authorgroup>
        </sectioninfo>
        <title>Styles</title>
        <para>TODO: Stuff about Styles</para>
    </section>

    <section id="acp_maintenance">
        <sectioninfo>
            <authorgroup>
                <author>
                    <othername>dhn</othername>
                </author>
            </authorgroup>
        </sectioninfo>
        <title>Board Maintenance</title>
        <para>TODO: Stuff about maintenance</para>
    </section>

    <section id="acp_system">
        <sectioninfo>
            <authorgroup>
                <author>
                    <othername>dhn</othername>
                </author>
            </authorgroup>
        </sectioninfo>
        <title>System Configuration</title>
        <para>TODO: Stuff about system configuration</para>
    </section>
</chapter>
