<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
                         "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="admin_guide">
	<?dbhtml dir="adminguide" filename="index.html" ?>
	<chapterinfo>
		<releaseinfo>$Id$</releaseinfo>
		<copyright>
			<year>2006</year>
			<holder>phpBB Group</holder>
		</copyright>
	</chapterinfo>
	<title>Administration Guide</title>
	<abstract>
		<para>This chapter describes the phpBB 3.0 admin controls.</para>
	</abstract>
	<section id="admin_control_panel">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>The Administration Control Panel</title>
		<para>Even more so than its predecessor, phpBB 3.0 Olympus is highly configurable. You can tune, adjust, or turn off almost all features. To make this load of settings as accessible as possible, we redesigned the Administration Control Panel (ACP) completely. </para>
		<para>Click on the "Administration Control Panel" link on the bottom of the default forum style to visit the ACP. TODO: Screenshot</para>
		<para>The Admin Control Panel has seven different sections by default with each containing a number of subsections. We will discuss each section in this Admin Guide. </para>
		<para>TODO: Screenshot and explanation of the layout</para>
	</section>
	<section id="acp_general">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>General Configuration and Front Page</title>
		<para>The General section is the first screen you see each time you log into the Admin Control Panel. It contains some basic statistics and information about your forum. It also has a subsection called <guimenuitem>Quick Access</guimenuitem>. It provides a quick access to some of the more often visited admin pages like <link linkend="acp_users">User Management</link> or <link linkend="acp_maintenance">Moderator Logs</link>. We will discuss its items later in their specific sections.</para>
		<para>We will concentrate on the other three subsections: <link linkend="acp_general_board">Board Configuration</link>, <link linkend="acp_general_client">Client Communication</link>, and <link linkend="acp_general_server">Server Configuration</link>.</para>
		<section id="acp_general_config">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>dhn</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Board Configuration</title>
			<para>This subsection contains items to adjust the overall features and settings of the forum. </para>
			<section id="acp_general_settings">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>dhn</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Board Settings</title>
				<para>The <guimenuitem>Board Settings</guimenuitem> allow you to change the most important setting of your forum installation: the name of your forum. Put the name of your site into the <guilabel>Site Name</guilabel> text field and it will be shown on the header of the default style and will be the prefix to the window title of your browser.</para>
				<para>The <guilabel>Site Description</guilabel> is the slogan or tag line of your forum. It will appear below the <guilabel>Site Name</guilabel> on the default style's header.</para>
				<para>If you need to close your whole forum to do maintenance work, for instance, you can do it by using the <guilabel>Disable Board</guilabel> switch. This will keep any members of your forum that are not Administrators or Moderators from accessing the board. They will either see a default message instead of the forum or you can add your own message in the text field below the check boxes. Administrators and Moderators will still be able to browse forums and use their specific control panels.</para>
				<para>You need to set the <guilabel>Default Language</guilabel> of your board. This is the language guests will see when they visit the board. You can allow users to choose other languages. By default there is only <guilabel>English [UK]</guilabel> installed but you can <ulink url="http://www.phpbb.com/languages">download more languages on the phpBB website</ulink>. Find out more about working with languages in the <link linkend="acp_system">Language Pack configuration</link>.</para>
				<para>TODO: Write about date format and timezone, may change, so leaving this out for now.</para>
				<para>The board will appear to your guests and members in the <guilabel>Default Style</guilabel>. In the standard phpBB installation two Styles are available (TODO: write more about them?). You can either allow users to select another Style than the default by selecting <guilabel>No</guilabel> in the <guilabel>Override User Style</guilabel> setting or disallow it. Please visit the <link linkend="acp_styles">Styles section</link> to find out how to add new Styles and where to find them.</para>
				<para>Moderators can send warnings to users that break the forum rules. The value of <guilabel>Warning Duration</guilabel> defines the number of days a warning is valid until it expires. Read more about warnings in the Moderator Control Panel. TODO: Add link to this section.</para>
			</section>
			<section id="acp_board_features">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>dhn</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Board Features</title>
				<para>Through the <guimenuitem>Board Features</guimenuitem> section you can enable or disable several features board-wide. Note that any feature you disable here will not be available on your forum, even if you give your users permissions to use them.</para>
			</section>
			<section id="acp_board_attachments">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>dhn</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Attachment Settings</title>
				<para>One of the many new  features in Olympus is Attachments.</para>
			</section>
			<section id="acp_board_avatars">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>dhn</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Avatar Settings</title>
				<para>Avatars are generally small, unique images a user can associate with themselves. Depending on the style they are usually displayed below the user name when viewing topics. Here you can determine how users can define their avatars.</para>
				<para>There are three different ways a user can add an avatar to their profile. The first way is through an avatar gallery you provide. Note, that there is no avatar gallery available in a default phpBB installation. The <guilabel>Avatar Gallery Path</guilabel> is the path to the gallery images. The default path is <guilabel>images/avatars/gallery</guilabel>. The gallery folder does not exist in the default installation so you have to add it manually if you want to use it.</para>
				<para>The images you want to use for your gallery need to be in a folder inside the gallery path. Images directly in the gallery path won't be recognised. There is also no support for sub folders inside the gallery folder. </para>
				<para>The second approach to avatars is through <guilabel>Remote Avatars</guilabel>. This are simply images linked from another website. Your members can add a link to the image they want to use in their profile. To give you some control over the size of the avatars you can define the minimum and maximum size of the images. The disadvantage of <guilabel>Remote Avatars</guilabel> is that you are not able to control the file size.</para>
				<para>The third approach to avatars is through <guilabel>Avatar Uploading</guilabel>. Your members can upload an image form their local system which will be stored on your server. They will be uploaded into the <guilabel>Avatar Storage Path</guilabel> you can define. The default path is <guilabel>images/avatars/upload</guilabel> and does already exist after installation. You have to make sure that it is server writable (TODO: a link to a FAQ that explains this). The file format of the images has to be either gif, jpeg, or png, and the avatars will be automatically checked for their file and image size after the upload. You can adjust the <guilabel>Maximum Avatar File Size</guilabel> and images that are bigger than the allowed value will be discarded.</para>
			</section>
			<section id="acp_board_pms">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>dhn</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Private Messaging</title>
				<para> Private Messages are a way for registered members to communicate privately through your board without the need to fall back to e-mail or instant messaging. </para>
				<para> You can disable this feature with the <guilabel>Private Messaging</guilabel> setting. This will keep the feature turned off for the whole board. You can disable Private Messages for selected users or groups with <link linkend="acp_permissions">Permissions</link>. Please see the <link linkend="acp_permissions">Permissions section</link> for more information. </para>
				<para> Olympus allows users to create own personal folders to organise Private Messages. The <guilabel>Max Private Messages Per Box</guilabel> setting defines the number of message folders they can create. The default value is 4. You can disable the feature with setting value to 0. </para>
				<para>
					<guilabel>Max Private Messages Per Box</guilabel> sets the number of Private Messages each folder can contain. The default value is <guilabel>50</guilabel>, Set it to 0 to allow unlimited messages per folder. </para>
				<para> If you limit the number of messages users can store in their folders, you need to define a default action that is taken once a folder is full. This can be changed in the "Full Folder Default Action" list. The oldest message gets deleted or the new message will be held back until the folder has place for it. Note that users will be able to choose this for themselves in their PM options and this setting only changes the default value they face. This will not override the action a user chosen. </para>
				<para> When sending a Private Message it is still possible to edit the message until the recipient reads it. After it was read, editing the message is no longer possible. To limit the time a message can be edited before the recipient reads it, you can set the <guilabel>Limit Editing Time</guilabel>. The default value is 0 which allows editing until the message is read. Note that you can disallow users or groups to edit Private Messages after sending through <link linkend="acp_permissions">Permissions</link>. If the permission to edit messages is denied, it will override this setting. </para>
				<para>The <guilabel>General Options</guilabel> allow you to further define the functionality of Private Messages on your board. 
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para><guilabel>Allow Mass PMs:</guilabel> enables the sending of Private Messages to multiple recipients. This feature is enabled by default. Disabling it will also disallow sending of Private Messages to groups. </para>
							<tip>
								<para>See the <link linkend="acp_groups">Groups section</link> for information on how to enable the ability to send a message to a whole group.</para>
							</tip>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>By default <glossterm>BBCode</glossterm> and <glossterm>Smilies</glossterm> are allowed in Private Messages.</para>
							<tip>
								<para>Even if enabled, you can still disallow users or groups to use <glossterm>BBCode</glossterm> and <glossterm>Smilies</glossterm> in Private Messages through <link linkend="acp_permissions">Permissions</link>.</para>
							</tip>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>We don't allow attachments by default. Further settings for attachments in Private Messages are in the <link linkend="acp_board_attachments">Attachment Settings</link>. There you can define the number of attachments per message for instance.</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_general_client">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>dhn</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>			
			<title>Client communication</title>
			<para>TODO: Stuff about client communication</para>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_general_server">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>dhn</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>			
			<title>Server configuration</title>
			<para>TODO: Stuff about server configuration</para>
		</section>		
	</section>
	<section id="acp_forums">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Forum Admin</title>
		<para>The <guilabel>Forum</guilabel> section offers the tools to manage your forums. Whether you want to add new forums, add new categories, change forum descriptions, reorder or rename your forums, this is the place to go.</para>
		<section id="acp_forums_types">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>dhn</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Explanation of forum types</title>
			<para>In Olympus there are three forum types. A forum can be a normal forum where people can post in, it can be a category that contains forums, or it can be a simple link.</para>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Forum</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>In a forum people can post their topics.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Link</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>The forum list displays a forum link like a normal forum. But instead of linking to a forum, you can point it  to a URL of your choice. It can display a hit counter, which shows how many times the link was clicked.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Category</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>If you want to combine multiple forums or links for a specific topic, you can put them inside a category. The forums will appear below the category title, clearly separated from other categories. Users are not able to post inside categories.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>				
			</variablelist>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_forums_subforums">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>dhn</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Sub-forums</title>
			<para>One of the many new features in Olympus are sub-forums. Especially bulletin boards with a high number of forums will benefit from this. In the simple flat category and forum approach in phpBB 2.0, all forums and categories were listed on the forum index. In Olympus you can now put as many forums, links, or categories as you like inside other forums. (TODO: Diagram of a 2.0 / 3.0 comparison)</para>
			<para>If you have a forum about pets for instance, you are able to put sub-forums for cats, dogs, or guinea pigs inside it without making the parent "Pets" forum a category.  In this example, only the "Pets" forum will be listed on the index like a normal forum. Its sub-forums will appear as simple links below the forum description (unless you disabled this). (TODO: Screenshot) </para>
			<para>This system does allow (theoretically) unlimited levels of sub-forums. You can put as many sub-forums inside sub-forums as you like, or at least make sense. But please do not go overboard with this feature. On boards with five to ten forums or less, it is not a good idea to use sub-forums. Remember, the less forums you have, the more active your forum will appear. You can always add more forums later.</para>
			<para>Read the <link linkend="acp_forums_manage">section on forum management</link> to find out how to create sub-forums.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_forums_manage">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>dhn</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Manage forums</title>
			<para>Here you can add, edit, delete, and reorder the forums, categories, and links. (TODO: Icon legend)</para>
			<para>The initial <guilabel>Manage forums</guilabel> page shows you a list of your top level forums and categories. Note, that this is not analogue to the forum index, as categories are not expanded here. So if you want to reorder the forums inside a category, you have to open the category first.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="acp_posting">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Posting Settings</title>
		<para>TODO: Stuff about the posting settings</para>
	</section>

	<section id="acp_users">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
				
				<author>
					<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>User management</title>
		<section id="acp_users_manage">
			<title>Manage Users</title>
			<para>Users are the basis of your forum. As a forum administrator, it is very important to be able to manage your users. Managing your users and their information and specific options is easy, and can be done via the <acronym>ACP</acronym>.</para>
				
			<para>To begin, log in and reach your <acronym>ACP</acronym>. Find and click on <guimenuitem>Users and Groups</guimenuitem>  to reach the necessary page. If you do not see <guimenuitem>User Administration</guimenuitem> , simply find and click on <guimenuitem>Manage Users</guimenuitem> in the navigation menu on the left side of the page.</para>
				
			<para>To continue and manage a user, you must know the username(s) that you want to manage. In the textbox for the <guilabel>"Find a member:"</guilabel> field, type in the username of the user whose information and settings you wish to manage. On the other hand, if you want to find a member, click on <guilabel>[ Find a Member ]</guilabel> (which is below the textbox) and follow all the steps appropriate to find and select a user. If you wiant to manage the information and settings for the Anonymous user (any visitor who is not logged in is set as the Anonymous user), check the checkbox labeled <guilabel>"Select Anonymous User"</guilabel>. Once you have selected a user, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>.</para>
				
			<para>There are many sections relating to a user's settings. The following are subsections containing further information  on each form. Each form allows you to manage specific settings for the user you have selected. When you are done with editing the data on each form, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>  (located at the bottom of each form) to submit your changes.</para>
			
			<section id="acp_users_manage_overview">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>User Overview</title>
				<para>This is the first form that shows up when you first select a user to manage. Here, all of the general information and settings for each user is displayed.</para>
				
				<variablelist>
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Username</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This is the name of the user you're currently managing. If you want to change the user's username, type in a new username between three and twenty characters long into the textbox labeled <guilabel>Username:</guilabel></para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Registered</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This is the complete date on which the user registered. You cannot edit this value.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Registered from IP</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This is the <acronym>IP</acronym> address from which the user registered his or her account. If you want to determine the <acronym>IP</acronym> hostname, click on the <acronym>IP</acronym> address itself. The current page will reload and will display the appropriate information. If you want to perform a whois on the <acronym>IP</acronym> address, click on the <guilabel>Whois</guilabel> link. A new window will pop up with this data.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Last Active</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This is the complete date on which the user was last active.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Founder</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>Founders are users who have all administrator permissions and can never be banned, deleted or altered by non-founder members. If you want to set this user as a founder, select the <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> radio button. To remove founder status from a user, select the <guilabel>No</guilabel> radio button.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Email</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This is the user's currently set email address. To change the email address, fill in the <guilabel>Email:</guilabel> textbox with a valid email.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Confirm email address</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This textbox should only be filled if you are changing the user's email address. If you are changing the email address, both the <guilabel>Email:</guilabel> textbox and this one should be filled with the same email address. If you do not fill this in, the user's email address will not be changed.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>New password</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>As an administrator, you cannot see any of your users' password. However, it is possible to change passwords. To change the user's password, type in a new password in the <guilabel>New password:</guilabel> textbox. The new password has to be between six and thirty characters long.</para>
						
							<important><para>Before submitting any changes to the user, make sure this field is blank, unless you really want to change the user's password. If you accidentally change the user's password, the original password cannot be recovered!</para></important>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Confirm new password</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This textbox should only be filled if you are changing the user's password. If you are changing the user's password, the <guilabel>Confirm new password:</guilabel> textbox needs to be filled in with the same password you filled in in the above <guilabel>New password:</guilabel> textbox.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Warnings</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This is the number of warnings the user currently has. You can edit this number by typing in a number into the <guilabel>Warnings:</guilabel> number field. Only positive integers are allowed.</para>
							<para>For more information about warnings, see <link linkend="mcp_warnings">Section x.x Warnings</link>.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Quick Tools</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>The options in the <guilabel>Quick Tools</guilabel> drop-down selection box allow you to quickly and easily change one of the user's options. The available options are <guilabel>Delete Signature</guilabel>, <guilabel>Delete Avatar</guilabel>, <guilabel>Move all Posts</guilabel>, <guilabel>Delete all Posts</guilabel>, and <guilabel>Delete all attachments</guilabel>.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
				</variablelist>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_users_manage_feedback">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>User Feedback</title>
				<para>Another aspect of managing a user is editing their feedback data. Feedback consists of any sort of user warning issued to the user by a forum administrator.</para>
				
				<para>To customise the display of the user's existing log entries, select any criteria for your customisation by selecting your options in the drop-down selection boxes entitled <guilabel>Display entries from previous:</guilabel> and <guilabel>Sort by:</guilabel>. <guilabel>Display entries from previous:</guilabel> allows you to set a specific time period in which the feedback was issued.  <guilabel>Sort by:</guilabel> allows you to sort the existing log entries by <guimenuitem>Username</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Date</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>IP address</guimenuitem>, and <guimenuitem>Log Action</guimenuitem>. The log entries can then be sorted in ascending or descending order. When you are done setting these options, click the <guilabel>Go</guilabel> button to update the page with your customisations.</para>
			
				<para>Another way of managing a user's feedback data is by adding feedback. Simply find the section entitled <guilabel>Add feedback</guilabel> and enter your message into the <guilabel>FEEDBACK</guilabel> text area. When you are done, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> to add the feedback.</para>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_users_manage_profile">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>User Profile</title>
				
				<para>Users may sometimes have content in their forum profile that requires that you either update it or delete it. If you don't want to change a field, leave it blank.The following are the profile fields that you can change:
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>ICQ Number:</guilabel> has to be a number at least three digits long.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>AOL Instant Messenger:</guilabel> can have any alphanumeric characters and symbols.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>MSN Messenger:</guilabel> can have any alphanumeric characters, but should look similar to an email address (x@x.tld).</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Yahoo Messenger:</guilabel> can have any alphanumeric characters and symbols.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Jabber address:</guilabel> can have any alphanumeric characters, but needs to look like an email address would (x@x.tld).</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Website:</guilabel> can have any alphanumeric characters and symbols, but must have the protocol included (ex. http://).</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Location:</guilabel> can have any alphanumeric characters and symbols.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Occupation:</guilabel> can have any alphanumeric characters and symbols.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Interests:</guilabel> can have any alphanumeric characters and symbols.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Birthday:</guilabel> can be set with three different drop-down selection boxes: <guilabel>Day:</guilabel>, <guilabel>Month:</guilabel>, and <guilabel>Year:</guilabel>, respectively. Setting a year will list the user's age when it is his or her birthday.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_users_inactive">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>Graham</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Inactive Users</title>
			<para>Here you are able to view details of all users who are currently marked as inactive along with the reason their account is marked as inactive and when this occurred.</para>
			<para>Using the checkboxes on this page it is possible to perform bulk actions on the users, these include activating the accounts, sending them a reminder email indicating that they need to activate their account or deleting the account.</para>
			<para>There are 5 reasons which may be indicated for an account being inactive:</para>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Account deactivated by administrator</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>This account has been manually deactivated by an administrator via the <link linkend="acp_users_manage">user management tools</link>. More details on who performed this action and the reasons may be available via the User Notes.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Profile details changed</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>The board is configured to require user activation and this user has changed key information related to their account such as the email address and is required to reactivate the account to confirm these changes.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Newly registered account</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>The board is configured to require user activation and either the user or an administrator (depending on the settings) has not yet activated this new account.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Forced user account reactivation</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>An administrator has forced this user to reactivate their account via the <link linkend="acp_users_manage">user management tools</link>. More details on who performed this action and the reasons may be available via the User Notes.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Unknown</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>No reason was recorded for this user being inactive; it is likely that the change was made by an external application or that this user was added from another source.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="acp_groups">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Group management</title>
		<para>TODO: Stuff about users and groups</para>
		<section id="acp_groups_types">
			<title>Group types</title>
			<para>There are two types of groups:</para>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Pre-defined groups</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>These are groups that are available by default in phpBB 3.0. You <emphasis>cannot</emphasis> delete them, as the board needs them for various features. You can still change their attributes (description, colour, rank, avatar and so forth) and group leaders. Users that register to your board are automatically added to the predefined group "Registered Users", for instance. Do not try to remove them manually through the database, or your board will no longer function properly. </para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>User defined groups</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>The groups you create by yourself are called "User defined groups". These groups are similar to groups in 2.0. You may create as many as you want, remove them, set group leaders, and change their attributes (description, colour, rank, avatar, and so forth).</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
			<para>The "Manage groups" section in the "Administrator Control Panel" shows you separated lists of both your "User defined groups" and the "Pre-defined groups".</para>
<!-- TODO: LIST OF ALL PRE-DEFINED GROUPS AND THEIR FUNCTION -->
			
		</section>
		<section id="acp_groups_edit">
			<title>Group attributes</title>
			<para>A list of attributes a group can have:</para>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group name</term>
					<listitem><para>The name of your group.</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group description</term>
					<listitem><para>The description of the group that will be displayed on the group overview list..</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry id="acp_groups_edit_legend">
					<term>Display group in legend:</term>
					<listitem><para>This will enable the display of  the name of the group in the legend of the "Who is Online" list. Note, that this will only make sense if you specified a colour for the group.</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group able to receive private messages</term>
					<listitem><para>This will allow the sending of Private Messages to this group. Please note, that it can be dangerous to allow this for Registered Users, for instance. There is no permission to deny the sending to groups, so anyone who is able to send Private Messages will be able to send a message to this group!</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group private message limit per folder</term>
					<listitem><para>This setting overrides the per-user folder message limit. A value of 0 means the user default limit will be used. <!-- TODO: ADD LINK TO PM SETTINGS --></para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group colour</term>
					<listitem><para>The name of members that have this group as their default group (see <xref linkend="acp_groups_default"/>) will be displayed in this colour on all forum pages. If you enable <link linkend="acp_groups_edit_legend"><guilabel>Display group in legend</guilabel></link>, an legend entry with the same colour will appear below the "Who is Online" listing.</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group rank</term>
					<listitem><para>A member that has this group as the default group (see <xref linkend="acp_groups_default"/>) will have this rank below his username. Note, that you can change the rank of this member  to a different one that overrides the group setting.<!-- TODO: ADD LINK TO RANK SETTINGS --></para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group avatar</term>
					<listitem><para>A member that has this group as the default group (see <xref linkend="acp_groups_default"/>) will use this avatar. Note, that a member can change his avatar to a different one, if he has the permission to do so.<!-- TODO: ADD LINK TO AVATAR SETTINGS --></para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>				
			</variablelist>
			
		</section>
		<section id="acp_groups_default">
			<title>Default groups</title>
			<para>As it is now possible to assign attributes like colours or avatars to groups (see <xref linkend="acp_groups_edit" />, it can happen that a user is a member of two or more different groups that have different avatars or other attributes. So, which avatar will the user now inherit? </para>
			<para>To overcome this problem, you are able to assign each user exactly one "Default group". The user will only inherit the attributes of this group. Note, that it is not possible to mix attributes: If one group has a rank but no avatar, and another group has only a avatar, it is not possible to display the avatar from one group and the rank from the other group. You have to decide for one "Default group".</para>
			<important><para>Default groups have no influence on permissions. There is no added permissions bonus for your default group, so a user's permissions will stay the same, no matter what group is his default one.</para></important>
			<para>You can change default groups in two ways. Either through the user management (see <xref linkend="acp_users"/>) <!-- TODO: LINK  TO MANAGE USERS /--> or directly through the groups management (<guilabel>Manage groups</guilabel>). Please be careful with the second option, as when you change the default group through a group directly, this will change the default group for <emphasis>all</emphasis> its group members and overwrite their old default groups. So, if you change the default group for the "Registered Users" group by using the <guilabel>Default</guilabel> link, all members of your forum will have this group as their default one, even members of the Administrators and Moderators groups as they are also members of "Registered Users".</para>
			<important><para>If you make a group the default one that has a rank and avatar set, the user's old avatar and rank will be overwritten by the group.</para></important>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="acp_permissions">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Permission Overload</title>
		<para>TODO: Stuff about permissions</para>
	</section>

	<section id="acp_styles">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Styles</title>
		<para>TODO: Stuff about Styles</para>
	</section>

	<section id="acp_maintenance">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Board Maintenance</title>
		<para>TODO: Stuff about maintenance</para>
		<section id="acp_maintenance_logs">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>Graham</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Forum Logs</title>
			<para>The <guilabel>Forum Log</guilabel> section of the administration panel provdes an overview of what has been happening on the board. There are four types of logs:</para>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Admin Log</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>This log records all actions carried out within the administration panel itself.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Moderator Log</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>This logs records the actions performed by moderators of your board. Whenever a topic is moved or locked it will be recorded here, allowing you to see who carried out a particular action.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>User Log</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>This log records all important actions carried out either by users or on users. All email and password changes are recorded within this log.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Error Log</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>This log shows you any errors arising out of actions taken by the board itself, such as errors sending emails. If you are having problems with a particular feature not working, this log is a good place to start. If enabled, addtional debugging information may be written to this log.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
			<para>If you have appropriate permissions, you are able to remove any or all log entries from the above sections.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_maintenance_database">
			<title>Database backup and restore</title>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_maintenance_search">
			<title>Search Indexing</title>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="acp_system">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>System Configuration</title>
		<para>TODO: Stuff about system configuration</para>
		<section id="acp_system_updates">
			<title>Checking for updates</title>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_system_spiders">
			<title>Managing Search Robots</title>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_system_mail">
			<title>Mass email</title>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_system_language">
			<title>Language Packs</title>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_system_phpinfo">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>Graham</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>PHP Information</title>
			<para>This option will provide you with information about the version of PHP installed on your server, along with information on loaded modules and the configuration applicable to the current location. This information can be useful to phpBB team members in helping you to diagnose problems affecting your installation of phpBB. The information here can be security sensitive and it is recommended that you only grant access to this option to those users who need access to the information and do not disclose the information unless necessary.</para>
			<para>Please note that some hosting providers may limit the information which is available to you on this page for security reasons.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_system_reports">
			<title>Manage reasons for reporting and denying posts</title>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_system_modules">
			<title>Module Management</title>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
