<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
                         "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="admin_guide">
	<?dbhtml dir="adminguide" filename="index.html" ?>
	<chapterinfo>
		<releaseinfo>$Id$</releaseinfo>
		<copyright>
			<year>2006</year>
			<holder>phpBB Group</holder>
		</copyright>
	</chapterinfo>
	<title>Administration Guide</title>
	<abstract>
		<para>This chapter describes the phpBB 3.0 admin controls.</para>
	</abstract>
	<section id="admin_control_panel">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>The Administration Control Panel</title>
		<para>Even more so than its predecessor phpBB 3.0 Olympus is highly configurable. You can tune, adjust, or turn off almost all features. To make this load of settings as accessible as possible, we redesigned the Administration Control Panel (ACP) completely. </para>
		<para>Click on the "Administration Control Panel" link on the bottom of the default forum style to visit the ACP. TODO: Screenshot</para>
		<para>The Admin Control Panel has seven different sections by default with each containing a number of subsections. We will discuss each section in this Admin Guide. </para>
		<para>TODO: Screenshot and explanation of the layout</para>
	</section>
	<section id="acp_general">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>General Configuration and Front Page</title>
		<para>The General section is the first screen you see each time you log into the Admin Control Panel. It contains some basic statistics and information about your forum. It also has a subsection called <guimenuitem>Quick Access</guimenuitem>. It provides a quick access to some of the more often visited admin pages like <link linkend="acp_usergroups">User Management</link> or <link linkend="acp_maintenance">Moderator Logs</link>. We will discuss its items later in their specific sections.</para>
		<para>We will concentrate on the other three subsections: Board Configuration, Client Communication, and Server Configuration.</para>
		<section id="acp_general_board">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>dhn</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Board Configuration</title>
			<para>This subsection contains items to adjust the overall features and settings of the forum. </para>
			<section id="acp_general_settings">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>dhn</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Board Settings</title>
				<para>The <guimenuitem>Board Settings</guimenuitem> allow you to change the most important setting of your forum installation: the name of your forum. Put the name of your site into the <guilabel>Site Name</guilabel> text field and it will be shown on the header of the default style and will be the prefix to the window title of your browser.</para>
				<para>The <guilabel>Site Description</guilabel> is the slogan or tag line of your forum. It will appear below the <guilabel>Site Name</guilabel> on the default style's header.</para>
				<para>If you need to close your whole forum to do maintenance work, for instance, you can do it by using the <guilabel>Disable Board</guilabel> switch. This will keep any members of your forum that are not Administrators or Moderators unable from accessing the board. They will either see a default message instead of the forum or you can add your own message in the text field below the check boxes. Administrators and Moderators will still be able to browse forums and use their specific control panels.</para>
				<para>You need to set the <guilabel>Default Language</guilabel> of your board. This is the language guests will see when they visit the board. You can allow users to choose other languages. By default there is only <guilabel>English [UK]</guilabel> installed but you can <ulink url="http://www.phpbb.com/languages">download more languages on the phpBB website</ulink>. Find out more about working with languages in the <link linkend="acp_system">Language Pack configuration</link>.</para>
				<para>TODO: Write about date format and timezone, may change, so leaving this out for now.</para>
				<para>The board will appear to your guests and members in the <guilabel>Default Style</guilabel>. In the standard phpBB installation two Styles are available (TODO: write more about them?). You can either allow users to select another Style than the default by selecting <guilabel>No</guilabel> in the <guilabel>Override User Style</guilabel> setting or disallow it. Please visit the <link linkend="acp_styles">Styles section</link> to find out how to add new Styles and where to find them.</para>
				<para>Moderators can send warnings to users that break the forum rules. The value of <guilabel>Warning Duration</guilabel> defines the number of days a warning is valid until it expires. Read more about warnings in the Moderator Control Panel. TODO: Add link to this section.</para>
			</section>
			<section id="acp_board_features">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>dhn</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Board Features</title>
				<para>Through the <guimenuitem>Board Features</guimenuitem> section you can enable or disable several features board-wide. Note that any feature you disable here will not be available on your forum, even if you give your users permissions to use them.</para>
			</section>
			<section id="acp_board_attachments">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>dhn</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Attachment Settings</title>
				<para>TODO: Write about attachment settings.</para>
			</section>
			<section id="acp_board_avatars">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>dhn</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Avatar Settings</title>
				<para>Avatars are generally small, unique images a user can associate with themselves. Depending on the style they are usually displayed below the user name when viewing topics. Here you can determine how users can define their avatars.</para>
				<para>There are three different ways a user can add an avatar to their profile. The first way is through an avatar gallery you provide. Note, that there is no avatar gallery available in a default phpBB installation. The <guilabel>Avatar Gallery Path</guilabel> is the path to the gallery images. The default path is <guilabel>images/avatars/gallery</guilabel>. The gallery folder does not exist in the default installation so you have to add it manually if you want to use it.</para>
				<para>The images you want to use for your gallery need to be in a folder inside the gallery path. Images directly in the gallery path won't be recognised. There is also no support for sub folders inside the gallery folder. </para>
				<para>The second approach to avatars is through <guilabel>Remote Avatars</guilabel>. This are simply images linked from another website. Your members can add a link to the image they want to use in their profile. To give you some control over the size of the avatars you can define the minimum and maximum size of the images. The disadvantage of <guilabel>Remote Avatars</guilabel> is that you are not able to control the file size.</para>
				<para>The third approach to avatars is through <guilabel>Avatar Uploading</guilabel>. Your members can upload an image form their local system which will be stored on your server. They will be uploaded into the <guilabel>Avatar Storage Path</guilabel> you can define. The default path is <guilabel>images/avatars/upload</guilabel> and does already exist after installation. You have to make sure that it is server writable (TODO: a link to a FAQ that explains this). The file format of the images has to be either gif, jpeg, or png, and the avatars will be automatically checked for their file and image size after the upload. You can adjust the <guilabel>Maximum Avatar File Size</guilabel> and images that are bigger than the allowed value will be discarded.</para>
			</section>
			<section id="acp_board_pms">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>dhn</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Private Messaging</title>
				<para> Private Messages are a way for registered members to communicate privately through your board without the need to fall back to e-mail or instant messaging. </para>
				<para> You can disable this feature with the <guilabel>Private Messaging</guilabel> setting. This will keep the feature turned off for the whole board. You can disable Private Messages for selected users or groups with <link linkend="acp_permissions">Permissions</link>. Please see the <link linkend="acp_permissions">Permissions section</link> for more information. </para>
				<para> Olympus allows users to create own personal folders to organise Private Messages. The <guilabel>Max Private Messages Per Box</guilabel> setting defines the number of message folders they can create. The default value is 4. You can disable the feature with setting value to 0. </para>
				<para>
					<guilabel>Max Private Messages Per Box</guilabel> sets the number of Private Messages each folder can contain. The default value is <guilabel>50</guilabel>, Set it to 0 to allow unlimited messages per folder. </para>
				<para> If you limit the number of messages users can store in their folders, you need to define a default action that is taken once a folder is full. This can be changed in the "Full Folder Default Action" list. The oldest message gets deleted or the new message will be held back until the folder has place for it. Note that users will be able to choose this for themselves in their PM options and this setting only changes the default value they face. This will not override the action a user chosen. </para>
				<para> When sending a Private Message it is still possible to edit the message until the recipient reads it. After it was read, editing the message is no longer possible. To limit the time a message can be edited before the recipient reads it, you can set the <guilabel>Limit Editing Time</guilabel>. The default value is 0 which allows editing until the message is read. Note that you can disallow users or groups to edit Private Messages after sending through <link linkend="acp_permissions">Permissions</link>. If the permission to edit messages is denied, it will override this setting. </para>
				<para>The <guilabel>General Options</guilabel> allow you to further define the functionality of Private Messages on your board. <itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para><guilabel>Allow Mass PMs:</guilabel> enables the sending of Private Messages to multiple recipients. This feature is enabled by default. Disabling it will also disallow sending of Private Messages to groups. </para>
							<tip>
								<para>See the <link linkend="acp_usergroups">Groups section</link> for information on how to enable the ability to send a message to a whole group.</para>
							</tip>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>By default <glossterm>BBCode</glossterm> and <glossterm>Smilies</glossterm> are allowed in Private Messages.</para>
							<tip>
								<para>Even if enabled, you can still disallow users or groups to use <glossterm>BBCode</glossterm> and <glossterm>Smilies</glossterm> in Private Messages through <link linkend="acp_permissions">Permissions</link>.</para>
							</tip>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>We don't allow attachments by default. Further settings for attachments in Private Messages are in the <link linkend="acp_board_attachments">Attachment Settings</link>. There you can define the number of attachments per message for instance.</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="acp_forums">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Forum Admin</title>
		<para>TODO: Stuff about forum admin</para>
	</section>

	<section id="acp_posting">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Posting Settings</title>
		<para>TODO: Stuff about the posting settings</para>
	</section>

	<section id="acp_users">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>User management</title>
		<para>TODO: Stuff about users</para>
	</section>

	<section id="acp_groups">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Group management</title>
		<para>TODO: Stuff about users and groups</para>
		<section id="acp_groups_types">
			<title>Group types</title>
			<para>There are two types of groups:</para>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Pre-defined groups</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>These are groups that are available by default in phpBB 3.0. You <emphasis>cannot</emphasis> delete them, as the board needs them for various features. You can still change their attributes (description, colour, rank, avatar and so forth) and group leaders. Users that register to your board are automatically added to the predefined group "Registered Users" for instance. Do not try to remove them manually through the database or your board will no longer function properly. </para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>User defined groups</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>The groups you create by yourself, are called "User defined groups". This are the groups similar to 2.0. You may create as many as you want, can remove them, set group leaders and change their attributes (description, colour, rank, avatar, and so forth)</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
			<para>The "Manage groups" section in the "Administrator Control Panel" shows you separated lists of both your "User defined groups" and the "Pre-defined groups".</para>
<!-- TODO: LIST OF ALL PRE-DEFINED GROUPS AND THEIR FUNCTION -->
			
		</section>
		<section id="acp_groups_edit">
			<title>Group attributes</title>
			<para>A list of attributes a group can have:</para>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group name</term>
					<listitem><para>The name of your group.</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group description</term>
					<listitem><para>The description of the group that will be displayed on the group overview list..</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry id="acp_groups_edit_legend">
					<term>Display group in legend:</term>
					<listitem><para>This will enable the display of  the name of the group in the legend of the "Who is Online" list. Note, that this will only make sense if you specified a colour for the group.</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group able to receive private messages</term>
					<listitem><para>This will allow the sending of Private Messages to this group. Please note, that it can be dangerous to allow this for Registered Users, for instance. There is no permission to deny the sending to groups, so anyone who is able to send Private Messages will be able to send a message to this group!</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group private message limit per folder</term>
					<listitem><para>This setting overrides the per-user folder message limit. A value of 0 means the user default limit will be used. <!-- TODO: ADD LINK TO PM SETTINGS --></para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group colour</term>
					<listitem><para>The name of members that have this group as their default group (see <xref linkend="acp_groups_default"/>) will be displayed in this colour on all forum pages. If you enable <link linkend="acp_groups_edit_legend"><guilabel>Display group in legend</guilabel></link>, an legend entry with the same colour will appear below the "Who is Online" listing.</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group rank</term>
					<listitem><para>A member that has this group as the default group (see <xref linkend="acp_groups_default"/>) will have this rank below his username. Note, that you can change the rank of this member  to a different one that overrides the group setting.<!-- TODO: ADD LINK TO RANK SETTINGS --></para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group avatar</term>
					<listitem><para>A member that has this group as the default group (see <xref linkend="acp_groups_default"/>) will use this avatar. Note, that a member can change his avatar to a different one, if he has the permission to do so.<!-- TODO: ADD LINK TO AVATAR SETTINGS --></para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>				
			</variablelist>
			
		</section>
		<section id="acp_groups_default">
			<title>Default groups</title>
			<para>As it is now possible to assign attributes like colours or avatars to groups (see <xref linkend="acp_groups_edit" />, it can happen that a user is a member of two or more different groups that have different avatars or other attributes. So, which avatar will the user now inherit? </para>
			<para>To overcome this problem, you are able to assign each user exactly one "Default group". The user will only inherit the attributes of this group. Note, that it is not possible to mix attributes: If one group has a rank but no avatar, and another group has only a avatar, it is not possible to display the avatar from one group and the rank from the other group. You have to decide for one "Default group".</para>
			<important><para>Default groups have no influence on permissions. There is no added permissions bonus for your default group, so a user's permissions will stay the same, no matter what group is his default one.</para></important>
			<para>You can change default groups in two ways. Either through the user management (see <xref linkend="acp_users"/>) <!-- TODO: LINK  TO MANAGE USERS /--> or directly through the groups management (<guilabel>Manage groups</guilabel>). Please be careful with the second option, as when you change the default group through a group directly, this will change the default group for <emphasis>all</emphasis> its group members and overwrite their old default groups. So, if you change the default group for the "Registered Users" group by using the <guilabel>Default</guilabel> link, all members of your forum will have this group as their default one, even members of the Administrators and Moderators groups as they are also members of "Registered Users".</para>
			<important><para>If you make a group the default one that has a rank and avatar set, the user's old avatar and rank will be overwritten by the group.</para></important>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="acp_permissions">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Permission Overload</title>
		<para>TODO: Stuff about permissions</para>
	</section>

	<section id="acp_styles">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Styles</title>
		<para>TODO: Stuff about Styles</para>
	</section>

	<section id="acp_maintenance">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Board Maintenance</title>
		<para>TODO: Stuff about maintenance</para>
		<section id="acp_maintenance_logs">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>Graham</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Forum Logs</title>
			<para>The <guilabel>Forum Log</guilabel> section of the administration panel provdes an overview of what has been happening on the board. There are four types of logs:</para>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Admin Log</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>This log records all actions carried out within the administration panel itself.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Moderator Log</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>This logs records the actions performed by moderators of your board. Whenever a topic is moved or locked it will be recorded here, allowing you to see who carried out a particular action.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>User Log</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>This log records all important actions carried out either by users or on users. All email and password changes are recorded within this log.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Error Log</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>This log shows you any errors arising out of actions taken by the board itself, such as errors sending emails. If you are having problems with a particular feature not working, this log is a good place to start. If enabled, addtional debugging information may be written to this log.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
			<para>If you have appropriate permissions, you are able to remove any or all log entries from the above sections.</para>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="acp_system">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>System Configuration</title>
		<para>TODO: Stuff about system configuration</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
