<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
                         "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="glossary">
	<?dbhtml dir="glossary" filename="index.html" ?>
	<chapterinfo>
		<releaseinfo>$Id$</releaseinfo>
		<copyright>
			<year>2006</year>
			<holder>phpBB Group</holder>
		</copyright>
	</chapterinfo>
	<title>Glossary</title>
	<abstract>
		<para>A guide to the terms used in the phpBB Documentation and on the forums.</para>
	</abstract>
	
	<section id="terms">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
				</author>
				
				<author>
					<othername>pentapenguin</othername>
				</author>
				
				<author>
					<othername>Techie-Micheal</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		
		<title>Terms</title>
		<para>There are quite a few terms that are commonly used throughout phpBB and the support forums. Here is some information on these terms.</para>
		
		<!-- TODO: Add links to sections on the respective item for whichever terms need it. For example, the ACP bit needs to link to the section of the Admin Guide. -->
		
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>ACP</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>The <link linkend="admin_control_panel"><acronym>ACP</acronym></link>, which stands for "Administration Control Panel",  is the main place from which you, the administrator, can control every aspect of your forum.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>ASCII</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><acronym>ASCII</acronym>, or "American Standard Code for Information Interchange", is a common way of encoding data to transfer it to a different computer. <acronym>FTP</acronym> clients have ASCII as a mode to transfer files. All phpBB files (files with the file extensions .php, .inc, .sql, .cfg, .htm, and .tpl), except for the image files, should be uploaded in ASCII mode.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Attachments</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><link linkend="acp_board_attachments">Attachments</link> are files that can be attached to posts, like e-mail attachments. Certain restrictions, set by the board administrator, control what users can attach.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Avatar</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><link linkend="ucp_avatar">Avatars</link> are small images that are displayed next to a username. Avatars can be changed in your profile and settings (such as allow/disallow uploading) edited from the <acronym>ACP</acronym>.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BBCode</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><link linkend="posting_bbcodes">BBCode</link> is a special way of formatting posts that offers great control over what and how something is displayed. BBCode has a syntax similar to HTML.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Binary</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Within phpBB, "binary" usually refers to another common way of encoding data for transfer (the other being <acronym>ASCII</acronym>. This is often found as a mode in an <acronym>FTP</acronym> clients to upload files. All of phpBB's images (found in the images/ and templates/subSilver/images/ directories) should be uploaded in binary mode. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Cache</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Cache is a way of storing frequently-accessed data. By storing this data, your server will have less load put on it, allowing it to process other tasks. By default, phpBB caches its templates when they are compiled and used.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Category</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A category is a group of any sort of similar items; for example, forums.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>chmod</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><abbrev>chmod</abbrev> is a way of changing the permissions of a file on a *nix (UNIX, Linux, etc.) server. Files in phpBB should be chmodded 644. Directories should be chmodded to 755. Avatar upload directories and templates cache directories should be chmodded to 777. For more information regarding chmod, please consult your <acronym>FTP</acronym> client's documentation.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Client</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A client is a computer that accesses another computer's service(s) via a network.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Cookie</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A cookie is a small piece of data put onto the user's computer. Cookies are used with phpBB to store login information (used for automatic logins).</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Database</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A database is a collection stored in a structured, organized manner (with different tables and row and columns, etc.). Databases provide a fast and flexible way of storing data, instead of the other commonly used data storage system of flat files where data is stored in a file. phpBB 3.0 supports a number of different <acronym>DBMSs</acronym>  and uses the database to store information such as user details, posts, categories. Data stored in a database can usually be backed up and restored easily.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>DBAL</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><acronym>DBAL</acronym>, or "Database Abstraction Layer", is a system that allows phpBB 3.0 to access many different <acronym>DBMSs</acronym> with little overhead. All code made for phpBB (including MODs) need to use the phpBB <acronym>DBAL</acronym> for compatibility and performance purposes.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>DBMS</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A <acronym>DBMS</acronym>, or "Database Management System", is a system or software designed to manage a database. phpBB 3.0 supports the following DBMSs: Firebird, MS SQL Server, mySQL, Oracle, postgreSQL, and SQLite.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>FTP</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><acronym>FTP</acronym> stands for "File Transfer Protocol". It is a protocol which allows files to be transferred between computers. <acronym>FTP</acronym> clients are programs that are used to transfer files via <acronym>FTP</acronym>.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Founder</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A founder is a special board administrator that cannot be edited or deleted. This is a new user level introduced in phpBB 3.0.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>GZip</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>GZip is a compression method often used in web applications and software such as phpBB to improve speed. Most modern browsers support this on-the-fly algorithm. Gzip is also used to compress an archive of files. Higher compression levels, however, will increase server load.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>IP address</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>An IP address, or Internet Protocol address, is a unique address that identifies a specific computer or user.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Jabber</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Jabber is an open-source protocol that can be used for instant messenging. For more information on how Jabber's role in phpBB, see <xref linkend="acp_client_jabber" />.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>MD5</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><acronym>MD5</acronym> (Message Digest algorithm 5) is a commonly-used hash function used by phpBB. MD5 is an algorithm which takes an input of any length and outputs a message digest of a fixed length (128-bit, 32 characters). MD5 is used in phpBB to turn the users' passwords into a one-way hash, meaning that you cannot "decrypt" (reverse) an MD5 hash and get users' passwords. User passwords are stored as MD5 hashes in the database.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>MOD</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A <abbrev>MOD</abbrev> is a code modification for phpBB that either adds, changes, or in some other way enhances, phpBB. <abbrev>MODs</abbrev> are written by third-party authors; as such, the phpBB Group does not assume any responsibility for MODs.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>PHP</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><acronym>PHP</acronym>, or "PHP: Hypertext Preprocessor", is a commonly-used open-source scripting language. phpBB is written in <acronym>PHP</acronym> and requires the <acronym>PHP</acronym> runtime engine to be installed and properly configured on the server phpBB is run on. For more information about <acronym>PHP</acronym>, please see the <ulink url="http://www.php.net">PHP</ulink> home page.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>phpMyAdmin</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>phpMyAdmin is a popular open-source program that is used to manage MySQL databases. When <abbrev>MODding</abbrev> phpBB or otherwise changing it, you may have to edit your database. phpMyAdmin is one such tool that will allow you to do so. For more information regarding phpMyAdmin, please see the <ulink url="http://www.phpmyadmin.net">phpMyAdmin project home page</ulink>.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Private Messages</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Private messages are a way for registered members to communicate privately through your board without the need to fall back to e-mail or instant messaging. They can be sent between users (they can also be forwarded and have copies sent, in phpBB 3.0) that cannot be viewed by anyone other than the intended recipient. The user guide contains more information on <link linkend="user_pm">using phpBB3's private messaging system</link>.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Rank</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A rank is a sort of title that is assigned to a user. Ranks can be added, edited, and deleted by administrators.</para>
					
					<note>
						<para>When assigning a special rank name to a user, remember that no permissions are associated. For example, if you create a "Support Moderator" rank and assign it to a user, that user will not automatically get moderator permissions. You must assign the user the special permissions separately.</para>
					</note>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Session</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A session is a visit to your phpBB forums. For phpBB, a session is how long you spend on the forums. It is created when you login deleted when you log off. Session <acronym>IDs</acronym> are usually stored in a cookie, but if phpBB is unable to get cookie information from your computer, then a session <acronym>ID</acronym> is appended to the URL (e.g. index.php?sid=999). This session <acronym>ID</acronym> preserves the user's session without use of a cookie. If sessions were not preserved, then you would find yourself being logged out every time you clicked on a link in the forum.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Signature</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A signature is a message displayed at the end of a user's post. Signatures are set by the user. Whether or not a signature is displayed after a post is sest by the user's profile settings.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>SMTP</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><acronym>SMTP</acronym> stands for "Simple Mail Transfer Protocol". It is a protocol for sending email. By default, phpBB uses <acronym>PHP</acronym>'s built-in <ulink url="http://www.php.net/manual/en/function.mail.php">mail()</ulink> function to send email. However, phpBB will use <acronym>SMTP</acronym> to send emails if the required <acronym>SMTP</acronym> data is correctly set up.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Style</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A style is made up of a template set, image set, and stylesheet. A style controls the overall look of your forum.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Sub-forum</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Sub-forums are a new feature introduced in phpBB 3.0. Sub-forums are forums that are nested in, or located in, other forums.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Template</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A template is what controls the layout of a style. phpBB 3.0 template files have the .html file extension. These template files contain mostly <acronym>HTML</acronym> (no <acronym>PHP</acronym>, however), with some variables that phpBB uses (contained in braces: { and }).</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>UNIX Timestamp</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>phpBB stores all times in the <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unix_time">UNIX timestamp</ulink> format for easy conversion to other time zones and time formats.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Usergroup</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Usergroups are a way of grouping users. This makes it easier to set permissions to many people at the same time (e.g. create a moderator group and give it moderating permissions to a certain forum instead of giving lots of individual people moderating permissions separately). A usergroup has a usergroup moderator, who has the ability to add or delete users from the group. Usergroups can be set to hidden, closed or open. phpBB 3.0 has six pre-defined usergroups.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</section>
</chapter>
