<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
                         "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="moderator_guide">
	<?dbhtml dir="moderatorguide" ?>
	<title>Moderator Guide</title>
	<abstract>
		<para>This chapter describes the phpBB 3.0 forum moderation controls.</para>
	</abstract>
	<section id="moderator_edit">
		<title>Editing posts</title>
		<para>TODO: When are moderators allowed to edit posts, how are edited posts displayed. Which further options does the moderator have in the posting screen (preventing further editing for instance).</para>
	</section>
	<section id="moderator_modtools">
		<title>Moderation tools</title>
		<para>TODO: A short description of the mod tools locking, deleting, copy, move, change topic type (with link to section about topic types in the Userguide) first, then the more advanced split, merge functions.</para>
		<section id="modtools_lock">
			<title>Locking a topic or post</title>
			<para>TODO: A description of how to lock a topic. Also needs a link or description of the difference between locking a topic and a post.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="modtools_delete">
			<title>Deleting a topic or post</title>
			<para>TODO: A description of how to delete topics and posts. Needs warning that deleting is as of yet (unless the developers add the recycle bin feature) irreversible.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="modtools_move">
			<title>Moving a topic into another forum</title>
			<para>TODO: A description of how to move topics into another forum. What are shadow topics, how do I remove shadow topics. Note that for moving only selected posts of a topic, you need the split function.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="modtools_copy">
			<title>Duplicating a topic</title>
			<para>TODO: How to copy / duplicate a given topic.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="modtools_type">
			<title>Announcements and stickies</title>
			<para>TODO: How to change the topic type, link to the topic type overview that the Userguide needs.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="modtools_split">
			<title>Splitting posts off a topic</title>
			<para>TODO: How to split posts, as this will lead the moderator to the MCP a link to the <link linkend="moderator_queue">Forum moderation MCP section</link> is needed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="modtools_mergetopics">
			<title>Merge topics</title>
			<para>TODO: How to merge topics, as this will lead the moderator to the MCP a link to the <link linkend="moderator_queue">Forum moderation MCP section</link> is needed.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="modtools_mergeposts">
			<title>Merge posts into another topic</title>
			<para>TODO: How to merge selected posts of one topic into another topic, as this will lead the moderator to the MCP a link to the <link linkend="moderator_queue">Forum moderation MCP section</link> is needed.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="moderator_queue">
		<title>What is the 'Moderation queue'?</title>
		<para>TODO: Short description of what the moderation queue is, and how a moderator can recognise that a post or topic is in it, and how to approve / disapprove in the forum view. <link linkend="mcp_queue">Link to the MCP section that deals with it.</link></para>
	</section>
	<section id="moderator_reported">
		<title>What are 'Reported posts'?</title>
		<para>TODO: Short description of what reported posts are, how they are displayed in the forum / topic view and how to work with them. <link linkend="mcp_reported">Link to the MCP section about Reported posts.</link></para>
	</section>
	<section id="moderator_mcp">
		<title>The Moderator Control Panel (MCP)</title>
		<para>TODO: Some information about the moderator control panel.</para>
		<section id="mcp_queue">
			<title>Moderation queue</title>
			<para>TODO: <link linkend="moderator_queue">Link to the "WHat is the Moderation Queue description.</link> and some further explanation for what can be done and see in the MCP section for this.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="mcp_reported">
			<title>Reported posts</title>
			<para>TODO: <link linkend="moderator_reported">Link to the reported posts description.</link> and some further explanation for what can be done and see in the MCP section for this.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="mcp_forum">
			<title>Forum moderation</title>
			<para>TODO: Description of this 'meta-view' of the forum structure. No need to explain the specific moderation abilities you have here, as they have their own sections, but a link (related sections?) to those moderation functions should be included.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
