<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
                         "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="quick_start_guide">
	<?dbhtml dir="quickstart" ?>
	<title>Quick Start Guide</title>
	<abstract>
		<para>TODO: A quick guide through the first steps of setting up your very own phpBB 3.0 forum.</para>
	</abstract>
	<section id="quick_requirements">
		<title>Requirements</title>
		<para>TODO: An overview of the requirements.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="quick_installing">
		<title>Installing</title>
		<para>TODO: Detailing the installation process step by step. Explanation of all items on the install pages.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="quick_settings">
		<sectioninfo>
	      <authorgroup>
	         <author>
	            <othername>zeroK</othername>
	         </author>
	      </authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>General settings</title>
		<para>In this section you will learn how to change some of the basic settings of your new board.</para>
		<para>Right after the installation you will be redirected to the so called "Administation Control Panel" (<acronym>ACP</acronym>). You can also access this panel by clicking the <guilabel>[Administration Control Panel]</guilabel> link at the bottom of your forum. In this interface you can change everything about your board.</para>
		<section id="quick_settings_boardsettings">
			<title>Board Settings</title>
			<para>The first section of the <acronym>ACP</acronym> you will probably want to visit right after the installation is "Board Settings". Here you can first of all change the name (<guilabel>Site name</guilabel>) and description (<guilabel>Site description</guilabel>) of your board.</para>
			<figure id="quick_settings">
				<title>Board Settings</title>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/quick_start_guide/settings_sitename.png" format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Here you can edit the Site name and Site description of your board.</para>
				</caption>
			</figure>
			<para>This form also holds the options for changing things like the timezone (<guilabel>System timezone</guilabel>) as well as the date format used to render dates/times (<guilabel>Date format</guilabel>).</para>
			<para>There you can also select a new style (after having installed it) for your board and enforce it on all members ignoring whatever style they've selected in their "User Control Panel". The style will also be used for all forums where you haven't specified a different one. For details on where to get new styles and how to install them, please read [insert link here].</para>
			<para>If you want to use your board for a non-English community, this form also lets you change the default language (<guilabel>Default Language</guilabel>) (which can be overridden by each user in their UCPs). By default phpBB3 only ships with the English language pack. So before using this field, you will have to download the language pack for the language you want to use and install it. For details please read <xref linkend="acp_system"/> .</para>
			<!--TODO: Correct ACP link-->
		</section><!--/board_settings-->
		<section id="quick_settings_boardfeatures">
			<title>Board Features</title>
			<para>If you want to enable or disable some of the basic features of your board, this is the place to go. Here you can allow and disallow for example username changes (<guilabel>Allow Username changes</guilabel>) or the creation of attachments (<guilabel>Allow Attachments</guilabel>). You can even disable <acronym>BBCode</acronym> altogether (<guilabel>Allow BBCode</guilabel>).</para>
			<figure>
				<title>Board Features</title>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/quick_start_guide/settings_features.png" format="PNG"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Enabling and disabling basic features with just 2 clicks</para>
				</caption>
			</figure>
			<para>Disabling BBCode completely is a little bit to harsh for your taste but you don't want your users to abuse the signature field for tons of images? Simply set <guilabel>Allow use of IMG BBCode Tag in user signatures</guilabel> to "No". If you want to be a little bit more specific on what you want to allow and disallow in users' signatures, have a look at the "Signature Settings" form.</para>
			<para>The "Board Features" form offers you a great way to control the features in an all-or-nothing way. If you want to get into the details on each feature, there is for everything also a separated form which let's you specify everything from the maximum number of characters allowed in a post (<guilabel>Max characters per post</guilabel> in "Post Settings") to how large a user's avatar can be (<guilabel>Maximum Avatar Dimensions</guilabel> in "Avatar Settings").</para>
			<important>
				<para>If you disable features, these will also be unavailable to users who would normally have them according to their respective permissions. For details on the permissions system please read <xref linkend="quick_permissions"/> or the in-depth guide in the Administrator Guide.</para>
				<!-- TODO: Link to admin guide -->
			</important>
		</section>
		<!--<para>TODO: Probably needs a better title. How to change the default forum settings, forum name or description, for instance. Does not need to have all settings explained in detail. We have the Admin Guide for that. It would be good to provide a link if there is anything that is discussed more detailed in the Admin Guide. </para>-->
	</section>
	<section id="quick_forums">
		<title>Creating forums</title>
		<para>TODO: A short step by step explanation into how to create a new forum and categories. Probably not necessary to go into subforums at this point. They should be mentioned, but a link to the respective admin section for further information should be enough. </para>
	</section>
	<section id="quick_permissions">
		<title>Setting permissions</title>
		<para>TODO: This shouldn't be too detailed. Just go through the steps that are needed to set permissions for the default usergroups and members. It can contain a short paragraph about usergroups and how Olympus handles them, but there is no need to explain them in detail. </para>
	</section>
	<section id="quick_support">
		<title>Obtaining support</title>
		<para>The <ulink url="http://www.phpbb.com/about/">phpBB Team</ulink> provides many options for users to find support for their phpBB install. In addition to this very documentation, the <ulink url="http://www.phpbb.com/phpBB/viewforum.php?f=1">support forum on www.phpbb.com</ulink> has many answers that users like you are searching for. Therefore, we highly recommend the use of the search feature before asking a new question. If you are unable to find an answer, feel free to post a new topic asking for help. Be sure to be descriptive when explaining your problem! The more we know about what is happening, the faster we can provide you with the answer you are looking for. Be sure to fill out the <ulink url="http://www.phpbb.com/phpBB/viewtopic.php?t=128123">Support Request Template</ulink> with the information it asks for.</para>

		<para>In addition to the support forum on www.phpbb.com, we provide a <ulink url="http://www.phpbb.com/kb/">Knowledge Base</ulink> for users to read and submit articles on common answers to questions. Our community has taken a lot of time in writing these articles, so be sure to check them out.</para>

		<para>We provide realtime support in <ulink url="irc://chat.freenode.net/phpbb">#phpBB</ulink> on the popular Open Source IRC network, <ulink url="http://www.freenode.net/">Freenode</ulink>. You can typically find someone from each of the teams in here, as well as fellow users who are more than happy to help you out. Be sure to read the <ulink url="http://www.phpbb.com/support/irc/">IRC rules</ulink> before joining the channel, as we have a few basic netiquette rules that we ask users to follow. At any given time, there can be as many as 60 users, if not more in the channel, so you are almost certain to find someone there to help you. However, it is important that you read and follow the IRC rules as people may not answer you. An example of this is that oftentimes users come in to the channel and ask if anybody is around and then end up leaving 30 seconds later before someone has the chance to answer. Instead, be sure to ask your question and wait. As the saying goes, "don't ask to ask, just ask!"</para>

		<para>English is not your native language? Not a problem! We also provide an <ulink url="http://www.phpbb.com/support/intl/">International Support page</ulink> with links to various websites that provide support in Espanol, Deutsch, Francais, and more.</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
