<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
                         "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="user_guide">
	<?dbhtml dir="userguide" filename="index.html" ?>
	<title>User Guide</title>
	<abstract>
		<para>This chapter is targeted at the forum users. It explains all user facing functions that are needed to use phpBB 3.0.</para>
	</abstract>
	<section id="user_permissions">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>AdamR</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>How user permissions affect forum experience</title>
		<para>phpBB3 uses permissions, on a per-user or per-usergroup basis, to allow or disallow users to access certain functions or features which the bulletin board has to offer. Such things include posting in forums, having an avatar, or being able to communicate through private messages, along with tons of other options. All of the permissions are definable through the Administration Panel.</para>
		<para>Permissions can also be set to allow users or appointed members to perform special tasks or have special abilities on the bulletin board. Permissions allow the Administrator to define which moderation functions and in which forums certain users or groups of users are allowed to use. The administrator can also allow users to gain access to defined sections of the Administration panel, keeping important settings or functions restricted and safe.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="user_registering">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>zeroK</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Registering on a phpBB3 board</title>
		<para>The basic procedure of registering an account on a phpBB3 board consists in the simplest case of only two steps: <orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>After following the "Register" link you should see the board rules. If you agree to these terms the registration process continues. If you don't agree you can't register your account</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Now you see a short form for entering your user information where you can specify your username, e-mail address, password, language and timezone.</para>
				</listitem>

			</orderedlist>
		</para>
		<para>As mentioned above, this is only the simplest case. The board can be configured to add some additional steps to the registration process. </para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>If you get a site where you have to select whether you were born before or after a specified date, the administrator has enabled this to comply with the U.S. <acronym>COOPA</acronym> act. If you are younger than 13 years, your account will stay inactive until it is approved by a parent or guardian. You will receive an e-mail where the next steps required for your account activation are described. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>If you see in the form where you can specify your username, password etc. a graphic with some wierd looking characters, then you see the so called <emphasis>Visual Confirmation</emphasis>. Simply enter these characters into the <guilabel>Confirmation code</guilabel> field and proceed with the registration. </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Another option is the account activation. Here the administrator can make it a requirement that you have to follow and link mailed to you after registering before your account is activated. In this case you will see a message similiar to this one: <blockquote>
						<para> Your account has been created. However, this forum requires account activation, an activation key has been sent to the e-mail address you provided. Please check your e-mail for further information </para>
					</blockquote>
				</para>
				<para>It is also possible that the administrator himself/herself has to activate the account. <blockquote>
						<para> Your account has been created. However, this forum requires account activation by the administrator. An e-mail has been sent to them and you will be informed when your account has been activated. </para>
					</blockquote> In this case please have some patience with the administrators to review your registration and activate your account. </para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</section>
	<section id="user_control_panel">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>Heimidal</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Orienting Yourself in the User Control Panel</title>
		<para>The User Control Panel (UCP) allows you to alter personal preferences, manage posts you are watching, send and receive private messages, and change the way information about you appears to other users. To view the UCP, click the 'User Control Panel' link that appears after logging in.</para>
		<para>The UCP is separated into seven tabs: Overview, Private Messages, Profile, Preferences, Friends and Foes, Attachments, and Groups. Within each tab are several sub pages, accessed by clicking the desired link on the left side of the UCP interface. Some of these areas may not be available depending on the permissions set for you by the administrator.</para>
		<para>Every page of the UCP displays your Friends List on the left side. To send a private message to a friend, click their user name.</para>
		<para>TODO: Note that Private messaging will be discussed in its own section</para>
		<section id="ucp_overview">
			<title>Overview</title>
			<para>The Overview displays a snapshot of information about your posting habits such as the date you joined the forum, your most active topic, and how many total posts you have submitted. Overview sub pages include Subscriptions, Bookmarks, and Drafts.</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata format="PNG" fileref="../images/user_guide/ucp_overview.png" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The UCP Overview section - example screenshot</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
			<section id="ucp_subscriptions">
				<title>Subscriptions</title>
				<para>Subscriptions are forums or individual topics that you have elected to watch for any new posts. Whenever a new post is made inside an area you have subscribed to, an e-mail will be sent you to informing you of the new addition. To create a subscription, visit the forum or topic you would like to subscribe to and click the 'Subscribe' link located at the bottom of the page.</para>
				<para>To remove a subscription, check the box next to the subscription you would like to remove and click the 'Unsubscribe' button.</para>
			</section>
			<section id="ucp_bookmarks">
				<title>Bookmarks</title>
				<para>Bookmarks, much like subscriptions, are topics you've chosen to watch. However, there are two key differences: 1) only individual topics may be bookmarked, and 2) an e-mail will not be sent to inform you of new posts.</para>
				<para>To create a bookmark, visit the topic you would like to watch and click the 'Bookmark Topic' link located at the bottom of the page.</para>
				<para>To remove a bookmark, check the box next to the bookmark you would like to remove and click the 'Remove marked bookmarks' button.</para>
			</section>
			<section id="ucp_drafts">
				<title>Drafts</title>
				<para>Drafts are created when you click the 'Save' button on the New Post or Post Reply page. Displayed are the title of your post, the forum or topic that the draft was made in, and the date you saved it.</para>
				<para>To continue editing a draft for future submission, click the 'View/Edit' link. If you plan to finish and post the message, click 'Load Draft'. To delete a draft, check the box next to the draft you wish to remove and click 'Delete Marked'.</para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section id="ucp_profile">
			<title>Profile</title>
			<para>TODO: Short explanation of what this section is for. Needs to be clear why Profile and Preferences are separated.</para>
			<section>
				<title>Personal settings</title>
				<para>TODO: Explain the settings you can edit here. </para>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Registration details</title>
				<para>TODO: Explain the settings you can edit here.</para>
			</section>
			<section id="ucp_signature">
				<title>Signature</title>
				<para>TODO: Explain the settings you can edit here. Link to the BBcode explanation of the Posting section would be best.</para>
			</section>
			<section id="ucp_avatar">
				<title>Avatar</title>
				<para>TODO: Explain the settings you can edit here. Experience may differ on forum settings again. Short paragraph about the avatar gallery.</para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section id="ucp_preferences">
			<title>Preferences</title>
			<para>TODO: Short explanation of what this section is for.</para>
			<section id="ucp_personal">
				<title>Personal</title>
				<para>TODO: Explain the settings you can edit here. The date setting will offer presets, so a link to the <ulink url="http://www.php.net/date">php.net date function</ulink> for advanced users should be enough.</para>
			</section>
			<section id="ucp_viewing">
				<title>Viewing</title>
				<para>TODO: Explain the settings you can edit here. </para>
			</section>
			<section id="ucp_posting">
				<title>Posting</title>
				<para>TODO: Explain the settings you can edit here. </para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section id="ucp_friends_foes">
			<title>Friends and Foes</title>
			<para>TODO: (Not sure if this deserves its own section yet. For 3.0 this does not have much of an influence on the overall forum experience, this might change with 3.2, so leaving it here for now.) Write a detailed explanation about what Friends and Foes are and how they affect the forum like hiding posts of foes, adding users to the friends list for fast access / online checks, and so forth.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="ucp_attachments">
			<title>Attachments</title>
			<para>TODO: The attachment section of the UCP shows you a list of all attachments that you have uploaded to the board so far ... </para>
		</section>
		<section id="ucp_usergroups">
			<title>Usergroups</title>
			<para>TODO: Work in progress, might change, so not sure how this is going to be structured.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="user_posting">
		<title>Mastering the Posting Screen</title>
		<para>TODO: How to write a new post and how to reply. Special items like attachments or polls are subsections. Don't forget to mention the "someone has replied before you replied" feature, the topic review, and so forth. Topic icons, smilies, post options, usage of HTML ... it would probably best to add a screenshot with arrows to the different sections.</para>
		<para>Posting is the purpose of bulletin boards and the forums contained within them. Posting allows you to start a new topic for discussion or reply to an existing one which another user has created. There are a few things you may want to know about posting before you get started.</para>
		<para>To post a new topic or reply to an existing one, first you must enter the forum you wish to post in by clicking its link on the index. On the forum's page, you will see one button at the top-left corner above the topics already existing. To begin a new topic, click this button labled, "New Topic." In order to reply to an existing topic, from the forum's page, click a topic's link to enter its page. Here you will see two buttons at the top-left corner above the posts. To reply to this topic, hit the "New Reply" button. Clicking the "New Topic" button on this page will create a new topic in the forum you are currently in.</para>
		<para>Clicking either of these buttons will bring you to the posting page. Here you have several options as to how you'd like your topic or reply to be displayed on the topic page. When creating a new topic, you must enter a subject in the subject field. However, if you are replying to a topic, only a message is required. Hitting submit after entering a message (and subject for new topics) without any extra settings. Will simply enter your message using your profile's and/or the board's default settings. The special features in posting are examined below.</para>
		<section id="posting_bbcodes">
			<title>BBcodes</title>
			<para>TODO: What are BBcodes. Again, permission based which ones you can use. Explain syntax of the default ones (quote and URL for instance). How to disable BBcode by default, how to disable/enable it for one post.</para>
			<para>BBCode stands for Bulletin Board Code. BBCodes are a way for you to format your message's text and how its content is displayed. BBCode is much like HTML but simplified for use on bulletin boards. Whether or not users can use BBCode is up to the permissions set by the Administrator on the board. If you are allowed to use BBCode when posting messages, you will see "BBCode is ON" under "Options" to the left side below the message box.</para>
			<para>You can also control whether or not you wish to see other user's BBCode in your persoanl account preferences.. For more information about changing these settings, see the <link linkend="ucp_preferences">UCP Perferences</link> section.</para>
			<para>BBCode is used by placing the text you wish to format in between two BBCode tags. To make text bold, you would enclose it in B tags: [b]bolded text[/b]. Italisized text uses the [i][/i] tags, and to underline, you would use the [u][/u] tags. Some tags, such as quote and URL, allow for attributes to be used. Attributes gain further control to be gained over the appearance of the text.</para>
			<para>For example, to quote another user or perhaps something else you wish to specify, you can enter [quote="person being quoted"]Here is the text which will be quoted![/quote] into the message box. This will, when the message is posted, display in its own box set off from the rest of your message, letting users know this is a quote, and showing who or what it is quoted from.</para>
			<para>As another example, to make text a hyperlink to another page, you can use the URL BBCode tag and it's attribute, which is the URL you wish to point the text hyperlinked to. Entering [URL=http://www.phpbb.com]Click here to go to phpBB[/URL] into the message box would display the text "Click here to go to phpBB" as a hyperlink. When someone clicks this link, they will be taken to www.phpbb.com.</para>
			<para>Custom BBCodes can be crated by the Administrator of the forum.</para>

		</section>
		<section id="posting_attachments">
			<title>Attachments</title>
			<para>TODO: How to add attachments, what restrictions might there be. Note that one needs to have the permission to use attachments. How to add more than one file, and so forth.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="posting_polls">
			<title>Polls</title>
			<para>TODO: Again, permission based should be noted. Explain how to add the different options, allow for multiple votes, vote changing, and so forth.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="posting_drafts">
			<title>Drafts</title>
			<para>TODO: Explain how to load and save drafts. A link to the UCP drafts section should be added for reference. Not sure if permission based.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="user_pm">
		<title>Communicate with Private Messages</title>
		<para>phpBB 3.0 allows its users to communicate privately by using Private Messages. To visit the Private Messages section, you either can click on the [X new messages] link on the left hand side below the forum header, or you can directly access it through the <link linkend="user_control_panel">User Control Panel.</link>.</para>
		<para>Depending on your [settings], there are 3 ways of being notified that a new Private Message has arrived:</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>By receiving an e-mail or Jabber message</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>While browsing the forum a notification window will pop up</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>The [X new messages] link will show the number of currently unread messages</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<para>You can set the options to your liking in the <link linkend="ucp_preferences">Preferences section</link>. Note, that for the popup window notification to work, your will have to add the forum you are visiting to your browser’s popup blocker white list.</para>
		<para>You can choose to not receive Private Messages by other users in your <link linkend="ucp_preferences"> Preferences</link>. Note, that moderators and administrators will still be able send you Private Messages, even if you have disabled them.</para>
		<para>[To use this feature, you have to be a registered user and need the to have the correct permissions.]</para>
		<section id="pm_display">
			<title>Message display</title>
			<para>The Inbox is the default incoming folder, which contains a list of your recently received Private Messages. </para>
		</section>
		<section id="pm_new">
			<title>Composing a new message</title>
			<para>TODO: Similar to the posting screen, so a reference for the basic functions should be enough. What needs to be explained are the To and Bcc fields, how they integrate with the friends list and how to find members (which could also be a link to the memberlist section).</para>
		</section>
		<section id="pm_folders">
			<title>Message folders</title>
			<para>TODO: How to manage folders, how to create new ones, how to delete them. How to move messages between folders. What happens if a folder is full, what are the options to influence that? Also how to mark messages as important, how to delete messages (not sure about that one)?</para>
		</section>
		<section id="pm_filters">
			<title>Message filters</title>
			<para>TODO: How to work with message filters. That is quite a complex system</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="user_search">
		<title>Search - How to Find What You are Looking For</title>
		<para>TODO: Explain how to use the search system. This should also include the results page, and the refine function. Also note, that the title (Search: search term) is a link that one can copy and paste into a post to directly link to the results. Egosearch and the global search field should also be included here.</para>
	</section>
	<section id="user_memberlist">
		<title>The Memberlist - More Than Meets the Eye</title>
		<para>TODO: Give a short introduction into how to search for someone on the memberlist, how you can sort the table using the table headers, and so forth.</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
