<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
                         "https://www.docbook.org/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="admin_guide">
	<?dbhtml dir="adminguide" filename="index.html" ?>
	<chapterinfo>
		<releaseinfo>$Id$</releaseinfo>
		<copyright>
			<year>2009</year>
			<holder>phpBB Group</holder>
		</copyright>
	</chapterinfo>
	<title>Administration Guide</title>
	<abstract>
		<para>This chapter describes the phpBB 3.2 admin controls.</para>
	</abstract>
	<section id="admin_control_panel">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>The Administration Control Panel</title>
		<para>Even more so than its predecessor, phpBB 3.2 &quot;Rhea&quot; is highly configurable. You can tune, adjust, or turn off almost all features. To make this load of settings as accessible as possible, we redesigned the Administration Control Panel (ACP) completely. </para>
		<para>Click on the <guilabel>Administration Control Panel</guilabel> link on the bottom of the default forum style to visit the <acronym>ACP</acronym>.</para>
		<para>The <acronym>ACP</acronym> has seven different sections by default with each containing a number of subsections. We will discuss each section in this Admin Guide. </para>
		
		<figure id="img_acp_index">
			<title>Administration Control Panel Index</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata format="PNG" fileref="../images/admin_guide/acp_index.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The Administration Control Panel Index, the home of managing your phpBB board. Administration functions are grouped into eight different categories: <guimenuitem>General</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Forums</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Posting</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Users and Groups</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Permissions</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Styles</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Maintenance</guimenuitem>, and <guimenuitem>System</guimenuitem>. Each category is a tab located at the top of the page. Specific functions of the category you're in can be found in the left-hand sidebar of each page.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
	</section>
	
	<section id="acp_general">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>General Configuration and Front Page</title>
		<para>The <guimenuitem>General</guimenuitem> section is the first screen you see each time you log into the <acronym>ACP</acronym>. It contains some basic statistics and information about your forum. It also has a subsection called <guimenuitem>Quick Access</guimenuitem>. It provides quick access to some of the admin pages that are frequently used, like <link linkend="acp_users">User Management</link> or <link linkend="acp_maintenance">Moderator Logs</link>. We will discuss its items later in their specific sections.</para>
		<para>We will concentrate on the other three subsections: <link linkend="acp_general_config">Board Configuration</link>, <link linkend="acp_general_client">Client Communication</link>, and <link linkend="acp_general_server">Server Configuration</link>.</para>
		<section id="acp_general_config">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>dhn</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Board Configuration</title>
			<para>This subsection contains items to adjust the overall features and settings of the forum. </para>
			
			<section id="acp_board_attachments">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>dhn</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Attachment Settings</title>
				<para>One of the many features in phpBB 3.2 is <glossterm>Attachments</glossterm>. Attachments are files that can be attached to posts, like e-mail attachments. Certain restrictions, set by the board administrator, control what users can attach. You can set these restrictions via the <guimenuitem>Attachment Settings</guimenuitem> page.</para>
				<para>For more information, see the section on <link linkend="acp_attach_settings">configuring your board's attachment settings</link>.</para>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_general_settings">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>dhn</othername>
						</author>
						
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Board Settings</title>
				<para>The <guimenuitem>Board Settings</guimenuitem> allow you to change many settings that govern your board. These settings include important things such as the name of your forum! There are two main groups of board settings: the general <guilabel>Board Settings</guilabel>, and <guilabel>Warnings</guilabel> settings.</para>
				
				<itemizedlist>
					<title>Board Settings</title>
					<listitem><para>The very first board setting you can edit is perhaps the most important setting of them all: the name of your board. Your users identify your board with this name. Put the name of your site into the <guilabel>Site Name</guilabel> text field and it will be shown on the header of the default style; it will be the prefix to the window title of your browser.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>The <guilabel>Site Description</guilabel> is the slogan or tagline of your forum. It will appear below the <guilabel>Site Name</guilabel> on the default style's header.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>You can also use the <guilabel>Main website URL</guilabel> and <guilabel>Main website text</guilabel> fields to add a link to your home page in the breadcrumbs. The board's logo will also use this link.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>If you need to close your whole forum to do maintenance work, for instance, you can do it by using the <guilabel>Disable Board</guilabel> switch. To temporarily disable your board, select<guilabel>Yes</guilabel>. This will keep any members of your forum who are not administrators or moderators from accessing your board. They will either see a default message instead of the forum, or a message that you create. You can add your own custom message that will be displayed when your board is disabled in the text box below the <guilabel>Disable board</guilabel> radio buttons. Administrators and moderators will still be able to browse forums and use their specific control panels when the board is disabled.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>You also need to set the <guilabel>Default Language</guilabel> of your board. This is the language that guests will see when they visit your board. You can allow registered users to choose other languages. By default, the only language installed is <guilabel>English [GB]</guilabel>, but you can <ulink url="https://www.phpbb.com/languages">download more languages on the phpBB website</ulink> and install them on your board. Find out more about working with languages in the <link linkend="acp_customise_language">section on Language Pack configuration</link>.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>You can also configure your board's default date format. phpBB3 has a few basic date formats that you can set your board to use; if these are not sufficient and you would like to customise your board's date format, choose <guimenuitem>Custom</guimenuitem> from the <guilabel>Date format</guilabel> selection menu. Then, in the text box besides it, type in the format you would like to use. This is the same as the <ulink url="http://www.php.net/date">PHP date() function</ulink>.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Along with setting your board's default date format, you can also set your board's preferred timezone. The timezones available in the <guilabel>System timezone</guilabel> selection menu are all based on relative <acronym>UTC</acronym> (for most intents and purposes, it is <acronym>GMT</acronym>, or Greenwich Mean Time) times.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>You can also set your board's default style. The board will appear to your guests and members in the <guilabel>Default Style</guilabel>. In the standard phpBB installation, two styles are available: prosilver and subsilver2. You can either allow users to select another style than the default by selecting <guilabel>No</guilabel> in the <guilabel>Override User Style</guilabel> setting or disallow it. Please visit the <link linkend="acp_customise_styles">styles section</link> to find out how to add new styles and where to find some.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				
				<itemizedlist>
					<title>Warnings</title>
					<listitem><para>Moderators can send warnings to users that break the forum rules. The value of <guilabel>Warning Duration</guilabel> defines the number of days a warning is valid until it expires. All positive integers are valid values. For more about warnings, please read <xref linkend="moderator_mcp" />.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_board_features">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>dhn</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Board Features</title>
				<para>Through the <guimenuitem>Board Features</guimenuitem> section, you can enable or disable several features board-wide. Note that any feature you disable here will not be available on your forum, even if you give your users permissions to use them.</para>
				<para>The <guimenuitem>Load Settings</guimenuitem> section allows you to disable some features which are computationally expensive if you are on shared or restricted hosting.</para>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_board_avatars">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>dhn</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Avatar Settings</title>
				<para>Avatars are generally small, unique images a user can associate with themselves. Depending on the style, they are usually displayed below the user name when viewing topics. Here you can determine how users can define their avatars.</para>
				<para>There are several ways a user can add an avatar to their profile. The first way is through <guilabel>Gravatar</guilabel>. If this feature is enabled, users can choose to have the board load the Gravatar.com image associated with their email address.</para>
				<para>The second way is through an avatar gallery you provide. Note that there is no avatar gallery available in a default phpBB installation. The <guilabel>Avatar Gallery Path</guilabel> is the path to the gallery images. The default path is <guilabel>images/avatars/gallery</guilabel>. The gallery folder does not exist in the default installation so you have to add it manually if you want to use it.</para>
				<para>The images you want to use for your gallery need to be in a folder inside the gallery path. Images directly in the gallery path won't be recognised.</para>
				<para>The third approach to avatars is through <guilabel>Avatar Uploading</guilabel>. Your members can upload an image from their local system which will be stored on your server. They will be uploaded into the <guilabel>Avatar Storage Path</guilabel> you can define. The default path is <guilabel>images/avatars/upload</guilabel> and does already exist after installation. You have to make sure that it is <glossterm>server-writable</glossterm>. The file format of the images has to be either gif, jpeg, or png, and the avatars will be automatically checked for their file and image size after the upload. You can adjust the <guilabel>Maximum Avatar File Size</guilabel> and images that are bigger than the allowed value will be discarded.</para>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_board_pms">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>dhn</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Private Messaging</title>
				<para><glossterm>Private Messages</glossterm> are a way for registered members to communicate privately through your board without the need to fall back to e-mail or instant messaging. </para>
				<para>You can disable this feature with the <guilabel>Private Messaging</guilabel> setting. This will keep the feature turned off for the whole board. You can disable private messages for selected users or groups with <link linkend="acp_permissions">Permissions</link>. Please see the <link linkend="acp_permissions">Permissions section</link> for more information. </para>
				<para>Rhea allows users to create own personal folders to organise Private Messages. The <guilabel>Maximum private message folders</guilabel> setting defines the number of message folders they can create. The default value is 4. You can disable the feature with setting value to 0. </para>
				<para><guilabel>Max Private Messages Per Box</guilabel> sets the number of Private Messages each folder can contain. The default value is <guilabel>50</guilabel>, Set it to 0 to allow unlimited messages per folder. </para>
				<para>If you limit the number of messages users can store in their folders, you need to define a default action that is taken once a folder is full. This can be changed in the &quot;Full Folder Default Action&quot; list. The oldest message gets deleted or the new message will be held back until the folder has place for it. Note that users will be able to choose this for themselves in their PM options and this setting only changes the default value they face. This will not override the action a user chosen. </para>
				<para>When sending a private message, it is still possible to edit the message until the recipient reads it. After a sent private message has been read, editing the message is no longer possible. To limit the time a message can be edited before the recipient reads it, you can set the <guilabel>Limit Editing Time</guilabel>. The default value is 0, which allows editing until the message is read. Note that you can disallow users or groups to edit Private Messages after sending through <link linkend="acp_permissions">Permissions</link>. If the permission to edit messages is denied, it will override this setting. </para>
				<para>The <guilabel>General Options</guilabel> allow you to further define the functionality of Private Messages on your board. 
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para><guilabel>Allow Mass PMs:</guilabel> enables the sending of Private Messages to multiple recipients. This feature is enabled by default. Disabling it will also disallow sending of Private Messages to groups. </para>
							<tip>
								<para>See the <link linkend="acp_groups">Groups section</link> for information on how to enable the ability to send a message to a whole group.</para>
							</tip>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>By default, <glossterm>BBCode</glossterm> and <glossterm>Smilies</glossterm> are allowed in Private Messages.</para>
							<tip>
								<para>Even if enabled, you can still disallow users or groups to use <glossterm>BBCode</glossterm> and <glossterm>Smilies</glossterm> in Private Messages through <link linkend="acp_permissions">Permissions</link>.</para>
							</tip>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>We don't allow attachments by default. Further settings for attachments in Private Messages are in the <link linkend="acp_board_attachments">Attachment Settings</link>. There you can define the number of attachments per message for instance.</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
			</section>
			<section id="acp_captcha">
        <sectioninfo>
           <authorgroup>
              <author>
                 <othername>Kellanved</othername>
              </author>
           </authorgroup>
        </sectioninfo>
        <title>Spambot Countermeasures</title>
        <para>phpBB 3.2 uses a plugin system to allow easy switching between different spambot countermeasures. Available plugins are automatically loaded from the includes/captcha/plugins directory in your installation. </para>
        <itemizedlist>
           <title>phpBB ships with these plugins installed:</title>
           <listitem><para>GD 3D image: a graphical CAPTCHA using 3D characters on a wave.</para></listitem>
           <listitem><para>GD image: a graphical CAPTCHA, using floating 3D characters.</para></listitem>
           <listitem><para>Simple image: a simple 2D CAPTCHA that should work in any configuration.</para></listitem>
           <listitem><para>reCaptcha: The reCaptcha service. You have to sign up for reCaptcha before being able to use this plugin.</para></listitem>
           <listitem><para>Q&amp;A: configurable questions and answers.</para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
		<note><para><glossterm>CAPTCHA</glossterm> or &quot;Completely Automated Public Turing Test To Tell Computers and Humans Apart&quot; is a term for riddles that are supposedly easy for humans but hard for computers. </para></note>
        <para>The page is split into two  areas, the top area, &quot;General Options&quot;, contains settings concerning where to use spambot countermeasures. The other area concerns itself with the selection, configuration and demonstration of the plugins.</para>
        <figure id="img_acp_captcha">
           <title>Spambot Countermeasures</title>
           <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                 <imagedata format="PNG" fileref="../images/admin_guide/captcha.png"/>
              </imageobject>
           <caption>
           <para>The spambot countermeasure plugin selection ACP page.</para>
           </caption>
           </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <tip>
           <para>Check the Extension database for new existing plugins.</para>
        </tip>
        <itemizedlist>
           <title>How to select a plugin</title>
           <listitem><para>Click the &quot;Installed plugins&quot; dropdown and select the module you want to use. Do not let grayed out entries stop you, they only mean that you have to perform another step. If your intended module is not in the list, check whether the files are present in the plugin directory.</para></listitem>
           <listitem><para>Click the &quot;Configure&quot; button to see the module's ACP page. Many plugins need configuration prior to use. Note that plugins without configuration options will not show the button.</para></listitem>
           <listitem><para>Configure the plugin to meet your needs.</para></listitem>
           <listitem><para>After configuring the plugin, re-select your intended plugin from the dropdown. It should not be grayed out any more.</para></listitem>
           <listitem><para>Click &quot;Submit&quot;.</para></listitem>
           <listitem><para>Congratulations, you’re done.</para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
     </section>
			<section id="acp_contact_page">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>Noxwizard</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Contact Page Settings</title>
				<para>The contact page allows users to email the board administrators if they are experiencing problems with the site. This form is visible to all users, including guests.</para>
				<para>You can enable or disable this feature, as well as set the message that you would like users to see when they visit the page. The message can contain BBcodes, smilies, and links, but not raw HTML.</para>
			</section>
		</section>
		
		<section id="acp_general_client">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>dhn</othername>
					</author>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>			
			<title>Client communication</title>
			<para>Other than its own authentication system, phpBB3 supports other <glossterm>client</glossterm> communications. phpBB3 supports authentication plugins (by default, the Apache, native DB, LDAP, and OAuth plugins), email, and <glossterm>Jabber</glossterm>. Here, you can configure all of these communication methods. The following are subsections describing each client communication method.</para>
		
			<section id="acp_client_auth">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Authentication</title>
				
				<para>phpBB3 offers support for authentication via plugins. By default, the Apache, DB, LDAP, and OAuth plugins are supported. Before switching from phpBB's native authentication system (the DB method) to one of these systems, you must make sure that your server supports it.</para>
				<para>After choosing the authentication method from the dropdwon menu, fill out any fields which appear to finalize configuration.</para>

				<itemizedlist>
					<title>Apache Authentication</title>
					<listitem><para>There are no specific configuration items for this method. You will need to set up authentication in Apache so that your users will be able to access the board. The following documentation can help you set that up: <ulink url="http://httpd.apache.org/docs/current/howto/auth.html">Apache: Authentication and Authorization</ulink>.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>

				<itemizedlist>
					<title>DB Authentication</title>
					<listitem><para>This is the default authentication method and is configured in config.php.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>

				<itemizedlist>
					<title>LDAP Authentication</title>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>LDAP server name</guilabel>: This is the name or IP address of the LDAP server.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>LDAP user</guilabel>: phpBB will connect to the LDAP server as this specified user. If you want to use anonymous access, leave this value blank.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>LDAP password</guilabel>: The password for the LDAP user specified above. If you are using anonymous access, leave this blank.</para><important><para>This password will be stored as plain text in the database; it will be visible to everybody who can access your database.</para></important></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>LDAP base dn</guilabel>: The distinguished name, which locates the user information.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>LDAP uid</guilabel>: The key under which phpBB will search for a given login identity.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>LDAP email attribute</guilabel>: this to the name of your user entry email attribute (if one exists) in order to automatically set the email address for new users. If you leave this empty, users who login to your board for the first time will have an empty email address.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>

				<itemizedlist>
					<title>OAuth Authentication</title>
					<listitem><para>OAuth requires a key and a secret. These are provided to you from the OAuth provider. Each provider may have a different name for the key and secret</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Bitly</guilabel>: Your token information can be found here: <ulink url="https://bitly.com/a/oauth_apps">https://bitly.com/a/oauth_apps</ulink>. Your key is the <emphasis>Client ID</emphasis> and your secret is the <emphasis>Client Secret</emphasis>.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Facebook</guilabel>: You will need to <ulink url="https://developers.facebook.com/apps/">create an application</ulink> on Facebook to obtain your token information. The <emphasis>App ID</emphasis> is your key and the <emphasis>App Secret</emphasis> is your secret.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Google</guilabel>: Visit the <ulink url="https://console.developers.google.com/">Google Developers Console</ulink> to create a new OAuth Client ID. You can find it on the left side under "APIs and auth --> Credentials". Your <emphasis>Client ID</emphasis> will serve as the key and your <emphasis>Client Secret</emphasis> will serve as the secret. Additionally, you will need to create a "Consent screen" in the Developers Console as well. Specify the following <guilabel>Request URIs</guilabel> when you set up your client ID on the Google Developers Console:</para>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem><para>http://{your_board_URL}/ucp.php?mode=login&amp;login=external&amp;oauth_service=google</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>http://{your_board_URL}/ucp.php?i=ucp_auth_link&amp;mode=auth_link&amp;link=1&amp;oauth_service=google</para>
						<para>The link ID may be different from your board. If it is, you will receive an error when attempting to link an account. Change the "1" to the number found in the request URI error that Google gives you.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_client_email">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Email settings</title>
				
				<para>phpBB3 is capable of sending out emails to your users. Here, you can configure the information that is used when your board sends out these emails. phpBB3 can send out emails by using either the native, PHP-based email service, or a specified <glossterm>SMTP</glossterm> server. If you are not sure if you have an SMTP server available, use the native email service. You will have to ask your hoster for further details. Once you are done configuring the email settings, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>.</para>
				
				<note>
					<para>Please ensure the email address you specify is valid, as any bounced or undeliverable messages will likely be sent to that address.</para>
				</note>
				
				<itemizedlist>
					<title>General Settings</title>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Enable board-wide emails</guilabel>: If this is set to disabled, no emails will be sent by the board at all.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Users send email via board:</guilabel>: If this is set to enabled, a form allowing users to send emails to each other via the board will be displayed, rather than an email address.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Email function name</guilabel>: If you are using the native, PHP-based email service, this should be the name of the email function. This is most likely going to be &quot;mail&quot;.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Email package size</guilabel>: This is the number of emails that can be sent in one package. This is useful for when you want to send mass emails, and you have a large amount of users.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Contact email address</guilabel>: This is the address that your board's email feedback will be sent to. This is also the address that will populate the &quot;From&quot; and &quot;Reply-to&quot; addresses in all emails sent by your board.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Return email address</guilabel>: This is the return address that will be put on all emails as the technical contact email address. It will always populate the &quot;Return-Path&quot; and &quot;Sender&quot; addresses in all emails sent by your board.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Email signature</guilabel>: This text will be attached at the end of all emails sent by your board.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Hide email addresses</guilabel>: If you want to keep email addresses completely private, set this value to <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				
				<itemizedlist>
					<title>SMTP Settings</title>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Use SMTP server for email</guilabel>: Select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> if you want your board to send emails via an SMTP server. If you are not sure that you have an SMTP server available for use, set this to <guilabel>No</guilabel>; this will make your board use the native, PHP-based email service, which in most cases is the safest available option.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>SMTP server address</guilabel>: The address of the SMTP server.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>SMTP server port</guilabel>: The port that the SMTP server is located on. In most cases, SMTP servers are located on port 25; do not change this value if you are unsure about this.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Authentication method for SMTP</guilabel>: This is the authentication method that your board will use when connecting to the specified SMTP server. This only applies if an SMTP username and password are set, and required by the server. The available methods are PLAIN, LOGIN, CRAM-MD5, DIGEST-MD5, and POP-BEFORE-SMTP. If you are unsure about which authentication method you must use, ask your hoster for more information.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>SMTP username</guilabel>: The username that phpBB will use when connecting to the specified SMTP server. You should only fill this in if the SMTP server requires it.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>SMTP password</guilabel>: The password for the above specified username that phpBB will use when connecting to the specified SMTP server. You should only fill this in if the SMTP server requires it.</para><important><para>This password will be stored as plain text in the database, visible to everybody who can access your database or who can view this configuration page.</para></important></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_client_jabber">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Jabber settings</title>
				
				<para>phpBB3 also has the ability to communicate messages to users via <glossterm>Jabber</glossterm>, your board can be configured to board notifications via Jabber. Here, you can enable and control exactly how your board will use Jabber for communication.</para>
			
				<note>
					<para>Some Jabber servers include gateways or transports which allow you to contact users on other networks. Not all servers offer all transports and changes in protocols can prevent transports from operating. Note that it may take several seconds to update Jabber account details, so do not stop the script until it has finished!</para>
				</note>
				
				<itemizedlist>
					<title>Jabber settings</title>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Enable Jabber</guilabel>: Set this to <guilabel>Enabled</guilabel> if you want to enable the use of Jabber for messaging and notifications.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Jabber server</guilabel>: The Jabber server that your board will use. For a list of public servers, see <ulink url="http://www.jabber.org">jabber.org</ulink>'s <ulink url="http://www.jabber.org/user/publicservers.shtml">list of open, public servers</ulink>.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Jabber port</guilabel>: The port that the Jabber server specified above is located on. Port 5222 is the most common port; if you are unsure about this, leave this value alone.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Jabber username or JID</guilabel>: The Jabber username or a complete Jabber ID (looks like an e-mail address) that your board will use when connecting to the specified Jabber server. You must specify an already registered account.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Jabber password</guilabel>: The password for the Jabber username specified above. If the Jabber username is unregistered, phpBB3 will attempt to register the above Jabber username, with this specified value as the password.</para><important><para>This password will be stored as plain text in the database, visible to everybody who can access your database or who can view this configuration page.</para></important></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Jabber package size</guilabel>: This is the number of messages that can be sent in one package. If this is set to &quot;0&quot;, messages will be sent immediately and is will not be queued for later sending.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_general_server">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>dhn</othername>
					</author>
					
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>			
			<title>Server configuration</title>
			<para>As an administrator of a board, being able to fine-tune the settings that your phpBB board uses for the server is a must. Configuring your board's server settings is very easy. There are five main categories of server settings: <guimenuitem>Cookie settings</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Server settings</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Security settings</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Load settings</guimenuitem>, and <guimenuitem>Search settings</guimenuitem>. Properly configuring these settings will help your board not only function, but also work efficiently and as intended. The following subsections will outline each server configuration category. Once you are done with updating settings in each setting, remember to click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> to apply your changes.</para>
		
			<section id="acp_server_cookies">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>dhn</othername>
						</author>
						
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>			
				<title>Cookie settings</title>
				<para>Your board uses cookies all the time. Cookies can store information and data; for example, cookies are what enable users to automatically login to the board when they visit it. The settings on this page define the data used to send cookies to your users' browsers.</para>
				
				<warning>
					<para>When editing your board's cookie settings, do so with caution. Incorrect settings can cause such consequences as preventing your users from logging in.</para>
				</warning>
				
				<para>To edit your board's cookie settings, locate the <guilabel>Cookie Settings</guilabel> form. The following are four settings you may edit:
				
					<itemizedlist>
						<title>Cookie Settings</title>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Cookie domain</guilabel>: This is the domain that your board runs on. Do not include the path that phpBB is installed in; only the domain itself is important here.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Cookie name</guilabel>: This is the name that will be assigned to the cookie when it is sent to your users' browsers and stored. This should be a unique cookie name that will not conflict with any other cookies.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Cookie path</guilabel>: This is the path that the cookie will apply to. In most cases, this should be left as &quot;/&quot;, so that the cookie can be accessible across your site. If for some reason you must restrict the cookie to the path that your board is installed in, set the value to the path of your board.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Cookie secure</guilabel>: If your board is only accessible via <acronym>SSL</acronym>, set this to <guilabel>Enabled</guilabel>. If the board is not accessible only via SSL, then leave this value set to <guilabel>Disabled</guilabel>, otherwise server errors will result during redirections and users may experience difficulties remaining logged in.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
				
				<para>When you are done editing your board's server settings, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> to submit your changes.</para>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_server_settings">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>dhn</othername>
						</author>
						
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>			
				<title>Server settings</title>
				<para>On this page, you can define server and domain-dependent settings. There are three main categories of server settings: <guilabel>Server Settings</guilabel>, <guilabel>Path Settings</guilabel>, and <guilabel>Server URL Settings</guilabel>. The following describes each server settings category and the corresponding settings in more detail. When you are done configuring your board's server settings, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> to submit your changes.</para>
				
				<warning>
					<para>When editing your board's server settings, do so with caution. Incorrect settings can cause such consequences as emails being sent out with incorrect links and/or information, or even the board being inaccessible.</para>
				</warning>
				
				<para>The <guilabel>Server Settings</guilabel> form allows you to set some settings that phpBB will use on the server level:
					<itemizedlist>
						<title>Server Settings</title>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Enable GZip Compression</guilabel>: Setting this value will enable <glossterm>GZip</glossterm> compression on your server. This means that all content generated by the server will be compressed before it is sent to users' browsers, if the users' browsers support it. Though this can reduce network traffic/bandwidth used, this will also increase the server and CPU load, on both the user's and server's sides.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Run periodic tasks from system cron</guilabel>: When off, phpBB will arrange for periodic tasks to be run automatically when users visit the board. When on, phpBB will not schedule any periodic tasks by itself; a system administrator must arrange for <emphasis>bin/phpbbcli.php cron:run</emphasis> to be run by the system cron facility at regular intervals (e.g. every 5 minutes).</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>

				<para>Next, the <guilabel>Path Settings</guilabel> form allows you to set the various paths that phpBB uses for certain board content. For default installations, the default settings should be sufficient. The following are the four values that you can set:
					<itemizedlist>
						<title>Path Settings</title>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Enable URL Rewriting</guilabel>: When enabled, URLs containing "app.php" will be rewritten to remove the filename (i.e. app.php/foo will become /foo). This will generally only be seen if you install extensions. This feature is currently limited to Apache web servers with mod_rewrite enabled.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Smilies storage path</guilabel>: This is the path to the directory, relative to the directory that your board is installed in, that your smilies are located in.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Post icons storage path</guilabel>: This is the path to the directory, relative to the directory that your board is installed in, that the topic icons are stored in.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Extension group icons storage path</guilabel>: This is the path to the directory, relative to the directory that your board is installed in, that the icons for the <link linkend="acp_attach_extension_groups">attachments extension groups</link>.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Rank image storage path</guilabel>: This is the path to the directory, relative to the directory that your board is installed in, that your <link linkend="acp_user_ranks">rank images</link> are located in.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
				
				<para>The last category of server settings is <guilabel>Server URL Settings</guilabel>. The <guilabel>Server URL Settings</guilabel> category contains settings that allow you to configure the actual <acronym>URL</acronym> that your board is located at, as well as the server protocol and port number that the board will be accessed to. The following are the five settings you may edit:
					<itemizedlist>
						<title>Server URL Settings</title>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Force server URL settings</guilabel>: If for some reason the default settings for the server URL are incorrect, then you can force your phpBB board to use the server URL settings you specify below by selecting the <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> radio button.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Server protocol</guilabel>: This is the server protocol (http:// or https://, for example) that your board uses, if the default settings are forced. If this value is empty or the above <guilabel>Force server URL settings</guilabel> setting is disabled, then the protocol will be determined by the cookie secure settings.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Domain name</guilabel>: This is the name of the domain that your board runs on. Include &quot;www&quot; if applicable. Again, this value is only used if the server URL settings are forced.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Server port</guilabel>: This is the port that the server is running on. In most cases, a value of &quot;80&quot; is the port to set. You should only change this value if, for some reason, your server runs on a different port. Again, this value is only used if the server URL settings are forced.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Script path</guilabel>: This is the directory where phpBB is installed, relative to the domain name. For example, if your board was located at www.example.com/phpBB3/, the value to set for your script path is &quot;/phpBB3&quot;. Again, this value is only used if the server URL settings are forced.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
				
				<para>When you are done editing your board's server settings, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> to submit your changes.</para>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_server_security">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Security settings</title>
				<para>Here, on the <guimenuitem>Security settings</guimenuitem> page, you are able to manage security-related settings; namely, you can define and edit session and login-related settings. The following describes the available security settings that you can manage. When you are done configuring your board's security settings, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> to submit your changes.</para>
				
				<!-- Perhaps include more introduction information? :-/ -->
				
				<variablelist>
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Allow persistent logins</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This determines whether users can automatically login to your board when they visit it.</para>
							<para>The available options are <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> and <guilabel>No</guilabel>. Choosing <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> will enable automatic logins.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
						
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Persistent login key expiration length (in days)</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This is the set number of days that login keys will last before they expire and are removed from the database.</para>
							<para>You may enter an integer in the text box located to the left of the word <guilabel>Days</guilabel>. This integer is the number of days for the persistent login key expiration. If you would like to disable this setting (and thereby allow use of login keys indefinitely), enter a &quot;0&quot; into the text box.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Session IP validation</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This determines how much of the users' <glossterm>IP address</glossterm> is used to validate a session.</para>
							<para>There are four settings available: <guilabel>All</guilabel>, <guilabel>A.B.C</guilabel>, <guilabel>A.B</guilabel>, and <guilabel>None</guilabel>. The <guilabel>All</guilabel> setting will compare the complete IP address. The <guilabel>A.B.C</guilabel> setting will compare the first x.x.x of the IP address. The <guilabel>A.B</guilabel> setting will compare the first x.x of the IP address. Lastly, selecting <guilabel>None</guilabel> will disable IP address checking altogether.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Validate browser</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This enables the validation of the users' browsers for each session. This can help improve the users' security.</para>
							<para>The available options are <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> and <guilabel>No</guilabel>. Choosing <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> will enable this browser validation.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Validate X_FORWARDED_FOR header</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This setting controls whether sessions will only be continued if the sent X_FORWARDED_FOR header is the same as the one sent with the previous request. Bans will be checked against <glossterm>IP address</glossterm>es in the X_FORWARDED_FOR header too.</para>
							<para>The available options are <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> and <guilabel>No</guilabel>. Choosing <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> will enable the validation of the X_FORWARDED_FOR header.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Check IP against DNS Blackhole List:</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>You are also able to check the users' <glossterm>IP address</glossterm>es against <acronym>DNS</acronym> blackhole lists. These lists are blacklists that list bad IP addresses. Enabling this setting will allow your board to check your users' IP addresses and compare them against the DNS blackhole lists. Currently, the DNS blacklist services on the sites <ulink url="http://www.spamcop.net">spamcop.net</ulink>, <ulink url="http://www.dsbl.org">dsbl.org</ulink>, and <ulink url="http://www.spamhaus.org">spamhaus.org</ulink>.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Check email domain for valid MX record</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>It is also possible to attempt to validate emails used by your board's users. If this setting is enabled, emails that are entered when users register or change the email in their profile will be checked for a valid <ulink url="http://www.wikipedia.org/wiki/MX_record">MX record</ulink>.</para>
							<para>The available options are <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> and <guilabel>No</guilabel>. Choosing <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> will enable the checking of MX records for emails.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Password complexity</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>Usually, more complex passwords fare well; they are better than simple passwords. To help your users try to make their account as secure as possible, you also have the option of requiring that they use a password as complex as you define. This requirement will apply to all users registering a new account, or when existing users change their current passwords.</para>
							<para>There are four options in the selection menu. <guimenuitem>No requirements</guimenuitem> will disable password complexity checking completely. The <guimenuitem>Must be mixed case</guimenuitem> setting requires that your users' passwords have both lowercase and uppercase letters in their password. The <guimenuitem>Must contain alphanumerics</guimenuitem> setting requires that your users' password include both letters from the alphabet and numbers. Lastly, the <guimenuitem>Must contain symbols</guimenuitem> setting will require that your users' passwords include symbols.</para>
							<note>
								<para>For each password complexity requirement, the setting(s) above it in the selection menu will also apply. For example, selecting <guimenuitem>Must contain alphanumerics</guimenuitem> will require your users' passwords to include not only alphanumeric characters, but also have both lowercase and uppercase letters.</para>
							</note>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Force password change</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>It is always ideal to change passwords once in a while. With this setting, you can force your users to change their passwords after a set number of days that their passwords have been used.</para>
							<para>Only integers can be entered in the text box, which is located next to the <guilabel>Days</guilabel> label. This integer is the number of days that, after which, your users will have to change their passwords. If you would like to disable this feature, enter a value of &quot;0&quot;.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Maximum number of login attempts</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>It is also possible to limit the number of attempts that your users can have to try to login. Setting a specific limit will enable this feature. This can be useful in temporarily preventing bots or other users from trying to log into other users' accounts.</para>
							<para>Only integers can be entered for this setting. The number entered it the maximum number of times a user can attempt to login to an account before having to confirm his login visually, with the visual confirmation.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Allow PHP in templates</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>Unlike phpBB2, phpBB3 allows the use of PHP code in the template files themselves, if enabled. If this option is enabled, <guilabel>PHP</guilabel> and <guilabel>INCLUDEPHP</guilabel> statements will be recognized and parsed by the template engine.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
				</variablelist>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_server_load">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Load settings</title>
				<para>On particularly large boards, it may be necessary to manage certain load-related settings in order to allow your board to run as smoothly as possible. However, even if your board isn't excessively active, it is still important to be able to adjust your board's load settings. Adjusting these settings properly can help reduce the amount of processing required by your server. Once you are done editing any of the server load-related settings, remember to click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> to actually submit and apply your changes.</para>
				
				<para>The first group of settings, <guilabel>General Settings</guilabel>, allows you to control the very basic load-related settings, such as the maximum system load and session lengths. The following describes each option in detail.
					<itemizedlist>
						<title>General settings</title>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Limit system load</guilabel>: This option enables you to control the maximum load that the server can undergo before the board will automatically go offline. Specifically, if the systemâ€™s one-minute load average exceeds this value, the board will automatically go offline. A value of &quot;1.0&quot; equals about 100% utilisation of one processor. Note that this option will only work with *nix-based servers that have this information accessible. If your board is unable to get the load limit, this value will reset itself to &quot;0&quot;. All positive numbers are valid values for this option. (For example, if your server has two processors, a setting of 2.0 would represent 100% server utilisation of both processors.) Set this to &quot;0&quot; if you do not want to enable this option.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Session length</guilabel>: This is the amount of time, in seconds, before your users' sessions expire. Valid values are positive integers greater than or equal to 60.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Limit sessions</guilabel>: It is also possible to control the maximum amount of sessions your board will handle before your board will go offline and be temporarily disabled. Specifically, if the number of sessions your board is serving exceeds this value within a one-minute period, the board will go offline and be temporarily disabled. All positive integers are valid values. Set this to &quot;0&quot; if you want to allow an unlimited amount of sessions.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>View online time span</guilabel>: This is the number of minutes after which inactive users will not appear in the <guilabel>Who is Online</guilabel> listings. The higher the number given, the greater the processing power required to generate the listing. All positive integers are valid values, and indicate the number of minutes that the time span will be.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
				
				<para>The second group of settings, <guilabel>General Options</guilabel>, allows you to control whether certain options are available for your users on your board. The following describes each option further.
					<itemizedlist>
						<title>General options</title>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Enable dotted topics</guilabel>: Topics in which a poster has already posted in will see dotted topic icons for these topics. To enable this feature, select, <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Enable server-side topic marking</guilabel>: One of the many new features phpBB3 offers is server-side read tracking. This is different from phpBB2, which only offered read tracking based on cookies. To store read/unread status information in the database, as opposed to in a cookie, select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Enable topic marking for guests</guilabel>: It is also possible to allow guests to have read/unread status information. If you want your board to store read/unread status information for guests, select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>. If this option is disabled, posts will be displayed as &quot;read&quot; for guests.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Enable online user listings</guilabel>: The online user listings can be displayed on your board's index, in each forum, and on topic pages. If you want to enable this option and allow the online user listings to be displayed, choose <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Enable online guest listings in viewonline</guilabel>: If you want to enable the display of guest user information in the <guilabel>Who is Online</guilabel> section, choose <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Enable display of user online/offline information</guilabel>: This option allows you to control whether or not online/offline status information for users can be displayed in profiles and on the topic view pages. To enable this display option, choose <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Enable birthday listing</guilabel>: In phpBB3, birthdays is a new feature. To enable the listing of birthdays, choose <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Enable display of moderators</guilabel>: Though it can be particularly useful to list the moderators who moderate each forum, it is possible to disable this feature, which may help reduce the amount of processing required. To enable the display of moderators, select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Enable display of jumpbox</guilabel>: The jumpbox can be a useful tool for navigating throughout your board. However, it is possible to control whether or not this is displayed. To display the jumpboxes, select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Show user's activity</guilabel>: This option controls whether or not the active topic/forum information displayed in your users' profiles and <glossterm>UCP</glossterm>. If you want to show this user activity information, select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>. However, if your board has more than one million posts, it is recommended that you disable this feature.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Recompile stale templates</guilabel>: This option controls the recompilation of old templates. If this is enabled, your board will check to see if there are updated templates on your filesystem; if there are, your board will recompile the templates. Select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> to enable this option.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Allow usage of third party content delivery networks</guilabel>: If this setting is enabled, some files will be served from external third party servers (ajax.googleapis.com) instead of your server. This reduces the network bandwidth required by your server, but may present a privacy issue for some board administrators. In a default phpBB installation, this includes loading "jQuery" and the font "Open Sans" from Google's content delivery network.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Allow live searches</guilabel>: When enabled, certain search fields (memberlist searches) will automatically prompt with search results as you type.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
				
				<para>Lastly, the last group of load settings relates to <guilabel>Custom Profile Fields</guilabel>, which are a new feature in phpBB3. The following describes these options in detail.
					<itemizedlist>
						<title>Custom Profile Fields</title>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Allow styles to display custom profile fields in memberlist</guilabel>: This option allows you to control if your board's style(s) can display the custom profile fields (if your board has any) in the memberlist. To enable this, choose <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Display custom profile fields in user profiles</guilabel>: If you want to enable the display of custom profile fields (if your board has any) in users' profiles, select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Display custom profile fields in viewtopic</guilabel>: If you want to enable the display of custom profile fields (if your board has any) in the topic view pages, choose <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_server_search">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Search settings</title>
				
				<para>Your board can be a well of information. Being able to effectively search through this information is very important, especially if you want to reduce the amount of redundant topics are posted on your board. Here, on the <guimenuitem>Search settings</guimenuitem> page, you can control what search backend your board's search functionality will use for indexing posts and searching, and set various options related to it. There are four main categories of search settings: <guilabel>General Search Settings</guilabel>, <guilabel>Search Backend</guilabel>, <guilabel>Fulltext mysql</guilabel>, and <guilabel>Fulltext native</guilabel>. The following describes each set of search settings in detail.</para>
			
				<para>The first group of search settings are general and user-facing, meaning that they concern the users who use the search functionality directly.
					<itemizedlist>
						<title>General Search Settings</title>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Enable search facilities</guilabel>: Setting this option to <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> will enable the search functionality for your users; member-searching functionality will also be enabled.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>User search flood interval</guilabel>: This value indicates the number of seconds that your users have to wait between consecutive searches. This value is checked independently for each user. All positive integers are valid values. If you want to disable checking for search intervals for users, set this value to &quot;0&quot;.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Guest search flood interval</guilabel>: This is the number of seconds between searches that guest users must wait. This value is shared for all guest users, if one guest searches, the others will have to wait until this interval passes. All positive integers are valid values. If you want to disable checking for search intervals for guests, set this value to &quot;0&quot;.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Search page system load limit</guilabel>: You can also limit the amount of load your system will undergo for searches. If the system load exceeds this value, your board will go offline and be temporarily disabled. All numbers between 0 and 1.0 (inclusive) are valid values. A value of &quot;1.0&quot;, for example, represents about 100% utilisation of a single processor; if the system load exceeds this value, the board will go offline. Note that this feature only works for *nix-based servers.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Min author name characters</guilabel>: Users have to enter at least this many characters of the name when performing a wildcard author search. If the author's username is shorter than this number, your users can still search for the author's posts by entering the complete username. All positive integers are valid values.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Search result cache length</guilabel>: phpBB3 can also cache search results. These cached search results will expire after this number of seconds. All positive integers are valid values. Set this value to &quot;0&quot; if you want to disable search caching.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
				
				<para>The next group of search settings actually only contains one setting: choosing what backend your board's search facilities, if enabled, will use. The following details this option.
					<itemizedlist>
						<title>Search Backend</title>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Search backend</guilabel>: This option specifies the backend that your board's search facilities will use if it is enabled. The backend is essentially the system/method that is actually responsible for conducting searches based on the queries it is given. There are four available options: <guimenuitem>MySQL Fulltext</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>phpBB Native Fulltext</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>PostgreSQL Fulltext</guimenuitem>, and <guimenuitem>Sphinx Fulltext</guimenuitem>.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
					<note>
						<para>If you choose to change your board's current search backend, you will have to create an index of your board's content for the new search backend. If you know for sure that you're not going to use the index that was used with your old, previously chosen search backend, you can also delete it in order to free up some of your system's resources. To learn more about maintaining your board's search indices, see <xref linkend="acp_maintenance_search" />.</para>
					</note>
				</para>
				
				<para><guimenuitem>MySQL Fulltext</guimenuitem> will make your board use MySQL's fulltext search as its search backend. This causes the SQL server to perform the searches, rather than building our own search tables. The settings shown are informational only and require the server's system administrator for changes to be made.
					<itemizedlist>
						<title>Fulltext mysql</title>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Support for non-latin UTF-8 characters using PCRE</guilabel>: This tells you if your system supports searching for non-Latin <acronym>UTF</acronym>-8 characters. This is only available in <glossterm>PHP</glossterm> versions 4.4 and above, and 5.1 and above. This is only relevant if you actually want your users to have the ability to search for non-Latin characters.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Support for non-latin UTF-8 characters using mbstring</guilabel>: If your system doesn't support UTF-8 characters using <acronym>PCRE</acronym> (as indicated in the setting above), the mySQL fulltext search backend will try to use mbstring's regular expression engine. Again, this is only relevant if you actually want your users to have the ability to seasrch for non-Latin characters.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>

				<para><guimenuitem>phpBB Native Fulltext</guimenuitem> is the default option, which is phpBB's own native fulltext search.
					<itemizedlist>
						<title>Fulltext native</title>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Enable fulltext updating</guilabel>: This option allows you to control whether or not your board's search index will update when posts are made. If you would like to enable this, choose <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>. Note that this setting is not relevant if your board's search functionality is disabled entirely.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Min characters indexed by search</guilabel>: You can also control the minimum number of characters words must contain in order to be included in your board's search index. It is recommended that you not set this too low in order to have a quality search index. All positive integers are valid values.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Max characters indexed by search</guilabel>: Just like the above setting, you can also control the maximum number of characters words must contain in order to be included in your board's search index. If a word has more than this number of characters in it, it will not be included in the search index. All positive integers are valid values.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Common word threshold</guilabel>: Like phpBB2's stopwords feature, you can prevent the use of common words that you specify. However, this feature is expanded upon in phpBB3. You can now control the threshold that a word can have; this means that if a word is contained in more than a certain percentage of posts on your board, it will be deemed as a common word, and will be ignored in search queries. All positive integers are valid values, and represent the percentage of posts on your board words can be contained in. If you would like to disable this threshold and thereby allow searches using all words, even if they can be common, set this value to &quot;0&quot;. This setting only applies if your board has more than 100 posts.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>

				<para><guimenuitem>PostgreSQL Fulltext</guimenuitem> is similar to MySQL Fulltext, but for sites running on a PostgreSQL database.
					<itemizedlist>
						<title>PostgreSQL Fulltext</title>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>PostgreSQL version</guilabel>: This indicates if you are running a version of PostgreSQL that supports Fulltext searches. This feature is available in PostgreSQL 8.3 and above.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Text search Configuration Profile</guilabel>: If your database server has multiple search configurations created, you can choose between them here. The default is <emphasis>simple</emphasis>, though a language specific one may be more appropriate if your board contains non-Latin text.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Minimum word length for keywords</guilabel>: You can also control the minimum number of characters words must contain in order to be included in your board's search index. It is recommended that you not set this too low in order to have a quality search index. All positive integers are valid values.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Maximum word length for keywords</guilabel>: Just like the above setting, you can also control the maximum number of characters words must contain in order to be included in your board's search index. If a word has more than this number of characters in it, it will not be included in the search index. All positive integers are valid values.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>

				<para><guimenuitem>Sphinx Fulltext</guimenuitem> makes use of a special search server called <ulink url="http://sphinxsearch.com/">Sphinx</ulink>. Sphinx will need to be installed prior to configuring it here. If you have a large board with hundreds of thousands of posts or more, you will most likely want to use Sphinx.
					<itemizedlist>
						<title>Sphinx Fulltext</title>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Path to data directory</guilabel>: The absolute path to the data directory where Sphinx should store its indices and log files. The path should have a slash at the end.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Sphinx search daemon host</guilabel>: The hostname or IP address of the search server. Leave blank for localhost.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Sphinx search daemon port</guilabel>: The port which the search server is operating on. Leave blank for its default port 9312.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Indexer memory limit</guilabel>: The amount of memory the search server is allowed to use. This value should be less than the maximum amount of available memory on the system.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Sphinx config file</guilabel>: The generated output for your sphinx.conf file for the search server.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
					After submitting the form, a Sphinx search table will be created in the database. The search indexers must still be started manually before the indices are created. The exact commands needed to do that and more can be found in the server guide: <link linkend="server_sphinx">Sphinx search configuration</link>.
				</para>
			</section>
		</section>		
	</section>
	
	<section id="acp_forums">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Forum Admin</title>
		<para>The <guilabel>Forum</guilabel> section offers the tools to manage your forums. Whether you want to add new forums, add new categories, change forum descriptions, reorder or rename your forums, this is the place to go.</para>
		<section id="acp_forums_types">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>dhn</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Explanation of forum types</title>
			<para>In phpBB 3.2, there are three forum types. A forum can be a normal forum where people can post in, a category that contains forums, or it can be a simple link.</para>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Forum</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>In a forum people can post their topics.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Link</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>The forum list displays a forum link like a normal forum. But instead of linking to a forum, you can point it to a URL of your choice. It can display a hit counter, which shows how many times the link was clicked.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Category</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>If you want to combine multiple forums or links for a specific topic, you can put them inside a category. The forums will appear below the category title, clearly separated from other categories. Users are not able to post inside categories.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>				
			</variablelist>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_forums_subforums">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>dhn</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Subforums</title>
			<para>One of the features in phpBB 3.2 is <glossterm>subforums</glossterm>. Especially bulletin boards with a high number of forums will benefit from this. In the simple flat category and forum approach in phpBB 2.0, all forums and categories were listed on the forum index. In Rhea you can now put as many forums, links, or categories as you like inside other forums.</para>
			<!-- (TODO: Diagram of a 2.0 / 3.0 comparison) -->
			<para>If you have a forum about pets for instance, you are able to put subforums for cats, dogs, or guinea pigs inside it without making the parent "Pets" forum a category. In this example, only the "Pets" forum will be listed on the index like a normal forum. Its subforums will appear as simple links below the forum description (unless you disabled this).</para>
				
			<figure id="img_acp_subforums_list">
				<title>Creating subforums</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata format="PNG" fileref="../images/admin_guide/subforums_list.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Creating subforums. In this example, the subforums titled &quot;Cats&quot; and &quot;Dogs&quot; belong in the &quot;Pets&quot; parent forum. Pay close attention to the breadcrumbs on the page, located right above the list of the subforums. This tells you exactly where you are in the forums hierarchy.</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			
			<para>This system theoretically allows unlimited levels of subforums. You can put as many subforums inside subforums as you like. However, please do not go overboard with this feature. On boards with five to ten forums or less, it is not a good idea to use subforums. Remember, the less forums you have, the more active your forum will appear. You can always add more forums later.</para>
			<para>Read the <link linkend="acp_forums_manage">section on forum management</link> to find out how to create subforums.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_forums_manage">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>dhn</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Manage forums</title>
			<para>Here you can add, edit, delete, and reorder the forums, categories, and links.</para>
			
			<figure id="img_acp_forums_manage_legend">
				<title>Managing Forums Icon Legend</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata format="PNG" fileref="../images/admin_guide/manage_forums_icon_legend.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>This is the legend for the icons on the manage forums page. Each icon allows you to commit a certain action. Pay close attention to which action you click on when managing your forums.</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			
			<para>The initial <guilabel>Manage forums</guilabel> page shows you a list of your top level forums and categories. Note, that this is not analogue to the forum index, as categories are not expanded here. If you want to reorder the forums inside a category, you have to open the category first.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="acp_posting">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
				
				<author>
					<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Posting Settings</title>
		
		<para>Forums are nothing without content. Content is created and posted by your users; as such, it is very important to have the right posting settings that control how the content is posted. You can reach this section by clicking the <guimenuitem>Posting</guimenuitem> navigation tab.</para>
		<para>The first page you are greeted with after getting to the <guimenuitem>Posting Settings</guimenuitem> section is <guilabel>BBCodes</guilabel>. The other available subsections are divided into two main groups: <guilabel>Messages</guilabel> and <guilabel>Attachments</guilabel>. <guimenuitem>Private message settings</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Topic icons</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Smilies</guimenuitem>, and <guimenuitem>Word censoring</guimenuitem> are message-related settings. <guimenuitem>Attachment settings</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Manage extensions</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Manage extension groups</guimenuitem>, and <guimenuitem>Orphaned attachments</guimenuitem> are attachment-related settings.</para>
	
		<section id="acp_posting_bbcodes">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>dhn</othername>
					</author>
					
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>BBCodes</title>
			
			<para><glossterm>BBCodes</glossterm> are a special way of formatting posts, similar to HTML. phpBB 3.2 allows you to create your own BBCodes very easily. On this page, you can see the custom BBCodes that currently exist.</para>
			<para>Adding a BBCode is very easy. If done right, allowing users to use your new BBCode may be safer than allowing them to use HTML code. To add a BBCode, click <guilabel>Add a new BBCode</guilabel> to begin. There are four main things to consider when adding a BBCode: how you want your users to use the BBCode, what HTML code the BBcode will actually use (the users will not see this), what short info message you want for the BBCode, and whether or not you want a button for the new BBCode to be displayed on the posting screen. Once you are done configuring all of the custom BBCode settings, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> to add your new BBCode.</para>
			
			<figure id="img_acp_creating_bbcodes">
				<title>Creating BBCodes</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata format="PNG" fileref="../images/admin_guide/creating_bbcodes.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Creating a new BBCode. In this example, we are creating a new [font] BBCode that will allow users to specify the font face of the specified text.</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			
			<para>In the <guilabel>BBCode Usage</guilabel> form, you can define how you want your users to use the BBCode. Let's say you want to create a new font BBCode that will let your users pick a font to use for their text. An example of what to put under <guilabel>BBCode Usage</guilabel> would be
				<code>[font={SIMPLETEXT}]{TEXT}[/font]</code>
				This would make a new [font] BBCode, and will allow the user to pick what font face they want for the text. The user's text is represented by <guilabel>TEXT</guilabel>, while <guilabel>SIMPLETEXT</guilabel> represents whatever font name the user types in.
			</para>
			<para>In the <guilabel>HTML Replacement</guilabel> form, you can define what HTML code your new BBCode will use to actually format the text. In the case of making a new [font] BBCode, try
				<code>&lt;span style="font-family: {SIMPLETEXT}"&gt;{TEXT}&lt;span&gt;</code>
				This HTML code will be used to actually format the user's text.
			</para>
			<para>The third option to consider when adding a custom BBCode is what sort of help message you want to display to your users if they choose to use the new BBCode. Ideally, the helpline message is a short note or tip for the user using the BBCode. This message will be displayed below the BBCode row on the posting screens.</para>
			<note>
				<para>If the next option described, <guilabel>Display on posting</guilabel>, isn't enabled, the helpline message will not be displayed.</para>
			</note>
			<para>Lastly, when adding a new BBCode, you can decide whether or not you want an actual BBCode button for your new BBCode to be displayed on the posting screens. If you want this, then check the <guilabel>Display on posting</guilabel> checkbox.</para>
			<para>It is important to choose appropriate tokens when creating your custom BBCodes. The tokens limit the type of input that they will accept. If you want to only allow URLs, use the <guilabel>URL</guilabel> token. If you only want to allow numbers, use the <guilabel>NUMBER</guilabel> token.</para>
			
			<variablelist>
				<title>BBCode Tokens</title>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>{TEXT}</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>Any text, including foreign characters, numbers, etc. You should <emphasis role="strong">NOT</emphasis> use this token in HTML element attributes (e.g. <code>&lt;a href="{TEXT}"&gt;</code>). Always use the most restrictive token possible.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>{SIMPLETEXT}</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>Characters from the latin alphabet (A-Z), numbers, spaces, commas, dots, minus, plus, hyphen, and underscore. Does not include apostrophes or quotation marks.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>{INTTEXT}</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>Unicode letter characters, numbers, spaces, commas, dots, minus, plus, hyphen, underscore, and whitespaces. Does not include apostrophes or quotation marks.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>{IDENTIFIER}</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>Characters from the latin alphabet (A-Z), numbers, hyphen, and underscore. Does not include most punctuation marks.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>{NUMBER}</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>Any series of digits.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>{EMAIL}</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>A valid email address.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>{URL}</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>A valid URL using any protocol (http, ftp, etc. cannot be used for javascript exploits). If none is given, "http://" is prefixed to the string.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>{LOCAL_URL}</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>A local URL. The URL must be relative to the topic page and cannot contain a server name or protocol, as links are prefixed with "http://yourdomain/forum/".</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>{RELATIVE_URL}</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>A relative URL. You can use this to match parts of a URL, but be careful: a full URL is a valid relative URL. When you want to use relative URLs of your board, use the LOCAL_URL token.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>{COLOR}</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>A HTML colour, can be either in the numeric form #FF1234 or a <ulink url="http://www.w3.org/TR/CSS21/syndata.html#value-def-color">CSS colour keyword</ulink> such as fuchsia or InactiveBorder.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
			If you need to use the same type of token more than once, you can differentiate between them by adding a number as the last character between the braces, e.g. {TEXT1}, {TEXT2}.
		</section>
		
		<section id="acp_posting_pm_settings">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Private message settings</title>
			
			<para>Many users use your board's private messaging system. Here you can manage all of the default <glossterm>private message</glossterm>-related settings. Listed below are the settings that you can change. Once you're done setting the posting settings, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> to submit your changes.</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<title>General settings</title>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Private messaging</guilabel>: You can enable to disable your board's private messaging system. If you want to enable it, select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Max private message folders</guilabel>: This is the maximum number of new private message folders your users can each create.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Max private messages per box</guilabel>: This is the maximum number of private messages your users can have in each of their folders.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Full folder default action</guilabel>: Sometimes your users want to send each other a private message, but the intended recipient has a full folder. This setting will define exactly what will happen to the sent message. You can either set it so that an old message will be deleted to make room for the new message, or the new messages will be held back until the recipient makes room in his inbox. Note that the default action for the <guilabel>Sentbox</guilabel> is the deletion of old messages.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Limit editing time</guilabel>: Users are usually allowed to edit their sent private messages before the recipient reads it, even if it's already in their outbox. You can control the amount of time your users have to edit sent private messages.</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>	
			
			<itemizedlist>
				<title>General options</title>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Allow sending of private messages to multiple users and groups</guilabel>: In phpBB 3.2, it is possible to send a private message to more than user. To allow this, select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Allow BBCode in private messages</guilabel>: Select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> to allow BBCode to be used in private messages.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Allow smilies in private messages</guilabel>: Select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> to allow smilies to be used in private messages.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Allow attachments in private messages</guilabel>: Select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> to allow attachments to be used in private messages.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Allow signature in private messages</guilabel>: Select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> to let your users include their <glossterm>signature</glossterm> in their private messages.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Allow print view in private messages</guilabel>: Another new feature in phpBB 3.2 is a printer-friendly view. Select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> to allow your users to view any of their PMs in print view.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Allow forwarding in private messages</guilabel>: Select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> to allow your users to forward private messages.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Allow use of [img] BBCode tag</guilabel>: Select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> if you want your users to be able to post inline images in their private messages.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Allow use of [flash] BBCode tag</guilabel>: Select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> if you want your users to be able to post inline Macromedia Flash objects in their private messages.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Enable use of topic icons in private messages</guilabel>: Select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> if you want to enable your users to include topic icons with their private messages. (Topic icons are displayed next to the private messages' titles.).</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			
			<tip>
				<para>If you want to set any of the above numerical settings so that the setting will allow unlimited amounts of the item, set the numerical setting to 0.</para>
			</tip>
		</section>
		
		<section id="acp_posting_topic_icons">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Topic icons</title>
			
			<para>A new feature in phpBB3 is the ability to assign icons to topics. On this page, you can manage what topic icons are available for use on your board. You can add, edit, delete, or move topic icons. The <guilabel>Topic Icons</guilabel> form displays the topic icons currently installed on your board. You can add topic icons manually, install a premade icons pack, export or download an icons pack file, or edit your currently installed topic icons.</para>
		
			<para>Your first option to add topic icons to your board is to use a premade icons pack. Icon packs have the file extension <filename>pak</filename>. To install an icons pack, you must first download an icons pack. Upload the icon files themselves and the pack file into the <filename>/images/icons/</filename> directory. Then, click <guilabel>Install icons pak</guilabel>. The <guilabel>Install icons pak</guilabel> form displays all of the options you have regarding topic icon installation. Select the icon pack you wish to add (you may only install one icon pack at a time). You then have the option of what to do with currently installed topic icons if the new icon pack has icons that may conflict with them. You can either keep the existing icon(s) (there may be duplicates), replace the matches (overwriting the icon(s) that already exist), or just delete all of the conflicting icons. Once you have selected the proper option, click <guilabel>Install icons pak</guilabel>.</para>
			
			<para>To add topic icon(s) manually, you must first upload the icons into the icons directory of your site. Navigate to the <guimenuitem>Topic icons</guimenuitem> page. Click <guilabel>Add multiple icons</guilabel>, which is located in the <guilabel>Topic Icons</guilabel> form. If you correctly uploaded your new desired topic icon(s) into the proper <filename>/images/icons/</filename> directory, you should see a row of settings for each new icon you uploaded. The following has a description on what each field is for. Once you are done with adding the topic icon(s), click, <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> to submit your additions.</para>
			
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Icon image file</guilabel>: This column will display the actual icon itself.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Icon location</guilabel>: This column will display the path that the icon is located in, relative to the <filename>/images/icons/</filename> directory.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Icon width</guilabel>: This is the width (in pixels) you want the icon to be stretched to.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Icon height</guilabel>: This is the height (in pixels) you want the icon to be stretched to.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Display on posting</guilabel>: If this checkbox is checked, the topic icon will actually be displayed on the posting screen.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Icon order</guilabel>: You can also set what order that the topic icon will be displayed. You can either set the topic icon to be the first, or after any other topic icon currently installed.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Add</guilabel>: If you are satisfied with the settings for adding your new topic icon, check this box.</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			
			<para>You may also edit your currently installed topic icons' settings. To do so, click <guilabel>Edit icons</guilabel>. You will see the <guilabel>Icon configuration</guilabel> form. For more information regarding each field, see the above paragraph regarding adding topic icons.</para>
		
			<para>Lastly, you may also reorder the topic icons, edit a topic icon's settings, or remove a topic icon. To reorder a topic icon, click the appropriate "move up" or "move down" icon. To edit a topic icon's current settings, click the "settings" button. To delete a topic icon, click the red "delete" button.</para>
		</section>
		
		<section id="acp_posting_smilies">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Smilies</title>
			
			<para>Smilies or emoticons are typically small, sometimes animated images used to convey an emotion or feeling. You can manage the smilies on your board via this page. To add smilies, you have the option to either install a premade smilies pack, or add smilies manually. Locate the <guilabel>Smilies</guilabel> form, which lists the smilies currently installed on your board, on the page. </para>
		
			<para>Your first option to add smilies to your board is to use a premade smilies pack. Smilies packs have the file extension <filename>pak</filename>. To install a smilies pack, you must first download a smilies pack. Upload the smilies files themselves and the pack file into the <filename>/images/smilies/</filename> directory. Then, click <guilabel>Install smilies pak</guilabel>. The <guilabel>Install smilies pak</guilabel> form displays all of the options you have regarding smilies installation. Select the smilies pack you wish to add (you may only install one smilies pack at a time). You then have the option of what to do with currently installed smilies if the new smilies pack has icons that may conflict with them. You can either keep the existing smilies (there may be duplicates), replace the matches (overwriting the smilies that already exist), or just delete all of the conflicting smilies. Once you have selected the proper option, click <guilabel>Install smilies pak</guilabel>.</para>
			
			<para>To add a smiley to your board manually, you must first upload the smilies into the <filename>/images/smilies/</filename> directory. Then, click on <guilabel>Add multiple smilies</guilabel>. From here, you can add a smilie and configure it. The following are the settings you can set for the new smilies. Once you are done adding a smiley, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>.</para>
		
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Smiley image file</guilabel>: This is what the smiley actually looks like.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Smiley location</guilabel>: This is where the smiley is located, relative to the <filename>/images/smilies/</filename> directory.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Smiley code</guilabel>: This is the text that will be replaced with the smiley.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Emotion</guilabel>: This is the smiley's title.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Smiley width</guilabel>: This is the width in pixels that the smiley will be stretched to.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Smiley height</guilabel>: This is the height in pixels that the smiley will be stretched to.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Display on posting</guilabel>: If this checkbox is checked, this smiley will actually be displayed on the posting screen.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Smiley order</guilabel>: You can also set what order that the smiley will be displayed. You can either set the smiley to be the first, or after any other smiley currently installed.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Add</guilabel>: If you are satisfied with the settings for adding your new smiley, check this box.</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			
			<para>You may also edit your currently installed smilies' settings. To do so, click <guilabel>Edit smilies</guilabel>. You will see the <guilabel>Smiley configuration</guilabel> form. For more information regarding each field, see the above paragraph regarding adding smilies.</para>
			
			<para>Lastly, you may also reorder the smilies, edit a smiley's settings, or remove a smiley. To reorder a smiley, click the appropriate "move up" or "move down" icon. To edit a smiley's current settings, click the "settings" button. To delete a smiley, click the red "delete" button.</para>
		</section>
		
		<section id="acp_posting_censors">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Word censoring</title>
			
			<para>On some forums, a certain level of appropriate, profanity-free speech is required. Like phpBB2, phpBB3 continues to offer word censoring. Words that match the patterns set in the <guilabel>Word censoring</guilabel> panel will automatically be censored with text that you, the admin, specify. To manage your board's word censoring, click <guimenuitem>Word censoring</guimenuitem>.</para>
			
			<para>To add a new word censor, click <guilabel>Add new word</guilabel>. There are two fields: <guilabel>Word</guilabel> and <guilabel>Replacement</guilabel>. Type in the word that you want automatically censored in the <guilabel>Word</guilabel> text field. (Note that you can use wildcards (*).) Then, type in the text you want the censored word to be replaced with in the <guilabel>Replacement</guilabel> text field. Once you are done, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> to add the new censored word to your board.</para>
			
			<para>To edit an existing word censor, locate the censored word's row. Click the "edit" icon located in that row, and proceed with changing the censored word's settings.</para>
		</section>
		
		<section id="acp_attach_settings">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Attachment Settings</title>
			
			<para>If you allow your users to post attachments, it is important to be able to control your board's attachments settings. Here, you can configure the main settings for attachments and the associated special categories. When you are done configuring your board's attachments settings, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>.</para>
			
			<itemizedlist>
				<title>Attachment Settings</title>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Allow attachments</guilabel>: If you want attachments to be enabled on your board, select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Allow attachments in private messages</guilabel>: If you want to enable attachments being posted in private messages, select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Upload directory</guilabel>: The directory that attachments will be uploaded to. The default directory is <filename>/files/</filename>.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Attachment display order</guilabel>: The order that attachments will be displayed, based on the time the attachment was posted.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Total attachment quota</guilabel>: The maximum drive space that will be available for all of your board's attachments. If you want this quota to be unlimited, use a value of 0.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Maximum filesize</guilabel>: The maximum filesize of an attachment allowed. If you want this value to be unlimited, use a value of 0.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Maximum filesize messaging</guilabel>: The maximum drive space that will be available per user for attachments posted in private messages. If you want this quota to be unlimited, use a value of 0.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Max attachments per post</guilabel>: The maximum number of attachments that can be posted in a post. If you want this value to be unlimited, use a value of 0.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Max attachments per message</guilabel>: The maximum number of attachments that can be posted in a private message. If you want this value to be unlimited, use a value of 0.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Enable secure downloads</guilabel>: If you want to be able to only allow attachments to be available to specific <glossterm>IP address</glossterm>es or hostnames, this option should be enabled. You can further configure secure downloads once you have enabled them here; the secure downloads-specific settings are located in the <guilabel>Define allowed IPs/Hostnames</guilabel> and <guilabel>Remove or un-exclude allowed IPs/hostnames</guilabel> forms at the bottom of the page.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Allow/Deny list</guilabel>: This allows you to configure the default behaviour when secure downloads are enabled. A whitelist (<guilabel>Allow</guilabel>) only allows <glossterm>IP address</glossterm>es or hostnames to access downloads, while a blacklist (<guilabel>Deny</guilabel>) allows all users except those who have an <glossterm>IP address</glossterm> or hostname located on the blacklist. <emphasis>This setting only applies if secure downloads are enabled.</emphasis></para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Allow empty referrer</guilabel>: Secure downloads are based on referrers.This setting controls if downloads are allowed for those omitting the referrer information. <emphasis>This setting only applies if secure downloads are enabled.</emphasis></para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Check attachment files</guilabel>: Some browsers can be tricked to assume an incorrect mimetype for uploaded files. This option ensures that such files likely to cause this are rejected. <emphasis>It is recommended that you leave this setting enabled.</emphasis></para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			
			<itemizedlist>
				<title>Image Category Settings</title>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Display images inline</guilabel>: How image attachments are displayed. If this is set to <guilabel>No</guilabel>, a link to the attachment will be given instead, rather than the image itself (or a thumbnail) being displayed inline.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Create thumbnail</guilabel>: This setting configures your board to either create a thumbnail for every image attached, or not.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Maximum thumbnail width in pixels</guilabel>: This is the maximum width in pixels for the created thumbnails.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Maximum thumbnail filesize</guilabel>: Thumbnails will not be created for images if the created thumbnail filesize exceeds this value, in bytes. This is useful for particularly large images that are posted.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Maximum image dimensions</guilabel>: The maximum size of image attachments, in pixels. If you would like to disable dimension checking (and thereby allow image attachments of any dimensions), set each value to 0.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Image link dimensions</guilabel>: If an image attachment is larger than these dimensions (in pixels), a link to the image will be displayed in the post instead. If you want images to be displayed inline regardless of dimensions, set each value to 0.</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			
			<itemizedlist>
				<title>Define Allowed/Disallowed IPs/Hostnames</title>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>IP addresses or hostnames</guilabel>: If you have secure downloads enabled, you can specify the <glossterm>IP address</glossterm>es or hostnames allowed or disallowed. If you specify more than one <glossterm>IP address</glossterm> or hostname, each <glossterm>IP address</glossterm> or hostname should be on its own line. Entered values can have wildcards (*). To specify a range for an <glossterm>IP address</glossterm>, separate the start and end with a hyphen (-).</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Exclude IP from [dis]allowed IPs/hostnames</guilabel>: Enable this to exclude the entered IP(s)/hostname(s).</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
		
		<section id="acp_attach_extensions">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Manage extensions</title>
			
			<para>You can further configure your board's attachments settings by controlling what file extensions attached files can have to be uploaded. It is recommended that you do not allow scripting file extensions (such as php, php3, php4, phtml, pl, cgi, py, rb, asp, aspx, and so forth) for security reasons. You can find this page by clicking <guimenuitem>Manage extensions</guimenuitem> once you're in the <glossterm>ACP</glossterm>.</para>
			
			<para>To add an allowed file extension, find the <guilabel>Add Extension</guilabel> form on the page. In the field labeled <guilabel>Extension</guilabel>, type in the file extension. Do not include the period before the file extension. Then, select the extension group that this new file extension should be added to via the <guilabel>Extension group</guilabel> selection menu. Then, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>.</para>
		
			<para>You can also view your board's current allowed file extensions. On the page, you should see a table listing all of the allowed file extensions. To change the group that an extension belongs to, select a new extension group from the selection menu located in the extension's row. To delete an extension, check the checkbox in the <guilabel>Delete</guilabel> column. When you're done managing your board's current file extensions, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> at the bottom of the page.</para>
		</section>
		
		<section id="acp_attach_extension_groups">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Manage extension groups</title>
			
			<para>Allowed file extensions can be placed into groups for easy management and viewing. To manage the extension groups, click <guimenuitem>Manage extension groups</guimenuitem> once you get into the <guilabel>Posting</guilabel> settings part of the <glossterm>ACP</glossterm>. You can configure specific settings regarding each extension group.</para>
			
			<para>To add a new file extension group, find the textbox that corresponds to the <guilabel>Create new group</guilabel> button. Type in the name of the extension group, then click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>. You will be greeted with the extension group settings form. The following contains descriptions for each option available, and applies to extension groups that either already exist or are being added.</para>
		
			<itemizedlist>
				<title>Add Extension Group</title>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Group name</guilabel>: The name of the extension group.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Special category</guilabel>: Files in this extension group can be displayed differently. Select a special category from this selection menu to change the way the attachments in this extension group is presented within a post.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Allowed</guilabel>: Enable this if you want to allow attachments that belong in this extension group.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Allowed in private messaging</guilabel>: Enable this if you want to allow attachments that belong in this extension group in private messages.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Upload icon</guilabel>: The small icon that is displayed next to all attachments that belong in this extension group.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Maximum filesize</guilabel>: The maximum filesize for attachments in this extension group.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Assigned extensions</guilabel>: This is a list of all file extensions that belong in this extension group. Click <guilabel>Go to extension management screen</guilabel> to manage what extensions belong in this extension group.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Allowed forums</guilabel>: This allows you to control what forums your users are allowed to post attachments that belong in this extension group. To enable this extension group in all forums, select the <guilabel>Allow all forums</guilabel> radio button. To set which specific forums this extension group is allowed in, select the <guilabel>Only forums selected below</guilabel> radio button, and then select the forums in the selection menu.</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			
			<para>To edit a current file extension group's settings, click the "Settings" icon that is in the extension group's row. Then, go ahead and edit the extension group's settings. For more information about each setting, see the above.</para>
		
			<para>To delete an extension group, click the "Delete" icon that is in the extension group's row.</para>
		</section>
		
		<section id="acp_attach_orphaned">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Orphaned attachments</title>
			
			<para>Sometimes, attachments may be orphaned, which means that they exist in the specified files directory (to configure this directory, see the section on <link linkend="acp_attach_settings">attachment settings</link>), but aren't assigned to any post(s). This can happen when posts are deleted or edited, or even when users attach a file, but don't submit their post.</para>
			
			<para>To manage orphaned attachments, click on <guimenuitem>Orphaned attachments</guimenuitem> on the left-hand menu once you're in the <guimenuitem>Posting</guimenuitem> settings section of the <glossterm>ACP</glossterm>. You should see a list of all orphaned attachments in the table, along with all the important information regarding each orphaned attachment.</para>
			
			<para>You can assign an orphaned attachment to a specific post. To do so, you must first find the post's post ID. Enter this value into the <guilabel>Post ID</guilabel> column for the particular orphaned attachment. Enable <guilabel>Attach file to post</guilabel>, then click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>.</para>
		
			<para>To delete an orphaned attachment, check the orphaned attachment's <guilabel>Delete</guilabel> checkbox, then click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>. Note that this cannot be undone.</para>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="acp_users">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
				
				<author>
					<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Users Management</title>

		<section id="acp_users_manage">
			<title>Manage Users</title>
			<para>Users are the basis of your forum. As a forum administrator, it is very important to be able to manage your users. Managing your users and their information and specific options is easy, and can be done via the <acronym>ACP</acronym>.</para>
				
			<para>To begin, log in and reach your <acronym>ACP</acronym>. Find and click on <guimenuitem>Users and Groups</guimenuitem> to reach the necessary page. If you do not see <guimenuitem>User Administration</guimenuitem> , simply find and click on <guimenuitem>Manage Users</guimenuitem> in the navigation menu on the left side of the page.</para>
				
			<para>To continue and manage a user, you must know the username(s) that you want to manage. In the textbox for the <guilabel>"Find a member:"</guilabel> field, type in the username of the user whose information and settings you wish to manage. On the other hand, if you want to find a member, click on <guilabel>[ Find a Member ]</guilabel> (which is below the textbox) and follow all the steps appropriate to find and select a user. If you wiant to manage the information and settings for the Anonymous user (any visitor who is not logged in is set as the Anonymous user), check the checkbox labeled <guilabel>"Select Anonymous User"</guilabel>. Once you have selected a user, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>.</para>
				
			<para>There are many sections relating to a user's settings. The following are subsections that have more information on each form. Each form allows you to manage specific settings for the user you have selected. When you are done with editing the data on each form, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> (located at the bottom of each form) to submit your changes.</para>
			
			<section id="acp_users_manage_overview">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>User Overview</title>
				<para>This is the first form that shows up when you first select a user to manage. Here, all of the general information and settings for each user is displayed.</para>
				
				<variablelist>
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Username</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This is the name of the user you're currently managing. If you want to change the user's username, type in a new username between three and twenty characters long into the textbox labeled <guilabel>Username:</guilabel></para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Registered</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This is the complete date on which the user registered. You cannot edit this value.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Registered from IP</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This is the <acronym>IP</acronym> address from which the user registered his or her account. If you want to determine the <acronym>IP</acronym> hostname, click on the <acronym>IP</acronym> address itself. The current page will reload and will display the appropriate information. If you want to perform a whois on the <acronym>IP</acronym> address, click on the <guilabel>Whois</guilabel> link. A new window will pop up with this data.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Last Active</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This is the complete date on which the user was last active.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Posts</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This number indicates how many posts the user has posted on the board.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Warnings</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This is the number of warnings the user currently has.</para>
							<para>For more information about warnings, see <xref linkend="mcp_warnings"/>.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Founder</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>Founders are users who have all administrator permissions and can never be banned, deleted or altered by non-founder members. If you want to set this user as a founder, select the <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> radio button. To remove founder status from a user, select the <guilabel>No</guilabel> radio button.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Email</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This is the user's currently set email address. To change the email address, fill in the <guilabel>Email:</guilabel> textbox with a valid email.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Confirm email address</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This textbox should only be filled if you are changing the user's email address. If you are changing the email address, both the <guilabel>Email:</guilabel> textbox and this one should be filled with the same email address. If you do not fill this in, the user's email address will not be changed.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>New password</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>As an administrator, you cannot see any of your users' password. However, it is possible to change passwords. To change the user's password, type in a new password in the <guilabel>New password:</guilabel> textbox. The new password has to be between six and thirty characters long.</para>
						
							<important><para>Before submitting any changes to the user, make sure this field is blank, unless you really want to change the user's password. If you accidentally change the user's password, the original password cannot be recovered!</para></important>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Confirm new password</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>This textbox should only be filled if you are changing the user's password. If you are changing the user's password, the <guilabel>Confirm new password:</guilabel> textbox needs to be filled in with the same password you filled in in the above <guilabel>New password:</guilabel> textbox.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term>Quick Tools</term>
						<listitem>
							<para>The options in the <guilabel>Quick Tools</guilabel> drop-down selection box allow you to quickly and easily change one of the user's options. The available options are <guilabel>Delete Signature</guilabel>, <guilabel>Delete Avatar</guilabel>, <guilabel>Move all Posts</guilabel>, <guilabel>Delete all Posts</guilabel>, and <guilabel>Delete all attachments</guilabel>.</para>
						</listitem>
					</varlistentry>
				</variablelist>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_users_manage_feedback">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>User Feedback</title>
				<para>Another aspect of managing a user is editing their feedback data. Feedback consists of any sort of user warning issued to the user by a forum administrator.</para>
				
				<para>To customise the display of the user's existing log entries, select any criteria for your customisation by selecting your options in the drop-down selection boxes entitled <guilabel>Display entries from previous:</guilabel> and <guilabel>Sort by:</guilabel>. <guilabel>Display entries from previous:</guilabel> allows you to set a specific time period in which the feedback was issued. <guilabel>Sort by:</guilabel> allows you to sort the existing log entries by <guimenuitem>Username</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Date</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>IP address</guimenuitem>, and <guimenuitem>Log Action</guimenuitem>. The log entries can then be sorted in ascending or descending order. When you are done setting these options, click the <guilabel>Go</guilabel> button to update the page with your customisations.</para>
			
				<para>Another way of managing a user's feedback data is by adding feedback. Simply find the section entitled <guilabel>Add feedback</guilabel> and enter your message into the <guilabel>FEEDBACK</guilabel> text area. When you are done, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> to add the feedback.</para>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_users_manage_profile">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>User Profile</title>
				
				<para>Users may sometimes have content in their forum profile that requires that you either update it or delete it. If you don't want to change a field, leave it blank.The following are the profile fields that you can change:
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>ICQ Number</guilabel> has to be a number at least three digits long.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>AOL Instant Messenger</guilabel> can have any alphanumeric characters and symbols.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>MSN Messenger</guilabel> can have any alphanumeric characters, but should look similar to an email address (joebloggs@example.com).</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Yahoo Messenger</guilabel> can have any alphanumeric characters and symbols.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Jabber address</guilabel> can have any alphanumeric characters, but needs to look like an email address would (joebloggs@example.com).</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Website</guilabel> can have any alphanumeric characters and symbols, but must have the protocol included (ex. http://www.example.com).</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Location</guilabel> can have any alphanumeric characters and symbols.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Occupation</guilabel> can have any alphanumeric characters and symbols.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Interests</guilabel> can have any alphanumeric characters and symbols.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para><guilabel>Birthday</guilabel> can be set with three different drop-down selection boxes: <guilabel>Day:</guilabel>, <guilabel>Month:</guilabel>, and <guilabel>Year:</guilabel>, respectively. Setting a year will list the user's age when it is his or her birthday.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_users_manage_preferences">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>User Preferences</title>
				
				<para>Users have many settings they can use for their account. As an administrator, you can change any of these settings. The user settings (also known as preferences) are grouped into three main categories: <guilabel>Global Settings</guilabel>, <guilabel>Posting Defaults</guilabel>, and <guilabel>Display Options</guilabel>.</para>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_users_manage_avatar">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>User Avatar</title>
				
				<para>Here you can manage the user's <glossterm>avatar</glossterm>. If the user has already set an avatar for himself/herself, then you are able to see the avatar image.</para>
				<para>Depending on your avatar settings (for more information on avatar settings, see <link linkend="acp_board_avatars">Avatar Settings</link>), you can choose any option available to change the user's avatar: <guilabel>Upload from your machine</guilabel>, <guilabel>Upload from a URL</guilabel>, or <guilabel>Link off-site</guilabel>. You can also select an avatar from your board's avatar gallery by clicking the <guilabel>Display gallery</guilabel> button next to <guilabel>Local gallery:</guilabel>.</para>
				<note>
					<para>The changes you make to the user's avatar still has to comply with the limitations you've set in the avatar settings.</para>
				</note>
				<para>To delete the avatar image, simply check the <guilabel>Delete image</guilabel> checkbox underneath the avatar image.</para>
				<para>When you are done choosing what avatar the user will have, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> to update the user's avatar.</para>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_users_manage_rank">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>User Rank</title>
				
				<para>Here you can set the user's <glossterm>rank</glossterm>. You can set the user's rank by selecting the rank from the <guilabel>User Rank:</guilabel> drop-down selection box. After you've picked the rank, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> to update the user's rank.</para>
				<para>For more information about ranks, see <xref linkend="acp_user_ranks"/>.</para>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_users_manage_signature">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>User Signature</title>
				
				<para>Here you can add, edit, or delete the user's <glossterm>signature</glossterm>.</para>
				<para>The user's current signature should be displayed in the <guilabel>Signature</guilabel> form. Just edit the signature by typing whatever you want into the text area. You can use <glossterm>BBCode</glossterm> and any other special formatting with what's provided. When you are done editing the user's signature, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> to update the user's signature.</para>
				<note>
					<para>The signature that you set has to obey the board's signature limitations that you currently have set.</para>
				</note>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_users_manage_groups">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Groups</title>
				
				<para>Here you can see all of the <glossterm>usergroups</glossterm> that the user is in. From this page you can easily remove the user from any usergroup, or add the user to an existing group. The table entitled <guilabel>Special groups user is a member of</guilabel> lists out the usergroups the user is currently a member of.</para>
				<para>Adding the user to a new usergroup is very easy. To do so, find the pull-down menu labeled <guilabel>Add user to group:</guilabel> and select a usergroup from that menu. Once the usergroup is selected, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>. Your addition will immediately take effect.</para>
				<para>To delete the user from a group he/she is currently a member of, find the row that the usergroup is in, and click <guilabel>Delete</guilabel>. You will be greeted with a confirmation screen; if you want to go ahead and do so, click <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>.</para>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_users_manage_permissions">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Permissions</title>
				
				<para>Here you can see all of the permissions currently set for the user. For each group the user is in, there is a separate section on the page for the permissions that relates to that category. To actually set the user's permissions, see <xref linkend="acp_permissions"/>.</para>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_users_manage_attachments">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Attachments</title>
				
				<para>Depending on the current attachments settings, your users may already have <glossterm>attachments</glossterm> posted. If the user has already uploaded at least one attachment, you can see the listing of the attachment(s) in the table. The data available for each attachment consist of: <guilabel>Filename</guilabel>, <guilabel>Topic title</guilabel>, <guilabel>Post time</guilabel>, <guilabel>Filesize</guilabel>, and <guilabel>Downloads</guilabel>.</para>
				<para>To help you in managing the user's attachment(s), you can choose the sorting order of the attachments list. Find the <guilabel>Sort by:</guilabel> pull-down menu and pick the category you want to use the sort the list (the possible options are <guimenuitem>Filename</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Extension</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Filesize</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Downloads</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Post time</guimenuitem>, and <guimenuitem>Topic title</guimenuitem>. To choose the sorting order, choose either <guimenuitem>Descending</guimenuitem> or <guimenuitem>Ascending</guimenuitem> from the pull-down menu besides the sorting category. Once you are done, click <guilabel>Go</guilabel>.</para>
				<para>To view the attachment, click on the attachment's filename. The attachment will open in the same browser window. You can also view the topic in which the attachment was posted by clicking on the link besides the <guilabel>Topic:</guilabel> label, which is below the filename. Deleting the user's attachment(s) is very easy. In the attachments listing, check the checkboxes that are next to the attachment(s) you want to delete. When everything you want has been selected, click <guilabel>Delete marked</guilabel>, which is located below the attachments listing.</para>
				<tip>
					<para>To select all of the attachments shown on the page, click the <guilabel>Mark all</guilabel> link, which is below the attachments listing. This helps especially if you want to delete all of the attachments shown on the page at once.</para>
				</tip>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_users_inactive">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>Graham</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Inactive Users</title>
			<para>Here you are able to view details of all users who are currently marked as inactive along with the reason their account is marked as inactive and when this occurred.</para>
			<para>Using the checkboxes on this page it is possible to perform bulk actions on the users, these include activating the accounts, sending them a reminder email indicating that they need to activate their account or deleting the account.</para>
			<para>There are 5 reasons which may be indicated for an account being inactive:</para>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Account deactivated by administrator</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>This account has been manually deactivated by an administrator via the <link linkend="acp_users_manage">user management tools</link>. More details on who performed this action and the reasons may be available via the User Notes.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Profile details changed</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>The board is configured to require user activation and this user has changed key information related to their account such as the email address and is required to reactivate the account to confirm these changes.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Newly registered account</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>The board is configured to require user activation and either the user or an administrator (depending on the settings) has not yet activated this new account.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Forced user account reactivation</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>An administrator has forced this user to reactivate their account via the <link linkend="acp_users_manage">user management tools</link>. More details on who performed this action and the reasons may be available via the User Notes.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Unknown</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>No reason was recorded for this user being inactive; it is likely that the change was made by an external application or that this user was added from another source.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
		</section>
		
		<section id="acp_users_permissions">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Users' permissions</title>
			<para>Along with being able to manage users' information, it is also important to be able to regularly maintain and control permissions for the users on your board. User permissions include capabilities such as the use of avatars and sending private messages. Global moderator permissions includings abilities such as approving posts, managing topics, and managing bans. Lastly administrator permissions such as altering permissions, defining custom BBCodes, and managing forums.</para>

			<para>To start managing a user's permissions, locate the <guimenuitem>Users and Groups</guimenuitem> tab and click on <guimenuitem>Users' Permissions</guimenuitem> in the left-side navigation menu. Here, you can assign global permissions to users. In the <guilabel>Look Up User</guilabel>. In the <guilabel>Find a user</guilabel> field, type in the username of the user whose permissions you want to edit. (If you want to edit the anonymous user, check the <guilabel>Select anonymous user</guilabel> checkbox.) Click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>.</para>

			<para>Permissions are grouped into three different categories: user, moderator, and admin. Each user can have specific settings in each permission category. To faciliate user permissions editing, it is possible to assign specific preset roles to the user.</para>

			<important>
				<para>For the following permissions editing actions that are described, there are three choices you have to choose from. You may either select <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>, <guilabel>No</guilabel>, or <guilabel>Never</guilabel>. Selecting <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> will enable the selected permission for the user, while selecting <guilabel>No</guilabel> will disallow the user from having permission for the selected setting, <emphasis>unless another permission setting from another area overrides the setting</emphasis>. If you want to completely disallow the user from having the selected permission <emphasis>ever</emphasis>, then select <guilabel>Never</guilabel>. The <guilabel>Never</guilabel> setting will override all other values assigned to the setting.</para>
			</important>

			<para>To edit the user's <guilabel>User permissions</guilabel>, select "<guimenuitem>User permissions</guimenuitem> from the <guilabel>Select type</guilabel> selection menu, then press <guilabel>Go</guilabel>. Select the role to apply to the user. If you would like to use the advanced form that will offer more detailed permission configuration, click the <guilabel>Advanced Permissions</guilabel> link. A new form will pop up below the <guilabel>Role</guilabel> selection menu. There are four categories of permissions you may edit: <guilabel>Post</guilabel>, <guilabel>Profile</guilabel>, <guilabel>Misc</guilabel>, and <guilabel>Private messages</guilabel>. </para>

			<para>To edit the user's <guilabel>Moderative permissions</guilabel>, select "<guimenuitem>Moderator permissions</guimenuitem> from the <guilabel>Select type</guilabel> selection menu, then press <guilabel>Go</guilabel>. Select the role to apply to the user. If you would like to use the advanced form that will offer more detailed permission configuration, click the <guilabel>Advanced Permissions</guilabel> link. A new form will pop up below the <guilabel>Role</guilabel> selection menu. There are three categories of permissions you may edit: <guilabel>Post actions</guilabel>, <guilabel>Misc</guilabel>, and <guilabel>Topic actions</guilabel>.</para>

			<para>To edit the user's <guilabel>Administrative permissions</guilabel>, select "<guimenuitem>Admin permissions</guimenuitem> from the <guilabel>Select type</guilabel> selection menu, then press <guilabel>Go</guilabel>. Select the role to apply to the user. If you would like to use the advanced form that will offer more detailed permission configuration, click the <guilabel>Advanced Permissions</guilabel> link. A new form will pop up below the <guilabel>Role</guilabel> selection menu. There are six categories of permissions you may edit: <guilabel>Permissions</guilabel>, <guilabel>Posting</guilabel>, <guilabel>Misc</guilabel>, <guilabel>Users &amp; Groups</guilabel>, <guilabel>Settings</guilabel>, and <guilabel>Forums</guilabel>.</para>
		</section>

		<section id="acp_users_forum_permissions">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Users' forum permissions</title>
			
			<para>Along with editing your users' user account-related permissions, you can also edit their forum permissions, which relate to the forums in your board. Forum permissions are different from user permissions in that they are directly related and tied to the forums. <guimenuitem>Users' forum permissions</guimenuitem> allows you to edit your users' forum permissions. When doing so, you can only assign forum permissions to one user at a time.</para>
		
			<para>To start editing a user's forum permissions, start by typing in the user's username into the <guilabel>Find a member</guilabel> text box. If you would like to edit the forum permissions that pertain to the anonymous user, check the <guilabel>Select anonymous user</guilabel> text box. Click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> to continue.</para>
			
			<figure id="img_acp_u_forum_permissions">
				<title>Selecting forums for users' forum permissions</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata format="PNG" fileref="../images/admin_guide/users_forum_permissions.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Selecting forums to assign forum permissions to users. In this example, the &quot;Cats&quot; and &quot;Dogs&quot; subforums (their parent forum is &quot;Pets&quot;) are selected. The user's forum permissions for these two forums will be edited/updated.</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			
			<para>You should now be able to assign forum permissions to the user. You now have two ways to assign forum permissions to the user: you may either select the forum(s) manually with a multiple selection menu, or select a specific forum or category, along with its associated subforums. Click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> to continue with the forum(s) you have picked. Now, you should be greeted with the <guilabel>Setting permissions</guilabel> screen, where you can actually assign the forum permissions to the user. You should now select what kind of forum permissions you want to edit now; you may either edit the user's <guimenuitem>Forum permissions</guimenuitem> or <guimenuitem>Moderator permissions</guimenuitem>. Click <guilabel>Go</guilabel>. You should now be able to select the role to assign to the user for each forum you selected previously. If you would like to configure these permissions with more detail, click the <guilabel>Advanced permissions</guilabel> link located in the appropriate forum permissions box, and then update the permissions accordingly. When you are done, click <guilabel>Apply all permissions</guilabel> if you are in the <guilabel>Advanced permissions</guilabel> area, or click <guilabel>Apply all permissions</guilabel> at the bottom of the page to submit all of your changes on the page.</para>
		</section>
		
		<section id="acp_users_custom_profile_fields">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Custom profile fields</title>
			
			<para>One of the many new features in phpBB3 that enhance the user experience is <guilabel>Custom Profile Fields</guilabel>. In the past, users could only fill in information in the common profile fields that were displayed; administrators had to add MODifications to their board to accommodate their individual needs. In phpBB3, however, administrators can comfortably create custom profile fields through the <acronym>ACP</acronym>.</para>
		
			<para>To create your custom profile field, login to your ACP. Click on the <guimenuitem>Users and Groups</guimenuitem> tab, and then locate the <guimenuitem>Custom profile fields</guimenuitem> link in the left-hand menu to click on. You should now be on the proper page. Locate the empty textbox below the custom profile fields headings, which is next to a selection menu and a <guilabel>Create new field</guilabel> button. Type in the empty textbox the name of the new profile field you want to create first. Then, select the field type in the selection menu. Available options are <guimenuitem>Numbers</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Single text field</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Textarea</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Boolean (Yes/No)</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Dropdown box</guimenuitem>, and <guimenuitem>Date</guimenuitem>. Click the <guilabel>Create new field</guilabel> button to continue. The following describes each of the three sets of settings that the new custom profile field will have.
				<itemizedlist>
					<title>Add profile field</title>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Field type:</guilabel> This is the kind of the field that your new custom profile field is. That means that it can consist of numbers, dates, etc. This should already be set.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Field identification:</guilabel> This is the name of the profile field. This name will identify the profile field within phpBB3's database and templates.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Display profile field:</guilabel> This setting determines if the new profile field will be displayed at all. The profile field will be shown on topic pages, profiles and the memberlist if this is enabled within the load settings. Only showing within the users profile is enabled by default.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				
				<itemizedlist>
					<title>Visibility option</title>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Display in user control panel:</guilabel> This setting determines if your users will be able to change the profile field within the <acronym>UCP</acronym>.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Display at registration screen:</guilabel> If this option is enabled, the profile field will be displayed on the registration page. Users will be able to be change this field within the <acronym>UCP</acronym>.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Required field:</guilabel> This setting determines if you want to force your users to fill in this profile field. This will display the profile field at registration and within the user control panel.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Hide profile field:</guilabel> If this option is enabled, this profile field will only show up in users' profiles. Only administrators and moderators will be able to see or fill out this field in this case.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				
				<itemizedlist>
					<title>Language specific options</title>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Field name/title presented to the user:</guilabel> This is the actual name of the profile field that will be displayed to your users.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Field description:</guilabel> This is a simple description/explanation for your users filling out this field.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</para>
			
			<para>When you are done with the above settings, click the <guilabel>Profile type specific options</guilabel> button to continue. Fill out the appropriate settings with what you desire, then click the <guilabel>Next</guilabel> button. If your new custom profile field was created successfully, you should be greeted with a green success message. Congratulations!</para>
		</section>
		
		<section id="acp_user_ranks">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Managing ranks</title>
			
			<para>Ranks are special titles that can be applied to forum users. As an administrator, it is up to you to create and manage the ranks that exist on your board. The actual names for the ranks are completely up to you; it's usually best to tailor them to the main purpose of your board.</para>
			
			<note>
				<para>When assigning a special rank name to a user, remember that no permissions are associated. For example, if you create a &quot;Support Moderator&quot; rank and assign it to a user, that user will not automatically get moderator permissions. You must assign the user the special permissions separately.</para>
			</note>
			
			<para>To manage your board's ranks, login to your <acronym>ACP</acronym>, click on the <guimenuitem>Users and Groups</guimenuitem> tab, and then click on the <guimenuitem>Manage ranks</guimenuitem> link located in the left-hand menu. You should now be on the rank management page. All current existing ranks are displayed.</para>
			
			<para>To create a new rank, click on the <guilabel>Add new rank</guilabel> button located below the existing ranks list. Fill in the first field <guilabel>Rank title</guilabel> with the name of the rank. If you uploaded an image you want to attribute to the rank into the <filename>/images/ranks/</filename> folder, you can select an image from the selection menu. The last setting you can set is if you want the rank to be a "special" rank. Special ranks are ranks that administrators assign to users; they are not automatically assigned to users based on their postcount. If you selected <guilabel>No</guilabel>, then you can fill in the <guilabel>Minimum posts</guilabel> field with the minimum number of posts your users must have before getting assigned this rank. When you are done, click the <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> button to add this new rank.</para>
			
			<para>To edit a rank's current settings, locate the rank's row, and then click on its "Edit" button located in the <guilabel>Action</guilabel> column.</para>
			
			<para>To delete a rank, locate the rank's row, and then click on its "Delete" button located in the <guilabel>Action</guilabel> column. Then, you must confirm the action by clicking on the <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> button when prompted.</para>
		</section>
				
		<section id="acp_user_security">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>User Security</title>
			<para>Other than being able to manage your users on your board, it is also important to be able to protect your board and prevent unwanted registrations and users. The <guilabel>User Security</guilabel> section allows you to manage banned emails, IPs, and usernames, as well as managing disallowed usernames and user pruning. Banned users that exhibit information that match any of these ban rules will not be able to reach any part of your board.</para>
			
			<section id="acp_ban_emails">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Ban emails</title>
				<para>Sometimes, it is necessary to ban emails in order to prevent unwanted registrations. There may be certain users or spam bots that use emails that you are aware of. Here, in the <guimenuitem>Ban emails</guimenuitem> section, you can do this. You can control which email addresses are banned, how long a ban is in effect, and the given reason(s) for banning.</para>
				
				<para>To ban or exclude one or more email addresses, fill in the <guilabel>Ban one or more email addresses</guilabel> form. Once you are done with your changes, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>.</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<title>Ban one or more email addresses</title>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Email address</guilabel>: This textbox should contain all the emails that you want to ban under a single rule. If you want to ban more than one email at this time, put each email on its own line. You can also use wildcards (*) to match partial addresses.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Length of ban</guilabel>: This is how long you want the email address(es) to be banned for. The available options include some common durations, such as number of hours or days. You may also set a date for which the email address(es) will be banned until; to set this, select <guilabel>Until -></guilabel> from the selection menu, and specify a date in the format "YYYY-MM-DD" in the textbox located below the selection menu.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Exclude from banning</guilabel>: You should enable this if you want to exclude the entered email address from all current bans.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Reason for ban</guilabel>: This is a short reason for why you want to ban the email address(es). This is optional, and can help you remember in the future why you banned the email address(es).</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Reason shown to the banned</guilabel>: This is a short explanation that will actually be shown to the users with the banned email address(es). This can be different from the above <guilabel>Reason for ban</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				
				<para>Other than adding emails to be banned, you can also un-ban or un-exclude email addresses from bans. To un-ban or exclude one or more email addresses from bans, fill in the <guilabel>Un-ban or un-exclude emails</guilabel> form. Once you are done, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>.</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<title>Un-ban or un-exclude emails</title>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Email address</guilabel>: This multiple selection menu lists all currently banned emails. Select the email that you want to un-ban or exclude by clicking on the email in the multiple selection menu. <tip><para>To select more than one email address, you have to use the appropriate combination of mouse and keyboard commands. The most common way to do this is to press and hold down the CTRL button on your keyboard, and then click all of the emails you want to select. Let go of the CTRL button once you are done.</para></tip></para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Length of ban</guilabel>: This is an uneditable information box that shows the length of the ban for the currently selected email. If more than one email address is selected, only one of the ban lengths will be displayed.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Reason for ban</guilabel>: This is an uneditable information box that shows the reason for the ban for the currently selected email. If more than one email address is selected, only one of the ban reasons will be displayed.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Reason shown to the banned</guilabel>: This is an uneditable information box that shows the reason shown to the banned for the currently selected email. If more than one email address is selected, only one of the shown ban reasons will be displayed.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_ban_ips">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Ban IPs</title>
				<para>Sometimes, it is necessary to ban <glossterm>IP address</glossterm>es or hostnames in order to prevent unwanted users. There may be certain users or spam bots that use IPs or hostnames that you are aware of. Here, in the <guimenuitem>Ban IPs</guimenuitem> section, you can do this. You can control which IP addresses or hostnames are banned, how long a ban is in effect, and the given reason(s) for banning.</para>
				
				<para>To ban or exclude one or more IP addresses and/or hostnames, fill in the <guilabel>Ban one or more email addresses</guilabel> form. Once you are done with your changes, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>.</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<title>Ban one or more IPs</title>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>IP addresses or hostnames</guilabel>: This textbox should contain all of the IP addresses and/or hostnames that you want to ban under a single rule. If you want to ban more than one IP address and/or hostname at this time, put each IP address and/or hostname on its own line. You can also use wildcards (*) to match partial addresses.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Length of ban</guilabel>: This is how long you want the IP address(es) and/or hostname(s) to be banned for. The available options include some common durations, such as number of hours or days. You may also set a date for which the IP address(es) and/or hostname(s) will be banned until; to set this, select <guilabel>Until -></guilabel> from the selection menu, and specify a date in the format "YYYY-MM-DD" in the textbox located below the selection menu.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Exclude from banning</guilabel>: You should enable this if you want to exclude the entered IP address(es) and/or hostnames from all current bans.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Reason for ban</guilabel>: This is a short reason for why you want to ban the IP address(es) and/or hostname(s). This is optional, and can help you remember in the future why you banned the IP address(es) and/or hostname(s).</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Reason shown to the banned</guilabel>: This is a short explanation that will actually be shown to the users with the banned IP address(es) and/or hostname(s). This can be different from the above <guilabel>Reason for ban</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				
				<para>Other than adding IP address(es) and/or hostname(s) to be banned, you can also un-ban or un-exclude IP address(es) and/or hostname(s) from bans. To un-ban or exclude one or more IP address(es) and/or hostname(s) from bans, fill in the <guilabel>Un-ban or un-exclude IPs</guilabel> form. Once you are done, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>.</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<title>Un-ban or un-exclude IPs</title>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>IP addresses or hostnames</guilabel>: This multiple selection menu lists all currently banned IP address(es) and/or hostname(s). Select the IP address(es) and/or hostname(s) that you want to un-ban or exclude by clicking on the IP address(es) and/or hostname(s) in the multiple selection menu. <tip><para>To select more than one IP address and/or hostname, you have to use the appropriate combination of mouse and keyboard commands. The most common way to do this is to press and hold down the CTRL button on your keyboard, and then click all of the IP address(es) and/or hostname(s) you want to select. Let go of the CTRL button once you are done.</para></tip></para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Length of ban</guilabel>: This is an uneditable information box that shows the length of the ban for the currently selected IP address or hostname. If more than one IP address or hostname is selected, only one of the ban lengths will be displayed.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Reason for ban</guilabel>: This is an uneditable information box that shows the reason for the ban for the currently selected IP address or hostname. If more than one IP address or hostname is selected, only one of the ban reasons will be displayed.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Reason shown to the banned</guilabel>: This is an uneditable information box that shows the reason shown to the banned for the currently selected IP address or hostname. If more than one IP address or hostname is selected, only one of the shown ban reasons will be displayed.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_ban_users">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Ban Users</title>
				<para>Whenever you encounter troublesome users on your board, you may have to ban them. On the <guimenuitem>Ban usernames</guimenuitem> page, you can do exactly that. On this page, you can manage all banned usernames.</para>
				
				<para>To ban or exclude one or more users, fill in the <guilabel>Ban one or more users</guilabel> form. Once you are done with your changes, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>.</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<title>Ban one or more usernames</title>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Username</guilabel>: This textbox should contain all of the usernames that you want to ban under a single rule. If you want to ban more than one username at this time, put each username on its own line. You can also use wildcards (*) to partially match usernames.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Length of ban</guilabel>: This is how long you want the username(s) to be banned for. The available options include some common durations, such as number of hours or days. You may also set a date for which the username(s) will be banned until; to set this, select <guilabel>Until -></guilabel> from the selection menu, and specify a date in the format "YYYY-MM-DD" in the textbox located below the selection menu.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Exclude from banning</guilabel>: You should enable this if you want to exclude the entered username(s) from all current bans.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Reason for ban</guilabel>: This is a short reason for why you want to ban the username(s). This is optional, and can help you remember in the future why you banned the user(s).</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Reason shown to the banned</guilabel>: This is a short explanation that will actually be shown to the banned user(s). This can be different from the above <guilabel>Reason for ban</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				
				<para>Other than adding users to be banned, you can also un-ban or un-exclude usernames from bans. To un-ban or exclude one or more users from bans, fill in the <guilabel>Un-ban or un-exclude usernames</guilabel> form. Once you are done, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>.</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<title>Un-ban or un-exclude usernames</title>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Username</guilabel>: This multiple selection menu lists all currently banned usernames. Select the username(s) that you want to un-ban or exclude by clicking on the username(s) in the multiple selection menu. <tip><para>To select more than one username, you have to use the appropriate combination of mouse and keyboard commands. The most common way to do this is to press and hold down the CTRL button on your keyboard, and then click all of the usernames you want to select. Let go of the CTRL button once you are done.</para></tip></para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Length of ban</guilabel>: This is an uneditable information box that shows the length of the ban for the currently selected username. If more than one username is selected, only one of the ban lengths will be displayed.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Reason for ban</guilabel>: This is an uneditable information box that shows the reason for the ban for the currently selected username. If more than one username is selected, only one of the ban reasons will be displayed.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Reason shown to the banned</guilabel>: This is an uneditable information box that shows the reason shown to the banned for the currently selected username. If more than one username is selected, only one of the shown ban reasons will be displayed.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_disallow_users">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Disallow usernames</title>
				
				<para>In phpBB3, it is also possible to disallow the registration of certain usernames that match any usernames that you configure. (This is useful if you want to prevent users from registering with usernames that might confuse them with an important board member.) To manage disallowed usernames, go to the ACP, click the <guimenuitem>Users and Groups</guimenuitem> tab, and then click on <guimenuitem>Disallow usernames</guimenuitem>, which is located on the side navigation menu.</para>
				
				<para>To add a disallowed username, locate the <guilabel>Add a disallowed username</guilabel> form, and then type in the username in the textbox labeled <guilabel>Username</guilabel>. <tip><para>You can use wildcards (*) to match any character. For example, to disallow any username that matches "JoeBloggs", you could type in "Joe*". This would prevent all users from registering a username that starts with "Joe".</para></tip> Once you are done, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>.</para>
				
				<para>To remove a disallowed username, locate the <guilabel>Remove a disallowed username</guilabel> form. Select the disallowed username that you would like to remove from the <guilabel>Username</guilabel> selection menu. Click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> to remove the selected disallowed username.</para>
			</section>
			
			<section id="acp_prune_users">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Prune users</title>
				
				<para>In phpBB3, it is possible to prune users from your board in order to keep only your active members. You can also delete a whole user account, along with everything associated with the user account. <guimenuitem>Prune users</guimenuitem> allows you to prune and deactivate user accounts on your board by post count, last visited date, and more.</para>
				
				<para>To start the pruning process, locate the <guilabel>Prune users</guilabel> form. You can prune users based on any combination of the available criteria. (In other words, fill out every field in the form that applies to the user(s) you're targeting for pruning.) When you are ready to prune users that match your specified settings, click <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>.</para>
				
				<itemizedlist>
					<title>Prune users</title>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Username</guilabel>: Enter a username that you want to be pruned. You can use wildcards (*) to prune users that have a username that matches the given pattern.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Email</guilabel>: The email that you want to be pruned. You can use wildcards (*) to prune users that have an email address that matches the given pattern.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Joined</guilabel>: You can also prune users based on their date of registration. To prune users who joined before a certain date (be careful with this setting), choose <guilabel>Before</guilabel> from the selection menu. To prune users who joined after a certain date, choose <guilabel>After</guilabel> from the selection menu. The date must be in the format YYYY-MM-DD.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Last active</guilabel>: You can also prune users based on the last time they were active. To prune users who were last active before a certain date (be careful with this setting), choose <guilabel>Before</guilabel> from the selection menu. To prune users who were last after a certain date (this is useful to prune users who have disappeared from your board), choose <guilabel>After</guilabel> from the selection menu. The date must be in the format YYYY-MM-DD.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Posts</guilabel>: You can prune users based on their post count as well. The criteria for post count can be above, below, or equal to, a specified number. The value you enter must be a positive integer.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Prune users</guilabel>: The usernames of the users you want to prune. Each username you want to prune should be on its own line. You can use wildcards (*) in username patterns as well.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Delete pruned user posts</guilabel>: When users are removed (actually deleted and not just deactivated), you must choose what to do with their posts. To delete all of the posts that belong to the pruned user(s), select the radio button labeled <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>. Otherwise, select <guilabel>No</guilabel> and the pruned user(s)' posts will remain on the board, untouched.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Deactivate or delete</guilabel>: You must choose whether you want to deactivate the pruned user(s)' accounts, or to completely delete and remove them from the board's database.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				
				<warning>
					<para>Pruning users cannot be undone! Be careful with the criteria you choose when pruning users.</para>
				</warning>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>
	
	<section id="acp_groups">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
				
				<author>
					<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		
		<title>Group Management</title>
		
		<para><glossterm>Usergroups</glossterm> are a way of grouping users. This makes it easier to set permissions to many people at the same time. phpBB 3.2 has six pre-defined groups: Administrators, Bots, Global Moderators, Guests, Registered Users, and Registered COPPA Users.</para>
		
		<section id="acp_groups_types">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>dhn</othername>
					</author>
					
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			
			<title>Group types</title>
			<para>There are two types of groups:</para>
			
			<!-- TODO: More info on each pre-defined group? -->
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Pre-defined groups</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>These are groups that are available by default in phpBB 3.2. You <emphasis>cannot</emphasis> delete them, as the board needs them for various features. You can still change their attributes (description, colour, rank, avatar, and so forth) and group leaders. Users that register to your board are automatically added to the predefined group "Registered Users", for instance. Do not try to remove them manually through the database, or your board will no longer function properly.
						
							<variablelist>
								<varlistentry>
									<term>Administrators</term>
									<listitem><para>This usergroup contains all of the administrators on your board. All founders are administrators, but not all administrators are founders. You can control what administrators can do by managing this group.</para></listitem>
								</varlistentry>
								
								<varlistentry>
									<term>Bots</term>
									<listitem><para>This usergroup is meant for search engine bots. phpBB 3.2 has the ability to overcome the common problems that search engine spiders encounter when spidering your board. For more information on managing settings for each bot, see the Spiders and Bots section.</para></listitem>
								</varlistentry>
								
								<varlistentry>
									<term>Global Moderators</term>
									<listitem><para>Global moderators are moderators that have moderator permissions for every forum in your board. You can edit what permissions these moderators have by managing this group.</para></listitem>
								</varlistentry>
								
								<varlistentry>
									<term>Guests</term>
									<listitem><para>Guests are visitors to your board who aren't logged in. You can limit what guests can do by managing this usergroup.</para></listitem>
								</varlistentry>
								
								<varlistentry>
									<term>Registered Users</term>
									<listitem><para>Registered users are a big part of your board. Registered users have already registered on your board. To control what registered users can do, manage this usergroup.</para></listitem>
								</varlistentry>
								
								<varlistentry>
									<term>Registered COPPA Users</term>
									<listitem><para>Registered COPPA users are basically the same as registered users, except that they fall under the <acronym>COPPA</acronym>, or Child Online Privacy Protection Act, law, meaning that they are under the age of 13 in the U.S.A. Managing the permissions this usergroup has is important in protecting these users. <acronym>COPPA</acronym> doesn't apply to users living outside of the U.S.A. and can be disabled altogether.</para></listitem>
								</varlistentry>
							</variablelist>
							
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>User defined groups</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>The groups you create by yourself are called "User defined groups". These groups are similar to groups in 2.0. You may create as many as you want, remove them, set group leaders, and change their attributes (description, colour, rank, avatar, and so forth).</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
			<para>The <guimenuitem>Manage Groups</guimenuitem> section in the <acronym>ACP</acronym> shows you separated lists of both your "User defined groups" and the "Pre-defined groups".</para>
			
		</section>
		<section id="acp_groups_edit">
			<title>Group attributes</title>
			<para>A list of attributes a group can have:</para>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group name</term>
					<listitem><para>The name of your group.</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group description</term>
					<listitem><para>The description of the group that will be displayed on the group overview list.</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry id="acp_groups_edit_legend">
					<term>Display group in legend:</term>
					<listitem><para>This will enable the display of the name of the group in the legend of the &quot;Who is Online&quot; list. Note, that this will only make sense if you specified a colour for the group.</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group able to receive private messages</term>
					<listitem><para>This will allow the sending of Private Messages to this group. Please note, that it can be dangerous to allow this for Registered Users, for instance. There is no permission to deny the sending to groups, so anyone who is able to send Private Messages will be able to send a message to this group!</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group private message limit per folder</term>
					<listitem><para>This setting overrides the per-user folder message limit. A value of &quot;0&quot; means the user default limit will be used. See the <link linkend="ucp_preferences">section on user preferences</link> for more information about private message settings.</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group colour</term>
					<listitem><para>The name of members that have this group as their default group (see <xref linkend="acp_groups_default" />) will be displayed in this colour on all forum pages. If you enable <link linkend="acp_groups_edit_legend"><guilabel>Display group in legend</guilabel></link>, an legend entry with the same colour will appear below the &quot;Who is Online&quot; listing.</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group rank</term>
					<listitem><para>A member that has this group as the default group (see <xref linkend="acp_groups_default" />) will have this rank below his username. Note, that you can change the rank of this member to a different one that overrides the group setting. See the <link linkend="acp_user_ranks">section on ranks</link> for more information.</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Group avatar</term>
					<listitem><para>A member that has this group as the default group (see <xref linkend="acp_groups_default" />) will use this avatar. Note that a member can change his avatar to a different one if he has the permission to do so. For more information on avatar settings, see the <link linkend="ucp_avatar">userguide section on avatars</link>.</para></listitem>
				</varlistentry>				
			</variablelist>
			
		</section>
		<section id="acp_groups_default">
			<title>Default groups</title>
			<para>As it is now possible to assign attributes like colours or avatars to groups (see <xref linkend="acp_groups_edit"/>, it can happen that a user is a member of two or more different groups that have different avatars or other attributes. So, which avatar will the user now inherit? </para>
			<para>To overcome this problem, you are able to assign each user exactly one "Default group". The user will only inherit the attributes of this group. Note, that it is not possible to mix attributes: If one group has a rank but no avatar, and another group has only a avatar, it is not possible to display the avatar from one group and the rank from the other group. You have to decide for one "Default group".</para>
			<important>
				<para>Default groups have no influence on permissions. There is no added permissions bonus for your default group, so a user's permissions will stay the same, no matter what group is his default one.</para>
			</important>
			<para>You can change default groups in two ways. You can do this either through the user management (see <xref linkend="acp_users"/>), or directly through the groups management (<guilabel>Manage groups</guilabel>) page. Please be careful with the second option, as when you change the default group through a group directly, this will change the default group for <emphasis>all</emphasis> its group members and overwrite their old default groups. So, if you change the default group for the &quot;Registered Users&quot; group by using the <guilabel>Default</guilabel> link, all members of your forum will have this group as their default one, even members of the Administrators and Moderators groups as they are also members of &quot;Registered Users&quot;.</para>
			<important>
				<para>If you make a group the default one that has a rank and avatar set, the user's old avatar and rank will be overwritten by the group.</para>
			</important>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_groups_position">
			<title>Group positions</title>
			<para>When groups are set to be shown in the legend, you can change their order on this page. They can be automatically sorted by name or manually by setting their order with the Up and Down arrows. If a group is not shown on the list, a dropdown menu is available to add it to the legend.</para>
			<para>It is also possible to change which groups are shown on the <guilabel>Team</guilabel> page. There are three options available for choosing how members are listed on the <guilabel>Team</guilabel> page.</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>First membership only</guilabel>: Of the groups selected to be shown on the team page, members will only appear in their first group in the list.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>User’s default group only</guilabel>: Of the groups selected to be shown on the team page, members will only appear in their default group.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>All memberships</guilabel>: Users will be shown in each group that is selected to appear on the team page, if they are a member of that group.</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>You may also choose to show which forums each team member is a moderator for.</para>
			<para>Categories can be created to affiliate members of multiple user groups with a common title.</para>
			<para>Finally, you are able to choose which groups are considered <guilabel>Team</guilabel> positions and should be shown on the Team page.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	
	<section id="acp_permissions">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>ameeck</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Permissions</title>
		<para>On your board, you will need to control what users can and cannot do, and what they can and cannot see. With the flexible and detailed system that Rhea provides, you have an extensive ability to manage permissions. There are five types of permissions in phpBB3:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>Global User permissions</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Global Moderator permissions</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Global Administrator permissions</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>User Forum permissions</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Forum Moderator permissions</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>The three <guilabel>Global permissions</guilabel> are ones which apply to every forum or are unrelated to forums altogether.</para>
		<para>The two <guilabel>Forum permissions</guilabel> are ones which apply to only one forum at a time.</para>
		<para>Any of these five permission types may be assigned to individual users or to usergroups.</para>
		<para>When setting permissions, you will encounter three possible values - <guilabel>NO</guilabel>, <guilabel>YES</guilabel> and <guilabel>NEVER</guilabel>, with <guilabel>NO</guilabel> as the default value for each permission. If you set a <guilabel>YES</guilabel>, it overrides the <guilabel>NO</guilabel>, however, if the permission is set to <guilabel>NEVER</guilabel>, you cannot override it by setting it to <guilabel>YES</guilabel> in another place. If you still have problems understanding this system, see the <link linkend="acp_permissions_mask">Permissions Masks</link> section.</para>
		<para>To understand how to set permissions and to know how to use the interface, it is important to recognize the different types of permissions and tools that the Permission tab in the ACP provides:</para>

		<section id="acp_permissions_global">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>ameeck</othername>
					</author>
					<author>
						<othername>stevemaury</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Global Permissions</title>
			<para>These affect the whole board and are not bound to specific forums. They include user permissions, which limit the use of the UCP, searching, private messaging, using of avatars/signatures/etc. Administrator permissions are also set here, as they are Global.</para>

			<section id="acp_permissions_global_user">
				<title>Global User Permissions</title>
				<para>Global User permissions are those permissions which apply to all forums, such as permissions to attach or download files or use a signature, or permissions which are unrelated to a forum, such as permissions relating to profiles, private messages, and email.</para>

				<para>Although Global User permissions can be assigned to users by click <guilabel>Users’ Permissions</guilabel> from your ACP Permissions tab, selecting a user, and then selecting <guilabel>User permissions</guilabel> from the <guilabel>Select type</guilabel> dropdown, it is generally far preferable to avoid using User permissions and use Group permissions instead. This will make it easier to manage permissions in the future and to assign permissions to users in the future. The only practical difference between User permissions and Group permissions is that User permissions require you to set permissions for each user individually, where Group permission let you create a Group and assign its members a set of permissions. Then, if you wish other users to have the same permissions, you can just add them to the Group.</para>

				<para>Global user permissions can be assigned to user groups by clicking <guilabel>Groups’ permissions</guilabel> from your ACP Permissions tab, selecting a user group, and then selecting <guilabel>User permissions</guilabel> from the <guilabel>Select type</guilabel> dropdown.</para>

				<para>In either case, you will be allowed to select a stock User Role in the dropdown, or you can click <guilabel>Advanced Permissions</guilabel> to customise the permissions. However, the better way to customise one of the stock Roles is to create a new User role based on the settings of an existing Role. You can alse create a new User role from scratch. Roles use fewer resource than if you make modifications by editing the Advanced permissions.</para>
			</section>
			<section id="acp_permissions_global_moderator">
				<title>Global Moderator Permissions</title>
				<para>Global Moderator permissions are those permissions which apply to editing, deleting, or otherwise affecting other users’ topics and posts, or to affect other users through reports, warnings, or bans. Permissions given here will apply to any forum the user or user group can see.</para>

				<para>Global Moderator permissions can be assigned to users by clicking <guilabel>Users’ permissions</guilabel> from your ACP Permissions tab, selecting a user, and then selecting <guilabel>Global moderator permissions</guilabel> from the <guilabel>Select type</guilabel> dropdown.</para>

				<para>Global Moderator permissions can be assigned to user groups by clicking <guilabel>Groups’ permissions</guilabel> from your ACP Permissions tab, selecting a user group, and then selecting <guilabel>Global moderator permissions</guilabel> from the <guilabel>Select type</guilabel> dropdown.</para>

				<para>Global Moderator permissions can also be assigned to both users and user groups by clicking <guilabel>Global Moderators</guilabel> from your ACP Permissions tab. This option will display all of the users and user groups who are currently assigned Global Moderator permissions. You can add, edit, or delete users and user groups from this option.</para>

				<para>In either case, you will be allowed to select a stock Moderator Role in the role dropdown, or you can click <guilabel>Advanced Permissions</guilabel> to customise the permissions, or, preferably, create a new Role having the permissions set you desire.</para>
			</section>
			<section id="acp_permissions_global_administrator">
				<title>Global Administrator Permissions</title>
				<para>Global Administrator permissions are those permissions which apply to maintaining your board through the Administration Control Panel. They include permissions for maintaining forums, users, and user groups, maintaining and assigning permissions, changing board configuration settings, and other such board maintenance tasks.</para>

				<para>Global Administrator permissions can be assigned to users by clicking <guilabel>Users’ permissions</guilabel> from your ACP permissions tab, selecting a user, and then selecting <guilabel>Global admin permissions</guilabel> from the <guilabel>Select type</guilabel> dropdown.</para>

				<para>Global Administrator permissions can be assigned to user groups by clicking <guilabel>Groups’ permissions</guilabel> from your ACP permissions tab, selecting a user group, and then selecting <guilabel>Global admin permissions</guilabel> from the <guilabel>Select type</guilabel> dropdown.</para>

				<para>Global Administrator permissions can also be assigned to both users and user groups by clicking <guilabel>Administrators</guilabel> from your ACP Permissions tab. This option will display all of the users and user groups who are currently assigned Administrator permissions. You can add, edit, or delete users and user groups from this option.</para>

				<para>In either case, you will be allowed to select a stock Admin Role in the role dropdown, or you can click <guilabel>Advanced Permissions</guilabel> to customise the permissions, or, preferably, create a new Role having the permissions set you desire.</para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_permissions_forumbased">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>stevemaury</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Forum Permissions</title>
			<para>These permissions are set for each forum/user or group combination individually. They can be divided into two types: User permissions and Moderator permissions. The first control if a user or group can see the forum, post in it, and so on, while the Moderator permissions control if the user or group can do moderator-related actions in it.</para>

			<section id="acp_permissions_forumbased_user">
				<title>User Forum Permissions</title>
				<para>User Forum permissions are those which apply to creating and editing ones own posts in a particular forum and printing and reporting topics. They also determine whether posts require approval or increment the post counter as well as some other user capabilities in a particular forum.</para>

				<para>User Forum permissions can be assigned to users by clicking <guilabel>Users’ forum permissions</guilabel> from your ACP Permissions tab, selecting a user, selecting one or more forums from the list, and then selecting <guilabel>Forum permissions</guilabel> from the <guilabel>Select type</guilabel> dropdown.</para>

				<para>User Forum permissions can be assigned to user groups by clicking <guilabel>Groups’ forum permissions</guilabel> from your ACP Permissions tab, selecting a user group, selecting one or more forums from the list, and then selecting <guilabel>Forum permissions</guilabel> from the <guilabel>Select type</guilabel> dropdown.</para>

				<para>User Forum permissions can also be assigned to both users and user groups by clicking <guilabel>Forum permissions</guilabel> from your ACP Permissions tab, and then selecting one or more forums from the list. This option will display the all of the users and user groups who are currently assigned User Forum permissions for that forum. You can add, edit, or delete users and user groups from this option.</para>

				<para>In either case, you will be allowed to select a stock Forum Role in the role dropdown, or you can click <guilabel>Advanced Permissions</guilabel> to customise the permissions, or, preferably, create a new Role having the permissions set you desire.</para>
			</section>
			<section id="acp_permissions_forumbased_moderator">
				<title>Forum Moderator Permissions</title>
				<para>Forum Moderator permissions are those which apply to editing, deleting, or otherwise affecting other users’ topics and posts in one particular forum, or to affect other users through reports, warnings, or bans.</para>

				<para>Forum Moderator permissions can be assigned to users by clicking <guilabel>Users’ forum permissions</guilabel> from your ACP Permissions tab, selecting a user, selecting one or more forums from the list, and then selecting <guilabel>Moderator permissions</guilabel> from the <guilabel>Select type</guilabel> dropdown.</para>

				<para>Forum Moderator permissions can be assigned to user groups by clicking <guilabel>Groups’ forum permissions</guilabel> from your ACP Permissions tab, selecting a user group, selecting one or more forums from the list, and then selecting <guilabel>Moderator permissions</guilabel> from the <guilabel>Select type</guilabel> dropdown.</para>

				<para>Forum Moderator permissions can also be assigned to both users and user groups by clicking <guilabel>Forum Moderators</guilabel> from your ACP Permissions tab, and then selecting one or more forums from the list. This option will display all of the users and user groups who are currently assigned Forum Moderator permissions for that forum. You can add, edit, or delete users and user groups from this option.</para>

				<para>In either case, you will be allowed to select a stock Moderator Role in the role dropdown, or you can click <guilabel>Advanced Permissions</guilabel> to customise the permissions, or, preferably, create a new Role having the permissions set you desire.</para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_permissions_roles">
			<title>Permission Roles</title>
			<para>To ease setting of permissions, you can create roles that have a pre-defined set of permissions and which you can then assign to users or groups. phpBB already prepared some predefined roles for you to use - e.g., in forum based permissions, you can make each user a Standard Moderator, Full Moderator or Limited Moderator, etc.</para>

			<para>There are four types of Permission Roles:
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem><para>Admin Roles, used with <guilabel>Global Administrator permissions</guilabel></para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>User Roles, used with <guilabel>Global User permissions</guilabel></para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Moderator Roles, used with <guilabel>Global Moderator permissions</guilabel> and <guilabel>Forum Moderator permissions</guilabel></para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Forum Roles, used with <guilabel>User Forum permissions</guilabel></para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</para>

			<para>Permission Roles can be maintained by clicking the corresponding link on the ACP Permissions tab. Roles provide a convenient permissions template to use when assigning permissions to either users or user groups. A Role’s permissions settings can be viewed or edited by clicking the green-gear for that role.</para>

			<para>Most standard Roles use combinations of <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> and <guilabel>No</guilabel>, meaning that if one user is assigned two different roles from being a member of two different groups, for instance Limited Access and Regular Access, the <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>es will override the <guilabel>No</guilabel>s and leave the user with Regular Access.</para>

			<para>The Exceptions are the ones with <guilabel>Never</guilabel> settings, such as the User Roles <guilabel>No Avatar</guilabel> , <guilabel>No PMs</guilabel> and <guilabel>Newly Registered User Features</guilabel>, and the Forum Role <guilabel>On Moderation Queue</guilabel>. These  four Roles use <guilabel>Never</guilabel> settings, and therefore override the <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> settings that would have been granted by other roles.</para>

			<para>You should never use one of these  four roles, or any other <guilabel>Never</guilabel> settings with your Registered Users group. Doing so will take those permissions away from everyone, including yourself.</para>

			<para>If a Role’s permission settings are not quite right for your forum -- for instance, you don’t want anyone to be able to hide their online status -- you can add or subtract a permission to or from a standard Role. Then  wherever that role is used, that permission will be changed.</para>

			<para>You can also create your own custom roles by typing a new name into the <guilabel>Create role</guilabel> box, selecting a role to copy from in the <guilabel>Use settings from</guilabel> dropdown, and click submit. Then you can customise your new role and use it for assigning those permissions.</para>

			<para>Using such custom roles is simpler than editing the advanced permissions for multiple forums and should reduce the resources required by your forum when checking permissions.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_permissions_mask">
			<title>Permission Masks</title>
			<para>In this section, you do not set or change anything, but you can view the final permissions a user or group has based on the combined result of the permissions a user has from his user permissions or group memberships. This feature is particularly useful when you need to debug your permissions and for example, you cannot find out why someone doesn’t have the permission you want him to have. Permission masks is a tool for viewing the permission settings for all five permissions types for both users and user groups.</para>

			<para>Each link on the Permissions Masks section of the ACP Permissions tab corresponds to one of the five permission types:
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem><para>View administrative permissions for <guilabel>Global Administrator permissions</guilabel></para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>View user-based permissions for <guilabel>Global User permissions</guilabel></para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>View global moderation permissions for <guilabel>Global Moderator permissions</guilabel></para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>View forum moderation permissions for <guilabel>Forum Moderators permissions</guilabel></para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>View forum-based permissions for <guilabel>User Forum permissions</guilabel></para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			Any of these five links will take you to a page listing the users and user groups that are assigned those Global or Forum permissions.</para>

			<para>Selecting one or more user groups will display the permissions for those user groups, the same way they are shown in the permissions edit pages, so there is no added utility in running the masks on group names. Permissions masks are most useful when run on a username, and not a group name, since the latter will give you only the same information provided by viewing that group’s permissions.</para>

			<para>Viewing a user’s permissions is much different. If you type a user’s name into the <guilabel>Find a member</guilabel> box for any of the five permission types and click <guilabel>View permissions</guilabel> it will display that user’s resulting permissions, taking into account all of the user's groups’ permissions. Also, the <guilabel>forum moderation</guilabel> mask will take into account global moderation permissions as well.</para>

			<para>Each individual permission will have a circle-arrow which is a link to display all of that user’s groups and which groups grant or deny that permission.</para>
			<figure id="img_choose_group_permissions">
				<title>Permission Masks</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata format="GIF" fileref="../images/admin_guide/permission_masks.gif"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The screens you will see when tracing permissions with the <guilabel>Permission Masks</guilabel> tool.</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<note><para>In this example you see how a Global Moderation <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> overrides a Forum Moderation <guilabel>Never</guilabel>. This is one exception to the rule about <guilabel>Never</guilabel>s overriding <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>es.
			The other exception is <guilabel>Founders</guilabel>. If a user is marked as a Founder on their User Administration Overview page, they will be granted All of the Global Administrator permissions, overriding any <guilabel>No</guilabel> or <guilabel>Never</guilabel> settings given to that user or his user groups.</para></note>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_permissions_shortcuts">
			<title>Other Shortcuts</title>
			<para>The shortcuts on the ACP Permissions tab are sprinkled around other spots in the ACP.
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem><para>The Users’ permissions, Users’ forum permissions, Groups’ permissions, and Groups’ forum permissions links are duplicated on the ACP <guilabel>User and Groups</guilabel>tab</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>The Forum permissions, Forum moderators, Users’ forum permissions, and Groups’ forum permissions links are duplicated on the ACP <guilabel>Forums</guilabel> tab</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>On the <guilabel>Manage Users</guilabel> page, after selecting a User, you can select <guilabel>Permissions</guilabel> on the <guilabel>Select form</guilabel> dropdown:
						<itemizedlist>
							<listitem><para>The three Global permissions Masks are shown by default</para></listitem>
							<listitem><para>The <guilabel>Select a forum</guilabel> dropdown will display the two Forum permissions masks</para></listitem>
							<listitem><para>Set users permissions link leads to update the three Global Permissions</para></listitem>
							<listitem><para>Set users forum permissions link leads to update the two Forum Permissions</para></listitem>
						</itemizedlist>
					</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_permissions_quickstart">
			<title>Permissions Quick Start</title>
			<para>The following permissions can be set to help start a new forum.</para>
			<section id="acp_permissions_quickstart_global_admin">
				<title>Global Administrator Permissions</title>
				<para>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem><para>By default the Administrators user group has the Standard Admin role. This will prevent anyone but the Founder from assigning any other Administrators, editing Roles, and installing any language packs, styles or modules into your forum.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>By default the Standard Admin Role cannot use other’s permissions. This makes maintaining permissions more difficult, so I would recommend editing the <guilabel>Standard Admin</guilabel> Admin role and adding the permission <guilabel>Can use others permissions</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
			</section>
			<section id="acp_permissions_quickstart_global_mod">
				<title>Global Moderator Permissions</title>
				<para>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem><para>By default the Global Moderators user group has the Standard Moderator role. This allows them to moderate any forum they can see, but does not allow them to change a post's author or ban users.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>Add the <guilabel>Standard Moderator</guilabel> or <guilabel>Full Moderator Role</guilabel> to the Administrators user group. This will allow your Administrators to moderate any forum, without having to add them to the Global Moderators user group.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
			</section>
			<section id="acp_permissions_quickstart_global_user">
				<title>Global User Permissions</title>
				<para>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem><para>Administrators and Global Moderators user groups start with All Features User role, which is fine.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>Registered Users start with Standard Features User role, which gives them most normal user rights, but does not allow them to change their username or default user group and a few other things.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>Standard Features User role allows users to hide their online status. You may want to edit this <guilabel>Standard Features</guilabel> role and set this permission to <guilabel>No</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>Guests start with custom Global User permissions that only allow downloading and searching.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
			</section>
			<section id="acp_permissions_quickstart_forum_mod">
				<title>Forum Moderator Permissions</title>
				<para>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem><para>Administrators and Global Moderators would have Global Moderator permissions, so it is unnecessary to assign them as <guilabel>Forum Moderators</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>If you will have junior moderators who will moderate individual forums, add those users to those forums’ moderator lists, or create moderator user groups for those moderators and add the user groups here. Assign the users or user groups appropriate Moderator Roles.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
			</section>
			<section id="acp_permissions_quickstart_user_forum">
				<title>User Forum Permissions</title>
				<para>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem><para>For most forums, give your Administrators and Global Moderators user groups the Full Access Forum Role. This will allow them to make Stickies and Announcements.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>Give your Registered Users user group the <guilabel>Standard Access</guilabel> Forum Role for any forums except your admin/mods only forums or other hidden forums.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>Give <guilabel>Read Only</guilabel> Access Forum Role to the Guests user group for forums you want un-registered guests to be able to read.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>Add the <guilabel>Bot Access</guilabel> Forum Role for the Bots user group for the same forums you want guests to read, so webcrawler searchbots can index those forums.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>The <guilabel>No Access</guilabel> Forum Role would be more useful with <guilabel>Never</guilabel> permissions than its current <guilabel>No</guilabel>s. Edit the <guilabel>No Access</guilabel> Forum Role and change <guilabel>Can see forum</guilabel> and <guilabel>Can read forum</guilabel> from <guilabel>No</guilabel> to <guilabel>Never</guilabel>. This will allow you to use this role to block access to a forum for a small group.</para></listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</para>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_permissions_quick_answers">
			<title>Quick Answers</title>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Nobody can see any of my new forums</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>By default, new forums have no permissions assigned. You have to assign forum permissions, or copy them from another forum before anyone can see them.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>I have Full Administrator permissions. Why can I not see my new forums?</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>Administrator Permissions have nothing to do with Forum Permissions. You have to assign Forum Permissions for yourself or your user group before you can see or post in a forum.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>I have added permissions to my new forums, but I still cannot see them.</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>You also have to add permissions to your forums’ parent categories.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>I have added a new category, with proper permissions, but I cannot see it.</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>Categories will not show unless there are viewable forums under them.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>How can I allow my moderators to create Sticky or Announcement Topics?</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>Sticky and Announcement permissions are in Forum Permissions. Assigning a <guilabel>Full Access</guilabel> forum role will allow them to make Stickies and Announcements.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>I set a sub-forum to copy permissions from its parent forum, but when I changed the permissions for the parent, the sub-forum did not change.</term>
					<listitem>
						<para><guilabel>Copy permissions</guilabel> is an action, not a setting. When you select to Copy permissions it copies the permissions when you click Submit. It will not copy any future changes unless you select to copy them again in Manage Forums, Edit.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>I created a private forum with a special group that has permissions to see the forum. Now, even members of that group cannot see that forum.</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>You probably set <guilabel>Never</guilabel> permissions for the Registered Users group. Since members of your special group are also members of Registered Users, that Never permission is overriding the Yes permission assigned by the new user group. You should be deleting the Registered Users group from that forum’s Forum Permissions list, rather than assigning Never permissions.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="acp_customise">
		<title>Customise</title>
		<para>phpBB 3.2 allows you to customise its appearance and interactions in several ways:</para>
		<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Styles</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>The appearance of your board can be changed by installing new styles or modifying the default style.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Extensions</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>Extensions allow you to easily add new functionality to your board.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Language Packs</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>If your board users speak a language other than English, you can install a language pack to translate the system text (not the board's content) to another language.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>

		<section id="acp_customise_styles">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>ameeck</othername>
					</author>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Styles</title>
			<para>Styling is one aspect of this customisability. Being able to manage the styles your board uses is important in keeping an interesting board. Your board's style may even reflect the purpose of your board. <guimenuitem>Styles</guimenuitem> allows you to manage all the styles available on your board.</para>
			
			<figure id="img_styles_overview">
				<title>Styles overview</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata format="PNG" fileref="../images/admin_guide/styles_overview.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>This is a list of the styles that are installed on the board. You can see the number of users using the style and you can follow the links to change the style's details.</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
				
			<para>Creating a style is not an easy task and it takes quite a lot of time. Skilled designers from the phpBB community create styles that are available publicly and anyone can download them. This is a good place to start if you want to download and install a new style and you cannot afford to create your own, for any possible reason. The first place where you should stop is the <ulink url="https://www.phpbb.com/styles/">Styles section on phpBB.com</ulink>, you will find a list of useful links for places like the:
				<variablelist>
					<varlistentry>
						<term><ulink url="https://www.phpbb.com/styles/demo/3.2/">Styles Demo</ulink></term>
						<listitem><para>The styles demo allows you to display each style on a live forum and see how each part of the board looks like using the specified style. You can browse through the styles until you find one that suits you and/or your board. The styles demo provides links to download the style and see its entry in the styles database.</para></listitem>
					</varlistentry>
					
					<varlistentry>
						<term><ulink url="https://www.phpbb.com/styles/db/">Styles Database</ulink></term>
						<listitem><para>The Style Database contains all the styles that were validated by the phpBB.com Styles Team. All styles are validated to ensure they are safe to use, work correctly and do not have any other caveats. You can filter styles by parameters like version, color or category to easily find a style that you would like. Each style entry in the database contains a link to the Style Demo, to show a live example of the style in use.</para></listitem>
					</varlistentry>

				</variablelist>
			</para>
			
			
			<section id="acp_styles_manage">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>ameeck</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Installing and managing styles</title>
				<para>After you choose a style and you are ready to install it, unpack it on your PC and upload the directory with the style to your board's server. Make sure that the directory you upload to the server's <filename class='directory'>styles</filename> contains the <filename class='directory'>template</filename> and <filename class='directory'>theme</filename> directories, as well as a <filename class='file'>style.cfg</filename> file. The only exception is when a style has its template or theme based on another one, you will however be informed of that when you download the style. Having the dependent style component installed is required to install such a style.</para>
			
				<para>Since you have uploaded all the necessary files, you can continue to install your style. Go to the <guilabel>Customise</guilabel> tab in the ACP and click the <guilabel>Install Styles</guilabel> link. You should see a table containing a list of your uploaded styles. If you want to install your downloaded style, click the <guilabel>Install style</guilabel> link next to its title.</para>
			
				<para>At this moment, you should know how to install a new style. However, there are some links and features on the Styles overview page that we have missed. They are:</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Details</guilabel>: This link will take you to the details of style, where you can change its name, set if the style is active or not, as well as if it should be the board's default style.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Activate/Deactivate</guilabel>: Pretty clear without an explanation, this link allows you to switch the style on and off very quickly and easily.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Uninstall</guilabel>: If you or your users do not like the style anymore, use this link. When you uninstall a style, the users of that style will be switched to the board's default style. You also have the option of completely deleting the style as well if you check the <guilabel>Delete from filesystem</guilabel> box. This will uninstall the style and delete its files, this cannot be undone.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Preview</guilabel>: This is a very useful and powerful feature for administrators. If you click this link, you will be taken to the board and the style you have selected will be applied - this is great when you want to see if the style looks good on your board and you want to make sure you should activate it. This feature can be used even with deactivated styles. The style ID is passed through the URL, so you can browse through the board and see any page you need.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</section>

		</section>
		<section id="acp_customise_extensions">
			<title>Extensions</title>
			<para>Extensions are self-contained packages which are uploaded to your board's <filename class='directory'>ext</filename> directory. Using the <guilabel>Extensions Manager</guilabel>, you can install and manage the extensions running on your board.</para>
			<figure id="img_extensions_overview">
				<title>Extensions overview</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata format="PNG" fileref="../images/admin_guide/extensions_overview.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>This is a list of the extensions that are activated or are ready for use on your board.</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<para>After uploading the extension, it will appear in the <guilabel>Extension Manager</guilabel>, where you simply need to click the <guilabel>Enable</guilabel> link to activate the extension. Once an extension is activated, an <guilabel>Extensions</guilabel> tab will appear in the Administration Control Panel if the extension has any configuration settings. The <guilabel>Details</guilabel> link shows you information about the extension, such as its authors, home page, description, and version requirements. The <guilabel>Current Version</guilabel> column indicates if you have the latest version of the extension. The <guilabel>Settings</guilabel> link at the top of the screen allows you to check for updates on pre-release extensions that are not yet considered to be stable. Your board will periodically check to see if you are running the latest extensions, but you can click the <guilabel>Re-Check all versions</guilabel> link to force a re-check of your extensions' versions.</para>
			
			<para>If a newer version of your extension is available, you can update it by following these steps:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem><para>Disable the extension by clicking the <guilabel>Disable</guilabel> link in the <guilabel>Actions</guilabel> column.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>Delete the extension's files from the board's <filename class='directory'>ext</filename> directory. Only delete the folder that corresponds to the extension you wish to update.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>Upload the latest version of the files to the <filename class='directory'>ext</filename> directory.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>Enable the extension by clicking the <guilabel>Enable</guilabel> link in the <guilabel>Actions</guilabel> column.</para></listitem>
			</orderedlist>

			<para>If you wish to completely remove an extension from your board, follow these steps:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem><para>Disable the extension by clicking the <guilabel>Disable</guilabel> link in the <guilabel>Actions</guilabel> column.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>Delete any data added by the extension by clicking the <guilabel>Delete data</guilabel> link in the <guilabel>Actions</guilabel> column.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>Delete the extension's files from the board's <filename class='directory'>ext</filename> directory. Only delete the folder that corresponds to the extension you wish to update.</para></listitem>
			</orderedlist>

		</section>
		<section id="acp_customise_language">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>ameeck</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Language Packs</title>
			<para>In phpBB, you can upload several language packs for your users to use. Every text string displayed by the system should be translated after you upload a new language pack. Using a different language pack does not change the contents of posts, as translating them is not possible due to the various content they can have and the limits of computer translation.</para>
			<para>Language packs can be downloaded from the <ulink url="https://www.phpbb.com/downloads/">Downloads</ulink> page on phpbb.com.</para>
			<para>To add a language pack, unzip the downloaded file and upload the contents, that is the <filename class='directory'>language</filename> and <filename class='directory'>styles</filename> directories, to the root directory of your board. The board's <filename class='directory'>language/</filename> directory should then contain an addtional directory with the name of the ISO code of the added language, for example, if French is added in addition to the default British English pack, the <filename class='directory'>en/</filename> directory, there will also be a <filename class='directory'>fr/</filename> directory. After you upload the files to the system, the pack should show in the <guilabel>Uninstalled language packs</guilabel> list. Click <guilabel>Install</guilabel> to add it to the board and make it available for users.</para>
			<para>Once the language pack is installed users can select it in User Control Panel &#187; Board preferences &#187; Edit global settings.</para>
			<note>
				<para>To make a language pack the default language of the board, you need to change the <link linkend="acp_general_config">Board Configuration</link>.</para>
			</note>
			<para>In case you have more language packs installed and you select another language pack than the default one, you will see a list of untranslated variables if the packs are not synchronised. This is useful when you install MODs for one language and you cannot find what language strings you are missing in the other ones for example.</para>
			<important>
				<para>Language packs, other than the default British English, are not automatically updated when the board is updated. If you have installed other language packs you will need to update those as well.</para>
			</important>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="acp_maintenance">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
				<author>
					<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
				</author>
				<author>
					<othername>ameeck</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Board Maintenance</title>
		
		<para>Running a phpBB 3.2 board is a very important job that is up to the administrator(s). Maintaining the board to make sure it runs as cleanly and properly as possible is the administrator's job.</para>
		
		<para><guimenuitem>Board Maintenance</guimenuitem> is a section in the <acronym>ACP</acronym> that allows you to keep track of internal phpBB information, such as logs, as well as maintaining your database (which holds your phpBB-related data), such as backing up and restoring data.</para>
		
		<section id="acp_maintenance_logs">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>Graham</othername>
					</author>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Forum Logs</title>
			<para>The <guilabel>Forum Log</guilabel> section of the <acronym>ACP</acronym> provides an overview of what has been happening on the board. This is important for you, the administrator, to keep track of. There are four types of logs:</para>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Admin Log</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>This log records all actions carried out within the administration panel itself.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Moderator Log</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>This logs records the actions performed by moderators of your board. Whenever a topic is moved or locked it will be recorded here, allowing you to see who carried out a particular action.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>User Log</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>This log records all important actions carried out either by users or on users. All email and password changes are recorded within this log.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Error Log</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>This log shows you any errors that were caused by actions done by the board itself, such as errors sending emails. If you are having problems with a particular feature not working, this log is a good place to start. If enabled, addtional debugging information may be written to this log.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
			
			<para>Click on one of the log links located in the left-hand <guilabel>Forum Logs</guilabel> section.</para>
			
			<para>If you have appropriate permissions, you are able to remove any or all log entries from the above sections. To remove log entries, go to the appropriate log entries section, check the log entries' checkboxes, and then click on the <guilabel>Delete marked</guilabel> checkbox to delete the log entries.</para>
		
		</section>
		
		<section id="acp_maintenance_database">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>ameeck</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Database backup and restore</title>
			<para>phpBB uses a database to store all the data used on the board, including users, posts, topics etc. Backing up the database can be useful as a protective measure in case of any accidents which could cause data loss or damage to the database. If any accident like this would occur, you would have a possibility to restore the database to a previous state from the backup. You can use the backup tool to move your board to another host - you will make a backup on your current server and restore it on the new one to keep all data.</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<title>Database backup</title>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Backup type</guilabel>: You can backup the whole database or you can either backup the <guilabel>structure</guilabel> or <guilabel>data</guilabel>. The structure only contains the hierarchy in which the data is stored, on the other side, if you only backup the data, you will need a pre-prepared structure when restoring/importing data.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>File type</guilabel>: Depending on your server setup, you can save the backup in several formats. The <guilabel>Text</guilabel> option saves the backup in plain text, other options compress the file to decrease the filesize of the dump.</para></listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><guilabel>Table select</guilabel>: You can either <guilabel>Select all</guilabel> tables or you can select individual tables to backup. When backing up a large database, you can exclude the search tables (do not forget to restore their structure) and recreate the search index on the new server.</para>
					<tip>
						<para>Use the CTRL and Shift keys together with your mouse to select individual tables.</para>
					</tip>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<itemizedlist>
				<title>Database restore</title>
				<listitem><para>File select: You will be offered a list of database backups which are saved in the store folder. Select the one you want to restore and click <guilabel>Start restore</guilabel>. The restoration might take some time and it will overwrite any existing data on the board.</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<figure id="img_database_restore">
				<title>List of backups available</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata format="PNG" fileref="../images/admin_guide/database_restore.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>In this list, located on the <guilabel>Restore</guilabel> page, you can find a list of backups made through the phpBB <acronym>ACP</acronym> which can be selected and restored.</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<note><para>The ability to download backups from the ACP was removed in 3.2.6. Backups will need to be downloaded from the server using FTP, SCP, or another mechanism.</para></note>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_maintenance_search">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>ameeck</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Search Indexing</title>
			<para>phpBB 3.2 provides you with a powerful search system which can be used to search throughout your board. The main controls for the search features are located in the <link linkend="acp_server_search">Search settings</link> section. Here you can manage the <guilabel>search index</guilabel>, which is used to hold the data necessary for quick and precise search results, it's something like an giant table of contents. By default, two search backends are available - fulltext native, which is included in the phpBB code and works on all <glossterm>DBMS</glossterm>s, and fulltext mysql, which uses the built-in MySQL fulltext searching feature. The first one offers more flexible configuration, while the second one doesn't take too much space in the database and the index is created much faster.</para>
			<note>
				<para>Creating a search index can take a very long time, a new window will pop up and refresh itself while creating the necessary search table entries. Please be patient, the process can take several hours on large boards.</para>
			</note>
			<para>The fulltext native backend works like this: it uses two tables, one containing the words, which are used on the board and which have a numeric ID assigned and a second table, which links post IDs to word IDs. This system is very fast when you need to search a specific word(s) in the whole database, the following statistics, which are offered on the Search Index page, describe how many words and relations the system holds:</para>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term><guilabel>Total number of indexed words</guilabel></term>
					<listitem>
						<para>This setting is quite self-explanatory, it is the number of different words that have ever been posted to your board. Only words that match the criteria for indexing, set in the <link linkend="acp_server_search">Search settings</link>, are considered.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term><guilabel>Total number of word to post relations indexed</guilabel></term>
					<listitem>
						<para>As described above, the second search table holds a list of relations between the posts and words. For example if someone would post "airplane" in two different posts, the system would add the word once and it would add to relations, one to each post.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term><guilabel>Total number of indexed posts</guilabel></term>
					<listitem>
						<para>This statistic is shown for the mysql fulltext backend, where the search is done by a internal mechanism of the Database system. It tells you how many posts on the board were indexed.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="acp_system">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>ameeck</othername>
				</author>
				<author>
					<othername>Graham</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>System Configuration</title>
		<para>Controls which affect the whole board and which are a key part of configuring and running phpBB are located in the System section. Most of these settings require more attention from the administrator and are not so easy to configure, fortunately you will probably not be changing them too often. This includes keeping your installation up-to-date, managing the board's languages or editing the structure of phpBB's control panels.</para>
		<section id="acp_system_updates">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>ameeck</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Checking for updates</title>
			<para>The phpBB 3.2.x branch is usually updated every couple of months as necessary. Bugfixes, new features and other changes are included in these updates. The minor version number gets incremented each time. It is strongly recommended to keep your phpBB installation up to date. Updating from older versions is more difficult and you will have a hard time finding solutions to possible conflicts. You can update with the Automatic Update Package, which is able to merge modifications from MODs with the updates or you can use one of the other packages provided.</para>
			<para>You will be notified in your ACP if a new version is released, you will also have a link to the newest release announcement, which will brief you on the added features and the overall changelog.</para>
			<para>Updating with the Automatic Update Package is very simple. First, you will go to the linked phpBB.com downloads page and download the appropriate file. You will extract the contents on your PC and upload them to the root directory of your board. The board will be offline for normal users for the moment. Then simply go to the <filename class='directory'>install/</filename> directory and select the <guilabel>Update</guilabel> tab, the updater will then give you further instructions.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_system_spiders">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>ameeck</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Managing Search Robots</title>
			<para>phpBB 3 introduced a new system for managing search indexer and bot accounts. It allows you to identify these automated bots by their IP or a part of their user-agent, which is a setting that normally identifies the browser of a user. After you add a bot and it is recognized, phpBB does not treat the session as anonymous, but uses the created bot account. Bots use permissions set by the predefined Bots group. Identifying bots is important so that phpBB can serve them content which is more appropriate for search engines - dead links to pages without content are omitted, e.g. posting pages, report post pages etc. Bots never receive a session ID in the URL, which should not appear in the search results. You can also assign a specific style and language to bots.</para>
			<para>You can easily track if a specific search indexer visited your site recently by checking the <guilabel>Last Visit</guilabel> column on the botlist page.</para>
			<note>
				<para>Bots do not use permissions from the Guest group, but permissions from the Bots group. For more about predefined groups, please read <xref linkend="acp_groups_types"/></para>
			</note>
			<itemizedlist>
				<title>Adding a bot</title>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Bot name</guilabel>: This is the title of the bot that will be used on the forum. You will see it in the list of bots in the <acronym>ACP</acronym> and in the Who is Online lists.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Bot style</guilabel>: You can select the style served to the bot from the list of installed styles on the board.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Bot language</guilabel>: You can do the same with the language. The bot will use the language selected here.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Bot active</guilabel>: The bot session will be created only if a bot is active, if not, the data for a bot set in this form will not be used anywhere.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Agent match</guilabel>: You can match a bot by either its user-agent or its IP. You can specify a part of the user-agent to be looked for. For example, the Google search indexer has "Googlebot" in its user-agent, so you would enter it here to identify when Google crawls your board.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Bot IP address</guilabel>: This field is also used to identify the bot. If a bot cannot be recognized by the user-agent, you can specify what <glossterm>IP address</glossterm> should be used to identify it. Partial matches are allowed, that means you can include only the first two or three octets of the IP if the rest dynamically changes. You can also enter multiple IPs separated by a comma.</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<note>
				<para>If you enter both a user-agent and an <glossterm>IP address</glossterm>, both have to match to identify the bot.</para>
			</note>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_system_mail">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>ameeck</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Mass email</title>
			<para>phpBB allows you to send an e-mail or message to every user on the board, which allows it in his <link linkend="ucp_preferences">board preferences</link>. The message can serve as a newsletter, notification about changes on the board etc. You can choose whether to send the e-mail to all users, a specific group or a list of specific users. The e-mail is sent from the administrator's e-mail address and all recipients are included in a BCC - Blind Carbon Copy.</para>
			<para>On some hosts, sending a mass e-mail can be a problem, since sometimes the hosting company limits the number of e-mails that can be sent out at once. phpBB includes only 50 recipients per e-mail and sends another one for the next batch to prevent this, however, if you still are not able to send a mass e-mail, consult the situation with your hosting provider.</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<title>Composing a mass e-mail</title>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Send to group</guilabel>: Select the group you want to send the e-mail too. The Registered Users group contains all the users on the board.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Send to users</guilabel>: You can also specify a list of users. Entering any usernames in this field will override the first setting. Each username should be on a new line.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Subject</guilabel>: This is the subject of the message, which you are used to enter when sending an e-mail.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Your message</guilabel>: This field contains the message, you can only enter plaintext. <glossterm>BBCode</glossterm> or HTML will be encoded in HTML entities and shown as is without formatting the text when the user receives the e-mail.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Mail priority</guilabel>: This is the priority of the e-mail sent with the e-mail headers.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Mail banned users</guilabel>: By default, banned users will not receive mass e-mails. Check this box if you would like to include those users in the mail mailing.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Send immediately</guilabel>: You can choose whether to send the e-mail immediately or pass the messages to the cache system and let them be sent gradually.</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<note>
				<para>Sending e-mails to all users on the board or a large group can be a lengthy process. Wait until the script confirms that the e-mails have been sent.</para>
			</note>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_system_phpinfo">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>Graham</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>PHP Information</title>
			<para>This option will provide you with information about the version of PHP installed on your server, along with information on loaded modules and the configuration applicable to the current location. This information can be useful to phpBB team members in helping you to diagnose problems affecting your installation of phpBB. The information here can be security sensitive and it is recommended that you only grant access to this option to those users who need access to the information and do not disclose the information unless necessary.</para>
			<para>Please note that some hosting providers may limit the information which is available to you on this page for security reasons.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_system_reasons">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>ameeck</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Manage reasons for reporting and denying posts</title>
			<para>phpBB has a feature that allows you to put new posts in queue, where the post waits until it is approved or denied by a moderator, this can be set with permissions or in the <guilabel>Post settings</guilabel> for users which do not have enough posts. If a moderator chooses to deny a post in the queue, he has an option to specify a reason for the denial. The predefined options from which he can choose are specified here. These reasons are also offered to users reporting a post on the board.</para>
			<para>For more information about queue moderation, see <xref linkend="mcp_queue"/>.</para>
			<figure id="img_denial_reasons">
				<title>Report/denial reasons page</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata format="PNG" fileref="../images/admin_guide/denial_reasons.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>This is the page from which you can manage reasons shown when denying or reporting a post. Four default reasons present in a standard phpBB installation are shown. The fifth one is added manually and is not localised, this can be achieved by specifying an identifier in the <guilabel>Reason title</guilabel> containing only letters and underscores and then adding localised titles and reasons in the language file called <filename>mcp.php</filename> located in the <filename>language/</filename> directory. The predefined reasons are at the bottom of the file, you need to add your reason in the same way as the others are saved. When you localise a reason, it is shown in the correct translation for each language pack used on the board.</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
		</section>
		<section id="acp_system_modules">
		 	<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>ameeck</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Module Management</title>
			<para>Modules are used the form the structure and content of the <acronym>UCP</acronym>, <acronym>MCP</acronym> and <acronym>ACP</acronym>. Individual modules can be optionally disabled and it is possible to reorganize them into a different structure. Modules for the User Control Panel and the Moderator Control panel have a Category &#187; Module two-level structure, while the Administration modules have three levels: Category (tabs at the top) &#187; Category (headers on the left-hand side) &#187; Module (individual sections).</para>
			<para>Very often, extensions that have controllable features add modules to the ACP to allow comfortable editing of various settings.</para>
			<para>To create a module category, use the text field next to the <guilabel>Create new module</guilabel> button. Enter the category title, click the button and on the next page ensure that the <guilabel>Module type</guilabel> is <guilabel>Category</guilabel>, the module is <guilabel>enabled</guilabel> and that the <guilabel>Module parent</guilabel> is set correctly. After you create a category, you can browse to it through the list of modules and add a specific module that is saved in a file. Modules are saved in the appropriate directory (acp/, mcp/ or /ucp) contained in the <filename>includes/</filename> directory.</para>
			<warning><para>By disabling the Module Management module, it is possible to cut yourself off from the ACP and other control panels. Be careful when you are editing modules.</para></warning>
			<itemizedlist>
				<title>Adding a module</title>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Module language name</guilabel>: This should be set to the language constant that holds the module name in the different languages, which are used on the board. You can also specify a normal title here, if you do not have the module title translated.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Module type</guilabel>: You can add a category or a module. As stated above, categories hold another level of categories or modules, they are used to organize the control panels.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Parent</guilabel>: This setting defines under which category the module or category will be displayed.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Module enabled</guilabel>: If a module is disabled, it will not be accessible at all, you will have to enable it to use it.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Module displayed</guilabel>: If the module is enabled, but not displayed, you will be able to access it with a direct URL but it will not show in the menus. This setting is shown only if the <guilabel>Module type</guilabel> is set to Module.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Choose module</guilabel>: Individual module files contain the various control panels. Similar modules are grouped into one file and are called by specifying a mode. Here you select the file in which the specific module you want is located. This setting is shown only if the <guilabel>Module type</guilabel> is set to Module.</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para><guilabel>Choose module mode</guilabel>: Here you set the what mode should be used in the module file selected above. The final contents of the module are based on this setting. This setting is shown only if the <guilabel>Module type</guilabel> is set to Module.</para></listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
