<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
                         "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="quick_start_guide">
	<?dbhtml  dir="quickstart" filename="index.html" ?>
	<chapterinfo>
		<releaseinfo>$Id$</releaseinfo>
		<copyright>
			<year>2006</year>
			<holder>phpBB Group</holder>
		</copyright>
	</chapterinfo>
	<title>Quick Start Guide</title>
	<abstract>
		<para>A quick guide through the first steps of installing and configuring up your very own phpBB 3.0 forum.</para>
	</abstract>
	<section id="quick_requirements">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>Graham</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Requirements</title>
		<para>phpBB has a few requirements which must be met before you are able to install and use it. In this section, these requirements are explained.</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>A webserver or web hosting account running on any major Operating System with support for PHP</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>A SQL database system, one of:</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>FireBird 2.1 or above</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>MySQL 3.23 or above</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>MS SQL Server 2000 or above (directly or via ODBC)</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Oracle</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>PostgreSQL 7.x or above</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>SQLite 2</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>PHP 4.3.3+ (>=4.3.3, >4.4.x, >5.x.x, >6.0-dev (compatible)) with support for the database you intend to use.</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>getimagesize() function enabled</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>The following PHP modules are optional, but will provide access to additional features.</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>zlib Compression support</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Remote FTP support</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>XML support</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Imagemagick support</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>GD support</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para> The presence of each of these required features will be checked during the installation process, explained in <xref linkend="quick_installation" />. </para>
	</section>
	<section id="quick_installation">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Installation</title>
		<para>phpBB 3.0 Olympus has an easy to use installation system that will guide you through the installation process.</para>
		<para>After you have decompressed the phpBB3 archive and uploaded the files to the location where you want it to be installed, you need to enter the <acronym>URL</acronym> into your browser to open the installation screen. The first time you point your browser to the <acronym>URL</acronym> (<uri>http://www.example.com/phpBB3</uri> for instance), phpBB will detect that it is not yet installed and automatically redirect you to the installation screen.</para>
		<figure id="img_quick_installation_intro">
			<title>Introduction</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="../images/quick_start_guide/installation_intro.png" format="PNG" />
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>The introduction page of the installation system.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<section id="quick_installation_intro">
			<title>Introduction</title>
			<para>The installation screen gives you a short introduction into phpBB. It allows you to read the license phpBB 3.0 is released under (the <ulink url="http://opensource.org/licenses/gpl-license.php">General Public License</ulink>) and provides information about how you can receive support. To start the installation, click the <guilabel>Install</guilabel> tab (see <xref linkend="img_quick_installation_intro" />).</para>
		</section>
		<section id="quick_installation_requirements">
			<title>Requirements</title>
			<important>
				<para>Please read the <link linkend="quick_requirements">section on phpBB3's requirements</link> to find out more about the phpBB 3.0's minimum requirements.</para>
			</important>
			<para>The requirements list is the first page you will see after starting the installation. phpBB 3.0 automatically checks if everything that it needs to run properly is installed on your server. In order to continue the installation, you will need to have <acronym>PHP</acronym> installed (the minimum version number is shown on the requirements page), and at least one database available to continue the installation. It is also important that all shown folders are available and have the correct permissions set. Please see the description of each section to find out if they are optional or required for phpBB 3.0 to run. If everything is in order, you can continue the installation by clicking the <guilabel>Start Install</guilabel> button.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="quick_installation_database">
			<title>Database settings</title>
			<para>You now have to decide which database to use. See the <link linkend="quick_requirements">Requirements section</link> for information on which databases are supported. If you do not know your database settings, please contact your hosting company and ask for them. You will not be able to continue without them. You need:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>The <guilabel>Database Type</guilabel> - the database you will be using (e.g. mySQL, SQL server, Oracle)</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The <guilabel>Database server hostname or DSN</guilabel> - the address of the database server.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The <guilabel>Database server port</guilabel> - the port of the database server (most of the time this is not needed).</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The <guilabel>Database name</guilabel>- the name of the database on the server.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The <guilabel>Database username</guilabel> and <guilabel>Database password</guilabel> - the login data to access the database.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<tip>
				<para>If you are installing using SQLite, you should enter the full path to your database file in the DSN field and leave the username and password fields blank. For security reasons, you should make sure that the database file is not stored in a location accessible from the web.</para>
			</tip>
			<figure id="img_quick_installation_database">
				<title>Database settings</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="../images/quick_start_guide/installation_database.png" format="PNG" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>The database settings screen, please make sure to have all the required data available</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<para>You don't need to change the <guilabel>Prefix for tables in database</guilabel> setting, unless you plan on using multiple phpBB installations on one database. In this case you can use a different prefix for each installation to make it work.</para>
			<para>After you have entered your details, you can continue by clicking the <guilabel>Proceed to next step</guilabel> button. Now, phpBB 3.0 will test and verify the data you entered.</para>
			<para>If you see a "<guilabel>Could not connect to the database</guilabel>" error, this means that you didn't enter the database data correctly and it is not possible for phpBB to connect. Make sure that everything you entered is in order and try again. Again, if you are unsure about your database settings, please contact your host.</para>
			<tip>
				<para>Remember that your database username and password are case sensitive. You must use the exact one you have set up or been given by your host</para>
			</tip>
			<para>If you installed another version of phpBB before on the same database with the same prefix, phpBB will inform you and you just need to enter a different database prefix.</para>
			<para>If you see the <guilabel>Successful Connection</guilabel> message, you can continue to the next step.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="quick_installation_admin">
			<title>Administrator details</title>
			<para>Now you have to create your administration user. This user will have full administration access and he will be the first user on your forum. All fields on this page are required. You can also set the default language of your forum on this page. In a vanilla (basic) phpBB 3.0 installation we only include <guilabel>English [GB]</guilabel>. You can download further languages from <ulink url="http://www.phpbb.com/languages/">www.phpbb.com</ulink>, and add them later.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="quick_installation_config">
			<title>Configuration file</title>
			<para>In this step, phpBB will automatically try to write the configuration file. The forum needs the configuration to run properly. It contains all of the database settings, so without it, phpBB will not be able to access the database.</para>
			<para>Usually, automatically writing the configuration file works fine. But in some cases it can fail due to wrong file permissions, for instance. In this case, you need to upload the file manually. phpBB asks you to <guilabel>download</guilabel> the config.php file and tells you what to do with it. Please read the instructions carefully. After you have uploaded the file, click <guilabel>Done</guilabel> to get to the last step. If <guilabel>Done</guilabel> returns you to the same page as before, and does not return a success message, you did not upload the file correctly.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="quick_installation_advanced">
			<title>Advanced settings</title>
			<para>The <guilabel>Advanced settings</guilabel> allow you to set some parameters of the board configuration. They are optional, and you can always change them later if you wish. So if you are unsure of what these settings mean, ignore them and proceed to the final step to finish the installation.</para>
			<para>If the installation was successful, you can now use the <guilabel>Login</guilabel> button to visit the <guilabel>Administration Control Panel</guilabel>. Congratulations, you have installed phpBB 3.0 successfully. But there is still a lot of work ahead!</para>
			<para>If you are unable to get phpBB 3.0 installed even after reading this guide, please look at the <link linkend="quick_support">support section</link> to find out where you can ask for further assistance. </para>
			<para>At this point if you are upgrading from phpBB 2.0, you should refer to the <link linkend="upgrade_guide">upgrade guide</link> for further information. If not, you should remove the install directory from your server as you will only be able to access the Administration Control Panel whilst it is present.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="quick_settings">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>zeroK</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>General settings</title>
		<para>In this section you will learn how to change some of the basic settings of your new board.</para>
		<para>Right after the installation you will be redirected to the so called "Administration Control Panel" (<acronym>ACP</acronym>). You can also access this panel by clicking the <guilabel>[Administration Control Panel]</guilabel> link at the bottom of your forum. In this interface you can change everything about your board.</para>
		<section id="quick_settings_boardsettings">
			<title>Board Settings</title>
			<para>The first section of the <acronym>ACP</acronym> you will probably want to visit right after the installation is "Board Settings". Here you can first of all change the name (<guilabel>Site name</guilabel>) and description (<guilabel>Site description</guilabel>) of your board.</para>
			<figure id="img_quick_settings_sitename">
				<title>Board Settings</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="../images/quick_start_guide/settings_sitename.png" format="PNG" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Here you can edit the Site name and Site description of your board.</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<para>This form also holds the options for changing things like the timezone (<guilabel>System timezone</guilabel>) as well as the date format used to render dates/times (<guilabel>Date format</guilabel>).</para>
			<para>There you can also select a new style (after having installed it) for your board and enforce it on all members ignoring whatever style they've selected in their "User Control Panel". The style will also be used for all forums where you haven't specified a different one. For details on where to get new styles and how to install them, please visit the <ulink url="http://www.phpbb.com/styles/">styles home page</ulink> at <ulink url="http://www.phpbb.com/">phpbb.com</ulink>.</para>
			<para>If you want to use your board for a non-English community, this form also lets you change the default language (<guilabel>Default Language</guilabel>) (which can be overridden by each user in their UCPs). By default, phpBB3 only ships with the English language pack. So, before using this field, you will have to download the language pack for the language you want to use and install it. For details, please read <link linkend="acp_system_language">Language packs</link> .</para>
		</section>
		<!--/board_settings-->
		<section id="quick_settings_boardfeatures">
			<title>Board Features</title>
			<para>If you want to enable or disable some of the basic features of your board, this is the place to go. Here you can allow and disallow for example username changes (<guilabel>Allow Username changes</guilabel>) or the creation of attachments (<guilabel>Allow Attachments</guilabel>). You can even disable <acronym>BBCode</acronym> altogether (<guilabel>Allow BBCode</guilabel>).</para>
			<figure id="img_quick_settings_features">
				<title>Board Features</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="../images/quick_start_guide/settings_features.png" format="PNG" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Enabling and disabling basic features with just 2 clicks</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<para>Disabling BBCode completely is a little bit to harsh for your taste but you don't want your users to abuse the signature field for tons of images? Simply set <guilabel>Allow use of IMG BBCode Tag in user signatures</guilabel> to "No". If you want to be a little bit more specific on what you want to allow and disallow in users' signatures, have a look at the "Signature Settings" form.</para>
			<para>The "Board Features" form offers you a great way to control the features in an all-or-nothing way. If you want to get into the details on each feature, there is for everything also a separated form which let's you specify everything from the maximum number of characters allowed in a post (<guilabel>Max characters per post</guilabel> in "Post Settings") to how large a user's avatar can be (<guilabel>Maximum Avatar Dimensions</guilabel> in "Avatar Settings").</para>
			<important>
				<para>If you disable features, these will also be unavailable to users who would normally have them according to their respective permissions. For details on the permissions system, please read <xref linkend="quick_permissions" /> or the <link linkend="acp_permissions">in-depth guide in the Administrator Guide.</link></para>
			</important>
		</section>
		<!--<para>TODO: Probably needs a better title. How to change the default forum settings, forum name or description, for instance. Does not need to have all settings explained in detail. We have the Admin Guide for that. It would be good to provide a link if there is anything that is discussed more detailed in the Admin Guide. </para>-->
	</section>
	<section id="quick_forums">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>Anon</othername>
				</author>
				<author>
					<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Creating and setting up forums</title>
		<para>Forums are the sections where topics are stored. Without forums, your users would have nowhere to post! Creating forums is very easy.</para>
		<para>Firstly, make sure you are logged in. Find the <guilabel>[ Administration Control Panel ]</guilabel> link at the bottom of the page, and click it. You should be in the Administration Index. You can administer your board here.</para>
		<para>There are tabs at the top for the Administration Control Panel that will guide you to each category. You must get to the Forum Administration section to create a forum, so click the <guilabel>Forums</guilabel> tab.</para>
		<para>The Forum Administration Index is where you can manage forums on your site. Along with being able to create forums, you are also able to create subforums. Subforums are forums that are located in a parent forum in a hierachy. For more information about subforums, see the <link linkend="acp_forums_subforums">administration guide on subforums</link>.</para>
		<para>Find the <guilabel>Create new forum</guilabel> button on the right side of the page. Type in the name of the forum you wish in the textbox located directly to the left of this button. For example, if the forum name was to be Test, in the text box put Test. Once you are done, click the <guilabel>Create new forum</guilabel> button create the forum.</para>
		<para>You should see a page headed with the text &quot;Create new forum :: Test&quot;. You can change options for your forum; for example you can set what forum image the forum can use, if it's a category, or what forum rules text will belong to the forum. You should type up a brief description for the forum as users will be able to figure out what the forum is for.</para>
		<figure id="img_quick_create_forum">
			<title>Creating a new forum</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata format="PNG" fileref="../images/quick_start_guide/creating_forums.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Here you can choose the name and the description of your a new forum.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<para>The default settings are usually good enough to get your new forum up and running; however, you may change them to suit your needs. But there are three key forum settings that you should pay attention to. The Parent Forum setting allows you to choose which forum your new forum will belong to. Be careful to what level you want your forum to be in. (The Parent Forum setting is important when creating subforums. For more information on subforums, continue reading to the section on creating subforums) The &quot;Copy Permissions&quot; setting allows you to copy the permissions from an existing forum to your new forum. Use this if you want to keep permissions constant. The forum style setting allows you to set which style your new forum will display. Your new forum can show a different style to another. For more information on each forum setting, see the <xref linkend="acp_forums">in-depth section on forum creation</xref></para>
		<para>Once you're done configuring the settings of your new forum, scroll to the bottom of the page and click the <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> button to create your forum and it's settings. If your new forum was created successfully, the screen will show you a success message.</para>
		<para>If you wish to set permissions for the forum (or if you do not click on anything), you will see the forum permissions screen. If you do not want to (and want to use the default permissions for your new forum), click on the <guilabel>Back to previous page</guilabel> link. Otherwise, continue and set each setting to what you wish. Once you are done, click the <guilabel>Apply all Permissions</guilabel> button at the bottom of the page. You will see the successful forum permissions updated screen if it worked.</para>
		<important>
			<para>If you do not set any permissions on this forum it will not be accessible to anyone (including yourself).</para>
		</important>
		<para>You have successfully updated your forum permissions and set up your new forum. To create more forums, follow this general procedure again.</para>
		<para>For more information on setting permissions, see <xref linkend="quick_permissions" /></para>
	</section>
	<section id="quick_permissions">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>dhn</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Setting permissions</title>
		<para>After you created your first forum, you have to decide who has access to it and what your users are allowed to do and what not. This is what Permissions are for. You can disallow guests to post or hand out moderating powers, for instance. Almost every aspect of user interaction with phpBB3 Olympus can be adjusted with permissions.</para>

		<section id="quick_permissions_types">
			<title>Permission types</title>
			<para>There are four different types of permissions:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem id="quick_permission_types_user">
					<para>User/Group permissions (global) - e.g. disallow changing avatar</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem id="quick_permission_types_admin">
					<para>Administrator permissions (global) - e.g. allow to manage forums</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem id="quick_permission_types_moderator">
					<para>Moderator permissions (global or local) - e.g. allow to lock topics or ban users (only global)</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem id="quick_permission_types_forum">
					<para>Forum permissions (local) - e.g. allow to see a forum or post topics</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<para>Each permission type consists of a different set of permissions and can apply either locally or globally. A global permission type is set for your whole bulletin board. If you disallow one of your users to send Private Messages, for instance, you have to do this with the global user permission. Administrator permission are also global.</para>
			<figure id="img_quick_permissions_types">
				<title>Global and local permissions</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata format="PNG" fileref="../images/quick_start_guide/permissions_types.png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Global and local permissions</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<para>On the other hand local permissions do only apply to specific forums. So if you disallow someone to post in one forum, for instance, it will not impact the rest of the board. The user will still be able to post in any other forum he has the local permission to post.</para>
			<para>You can appoint moderators either globally or locally. If you trust some of your users enough, you can make them Global Moderators. They can moderate all forums they have access to with the permissions you assign to them. Compared to that, local moderators will only be able to moderate the number of forums you select for them. They can also have different moderator permissions for different forums. While they are able to delete topics in one forum, they may not be allowed to do it in another. Global moderators will have the same permissions for all forums.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="quick_permissions_forum">
			<title>Setting forum permissions</title>
			<para>To set the permissions for your new forum we need the local <guilabel>Forum Based Permissions</guilabel>. First you have to decide how you want to set the permissions. If you want to set them for a single group or user, you should use the <guilabel>Group</guilabel> or <guilabel>User Forum Permissions</guilabel>. They will allow you to select one group or user, and then select the forums you want to set the permissions for. </para>
			<para>But for this Quick Start Guide we will concentrate on the <guilabel>Forum Permissions</guilabel>. Instead of selecting a user or group, you select the forums you want to change first. You can select them either by selecting the forums manually in the top list, or by single forum and single forum plus subforums respectively in the lower pull down menus. <guilabel>Submit</guilabel> will bring you to the next page.</para>
			<figure id="img_quick_permissions_select">
				<title>Select Groups</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata format="PNG" fileref="../images/quick_start_guide/permissions_select.png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Select Groups or Users to set Forum Permissions</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<para>The <guilabel>Forum Permissions</guilabel> page shows you two columns, one for users and one for groups to select (see <xref linkend="img_quick_permissions_select" />). The top lists on both columns labelled as <guilabel>Manage Users</guilabel> and <guilabel> Manage Groups</guilabel> show users and groups that already have permissions on at least one of your selected forums set. You can select them and change their permissions with the <guilabel>Edit Permissions</guilabel> button, or use <guilabel>Remove Permissions</guilabel> to remove them which leads to them not having permissions set, and therefore not being able to see the forum or have any access to it (unless they have access to it through another group). The bottom boxes allow you to add new users or groups, that do not currently have permissions set on at least one of your selected forums.</para>
			<para>To add permissions for groups, select one or more groups either in the <guilabel>Add Groups</guilabel> list (this works similar with users, but if you want to add new users, you have to type them in manually in the <guilabel>Add Users</guilabel> text box or use the <guilabel>Find a member</guilabel> function). <guilabel>Add Permissions</guilabel> will take you to the permission interface. Each forum you selected is listed, with the groups or users to change the permissions for below them. </para>
			<para>There are two ways to assign permissions: You can set them manually or use predefined <guilabel>Permission Roles</guilabel> for a simpler but less powerful way. You can switch between both approaches any time you want. You can skip the manual permission introduction and <link linkend="quick_permissions_roles">jump directly into the section on "Permissions Roles"</link>, if you are eager to get everything running as quickly as possible. But remember that permission roles do only offer a small bit of what the permission system has to offer and we believe that to be a good Olympus administrator, you have to fully grasp permissions. </para>
			<para>Both ways only differ in the way you set them. They both share the same interface.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="quick_permissions_manual">
			<title>Manual permissions</title>
			<para>This is the most important aspect of permissions. You need to understand this to properly work with them. There are three different values that a permission can take:</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para><guilabel>YES</guilabel> will allow a permission setting <emphasis>unless</emphasis> it is overwritten by a <guilabel>NEVER</guilabel>.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><guilabel>NO</guilabel> will be disallow a permission setting <emphasis>unless</emphasis> it is overwritten by a <guilabel>YES</guilabel>.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para><guilabel>NEVER</guilabel> will completely disallow a permission setting for a user. It <emphasis>cannot</emphasis> be overwritten by a <guilabel>YES</guilabel>.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>The three values are important as it is possible for a user to have more than one permissions for the same setting through multiple groups. If the user is a member of the default "Registered Users" group and a custom group called "Senior Users" you created for your most dedicated members, both could have different permissions for seeing a forum. In this example you want to make a forum called "Good old times" only available to the "Senior Users" group, but don't want all "Registered Users" to see it. You will of course set the <guilabel>Can see forum</guilabel> permission to <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> for "Senior Users". But <emphasis>do not</emphasis> set the permission to <guilabel>Never</guilabel> for "Registered Users". If you do this, "Senior Members" will not see the forum as the <guilabel>Never</guilabel> overrides any <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> they have. Leave the setting at <guilabel>No</guilabel> instead. <guilabel>No</guilabel> is a weak <guilabel>Never</guilabel> that a <guilabel>Yes</guilabel> can override.</para>
			<figure id="img_quick_permissions_manual">
				<title>Manual permissions</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata format="PNG" fileref="../images/quick_start_guide/permissions_manual.png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Setting permissions manually</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
		</section>
		<section id="quick_permissions_roles">
			<title>Permissions roles</title>
			<para>phpBB3 Olympus ships with a number of default permission roles, that offer you a wide variety of options for setting permissions. Instead of having to check each radio button manually, you can select a predefined role in the <guilabel>Role</guilabel>pull down list. Each role has a detailed description, that will pop up when you hover your mouse over it. Submit your changes with <guilabel>Apply Permissions</guilabel> or <guilabel>Apply All Permissions</guilabel> when you are satisfied with them. That will set the permissions and you are done.</para>
			<figure id="img_quick_permissions_roles">
				<title>Permission roles</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata format="PNG" fileref="../images/quick_start_guide/permissions_roles.png" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Setting permissions with roles</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<para>But permission roles are not only a quick and easy way to set permissions, they are also a powerful tool for experienced board administrators to manage permissions on bigger boards. You can create your own roles and edit existing ones. Roles are dynamic, so when you edit a role, all groups and users that have the role assigned will automatically be updated.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="quick_permissions_moderators">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>zeroK</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Assign moderators to forums</title>
			<para>A quite common use case for permissions and roles are forum moderation. phpBB3 makes assigning users as moderators of forums really simple.</para>
			<para>As you might have already guessed, moderation of specific forums is a local setting, so you can find <guilabel>Forum Moderators</guilabel> in the section for <guilabel>Forum Based Permissions</guilabel>. First of all, you will have to select for forum (or forums) you want to assign new moderators to. This form is divided into three areas. In the first one, you can select multiple forums (select multiple by holding down the CTRL button on your keyboard, or cmd (under MacOS X)), where the moderator settings you will set in the following form will only apply to these exact forums. The second area allows you to select only one forum but all the following settings will apply not only to this forum but also all its subforums. Finally, the third area's selection will only affect exactly this forum.</para>
			<para>After selecting the forums and hitting <guilabel>Submit</guilabel>, you will be greeted by a form you should already be familiar with from one of the previous sections in this guide: <xref linkend="img_quick_permissions_select"/>. Here you can select the users or groups that should get some kind of moderation power over the selected forums. So go ahead: Select some users and/or groups and hit the <guilabel>Set Permissions</guilabel> button.</para>
			<para>In the next form you can choose, what moderator permissions the selected users/groups should receive. First of all, there are some predefined roles from which you can select:</para>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Standard Moderator</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>A Standard Moderator can approve or disapprove, edit and delete posts, delete or close reports, but not necessarily change the owner of a post. This kind of moderator can also issue warnings and view details of a post.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Simple Moderator</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>A Simple Moderator can edit posts and close and delete reports and can also view post details.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Queue Moderator</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>As a Queue Moderator, you can only approve or disapprove posts that landed in the moderator queue and edit posts.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Full Moderator</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>Full Moderators can do everything moderation-related; they can even ban users.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
			<figure id="img_quick_permissions_moderator">
				<title>The Forum Moderator's Permissions</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
			        	<imagedata format="PNG" fileref="../images/quick_start_guide/permissions_moderator.png"/>
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>Set the moderator's permissions</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<para>When you're done simply hit <guilabel>Apply all Permissions</guilabel>. All the permissions mentioned here can also be selected from the right side of the form to give you more granular options.</para>
		</section>

		<section id="quick_permissions_global">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>zeroK</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Setting global permissions</title>
			<para>Local Permissions are too local for you? Well, then phpBB3 has something to offer for you, too: Global Permissions:</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem><para>Users Permissions</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>Groups Permissions</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>Administrators</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>Global Moderators</para></listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<para>In "User Permissions" and "Group Permissions" you can allow and disallow features like attachments, signatures and avatars for specific users and user groups. Note that some of these settings only matter, if the respective feature is enabled in the "Board Features" (see <xref linkend="quick_settings_boardfeatures"/> for details).</para>
			<para>Under "Administrators" you can give users or groups administrator privileges like the ability to manage forums or change user permissions. For details on these settings please read the <xref linkend="acp_permissions"/>.</para>
			<para>The "Global Moderators" form offers you the same settings as the forum specific form (described in <xref linkend="quick_permissions_moderators"/>) but applies to all forums on your board.</para>
		</section>

	</section>
	<section id="quick_support">
		<title>Obtaining support</title>
		<para>The <ulink url="http://www.phpbb.com/about/">phpBB Team</ulink> provides many options for users to find support for their phpBB install. In addition to this very documentation, the <ulink url="http://www.phpbb.com/community/viewforum.php?f=46">support forum on www.phpbb.com</ulink> has many answers that users like you are searching for. Therefore, we highly recommend the use of the search feature before asking a new question. If you are unable to find an answer, feel free to post a new topic asking for help. Be sure to be descriptive when explaining your problem! The more we know about what is happening, the faster we can provide you with the answer you are looking for. Be sure to fill out the <ulink url="http://www.phpbb.com/community/viewtopic.php?f=46&amp;t=543515">Support Request Template</ulink> with the information it asks for.</para>

		<para>In addition to the support forum on www.phpbb.com, we provide a <ulink url="http://www.phpbb.com/kb/">Knowledge Base</ulink> for users to read and submit articles on common answers to questions. Our community has taken a lot of time in writing these articles, so be sure to check them out.</para>

		<para>We provide realtime support in <ulink url="irc://irc.phpbb.com/phpbb">#phpBB</ulink> on the popular Open Source IRC network, <ulink url="http://www.freenode.net/">Freenode</ulink>. You can typically find someone from each of the teams in here, as well as fellow users who are more than happy to help you out. Be sure to read the <ulink url="http://www.phpbb.com/support/irc/">IRC rules</ulink> before joining the channel, as we have a few basic netiquette rules that we ask users to follow. At any given time, there can be as many as 60 users, if not more in the channel, so you are almost certain to find someone there to help you. However, it is important that you read and follow the IRC rules as people may not answer you. An example of this is that oftentimes users come in to the channel and ask if anybody is around and then end up leaving 30 seconds later before someone has the chance to answer. Instead, be sure to ask your question and wait. As the saying goes, "don't ask to ask, just ask!"</para>

		<para>English is not your native language? Not a problem! We also provide an <ulink url="http://www.phpbb.com/support/intl/">International Support page</ulink> with links to various websites that provide support in Espanol, Deutsch, Francais, and more.</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
