<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
                         "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="glossary">
	<?dbhtml dir="glossary" filename="index.html" ?>
	<chapterinfo>
		<releaseinfo>$Id: glossary.xml 140 2007-07-16 16:41:42Z mhobbit $</releaseinfo>
		<copyright>
			<year>2006</year>
			<holder>phpBB Group</holder>
		</copyright>
	</chapterinfo>
	<title>Ordliste</title>
	<abstract>
		<para>Termer og begreber anvendt i dokumentationen til phpBB og i supportfora.</para>
	</abstract>
	
	<section id="terms">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
				</author>
				
				<author>
					<othername>pentapenguin</othername>
				</author>
				
				<author>
					<othername>Techie-Micheal</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		
		<title>Termer</title>
		<para>I phpBB og på phpBB's supportboards anvendes en række termer og forkortelser. Nedenfor gennemgås på de mest almendt anvendte.</para>
		
		<!-- TODO: Add links to sections on the respective item for whichever terms need it. For example, the ACP bit needs to link to the section of the Admin Guide. -->
		<!-- TODO: Jan: Når oversættelse er færdiggjort sorteres termforklaringerne alfabetisk. Den er i øjeblikket sorteret alfabetisk efter de engelse benævnelser. Den holder ikke i flere tilfælde efter oversættelse til dansk. -->
		
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>ACP</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><link linkend="admin_control_panel"><acronym>ACP</acronym></link> er en forkortelse af &quot;Administratorkontrolpanel&quot;.  Her kan du, som administrator, kontrollere og indstille alle funtioner på dit board.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>ASCII</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><acronym>ASCII</acronym>, eller &quot;American Standard Code for Information Interchange&quot;, er en almindelig anvendt indkoding af data som skal flyttes til en anden computer. <acronym>FTP</acronym>-klienter bruger ASCII-mode når filer flyttes. Alle phpBB-filer (filtyperne .php, .inc, .sql, .cfg, .htm, and .tpl) skal uploades i ASCII-mode. Eneste undtagelse er grafikfiler, som skal uploades i BINARY-mode.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Vedhæftede filer</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Der kan <link linkend="acp_board_attachments">vedhæftes filer</link> til indlæg, på tilsvarende måde som når man skriver en email. Boardadministratoren kan have valgt visse restriktioner og bestemt at kun nogle filtyper kan vedhæftes og også begrænset størrelsen på den enkelte vedhæftede fil.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Avatar</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><link linkend="ucp_avatar">Avatars</link> er små billeder som vises sammen med brugernavnene. En avatar kan ændres under dine profilindstillinger. I <acronym>ACP</acronym> kan den overordnede brug af avatars tillades eller forbydes.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>BBkode</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><link linkend="posting_bbcodes">BBkode</link> er en måde at formatere indlæg på som giver fin kontrol over hvordan indlægget vises. Syntaksen i BBkoder er meget lig HTML.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Binær (Binary)</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>I phpBB-sammenhæng refererer &quot;binær&quot; eller på engelsk &quot;binary&quot; normalt til en måde at indkode filer der skal flyttes (den anden metode er <acronym>ASCII</acronym>). Den anvendes ofte af <acronym>FTP</acronym>-klienter ved upload af filer. Alle phpBB's grafikfiler (i mapperne images/ ,  styles/prosilver/imageset og styles/subsilver2/imageset/ ) skal uploades i BINARY-mode. </para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Mellemlager (Cache)</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Mellemlagring er en metode til at gemme data der ofte hentes. Ved benyttelse af denne metode aflastes din server. Som standard er phpBB3 indstillet til at mellemlagre skabelonfilerne.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Kategori</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>En kategori er en gruppe af alle slags identiske enheder, for eksempel fora.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>chmod</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><abbrev>chmod</abbrev> is a way of changing the permissions of a file on a *nix (UNIX, Linux, etc.) server. Files in phpBB should be chmodded 644. Directories should be chmodded to 755. Avatar upload directories and templates cache directories should be chmodded to 777. For more information regarding chmod, please consult your <acronym>FTP</acronym> client's documentation.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Klient</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>En klient er betegnelsen for en computer som tilgår og benytter sig af en anden computers service via et netværk.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Cookie</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>En cookie er a small piece of data put onto the user's computer. Cookies are used with phpBB to store login information (used for automatic logins).</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Database</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A database is a collection stored in a structured, organized manner (with different tables, rows, and columns, etc.). Databases provide a fast and flexible way of storing data, instead of the other commonly used data storage system of flat files where data is stored in a file. phpBB 3.0 supports a number of different <acronym>DBMSs</acronym>  and uses the database to store information such as user details, posts, and categories. Data stored in a database can usually be backed up and restored easily.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>DBAL</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><acronym>DBAL</acronym>, or &quot;Database Abstraction Layer&quot;, is a system that allows phpBB 3.0 to access many different <acronym>DBMSs</acronym> with little overhead. All code made for phpBB (including MODs) need to use the phpBB <acronym>DBAL</acronym> for compatibility and performance purposes.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>DBMS</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A <acronym>DBMS</acronym>, or &quot;Database Management System&quot;, is a system or software designed to manage a database. phpBB 3.0 supports the following DBMSs: Firebird, MS SQL Server, mySQL, Oracle, postgreSQL, and SQLite.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>FTP</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><acronym>FTP</acronym> stands for &quot;File Transfer Protocol&quot;. It is a protocol which allows files to be transferred between computers. <acronym>FTP</acronym> clients are programs that are used to transfer files via <acronym>FTP</acronym>.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Founder</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A founder is a special board administrator that cannot be edited or deleted. This is a new user level introduced in phpBB 3.0.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>GZip</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>GZip is a compression method often used in web applications and software such as phpBB to improve speed. Most modern browsers support this on-the-fly algorithm. Gzip is also used to compress an archive of files. Higher compression levels, however, will increase server load.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>IP address</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>An IP address, or Internet Protocol address, is a unique address that identifies a specific computer or user.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Jabber</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Jabber is an open-source protocol that can be used for instant messenging. For more information on Jabber's role in phpBB, see <xref linkend="acp_client_jabber" />.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>MCP</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>The <acronym>MCP</acronym>, or Moderation Control Panel, is the central point from which all moderators can moderate their forums. All moderation-related features are contained in this control panel.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>MD5</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><acronym>MD5</acronym> (Message Digest algorithm 5) is a commonly-used hash function used by phpBB. MD5 is an algorithm which takes an input of any length and outputs a message digest of a fixed length (128-bit, 32 characters). MD5 is used in phpBB to turn the users' passwords into a one-way hash, meaning that you cannot &quot;decrypt&quot; (reverse) an MD5 hash and get users' passwords. User passwords are stored as MD5 hashes in the database.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>MOD</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A <abbrev>MOD</abbrev> is a code modification for phpBB that either adds, changes, or in some other way enhances, phpBB. <abbrev>MODs</abbrev> are written by third-party authors; as such, the phpBB Group does not assume any responsibility for MODs.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>PHP</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><acronym>PHP</acronym>, or &quot;PHP: Hypertext Preprocessor&quot;, is a commonly-used open-source scripting language. phpBB is written in <acronym>PHP</acronym> and requires the <acronym>PHP</acronym> runtime engine to be installed and properly configured on the server phpBB is run on. For more information about <acronym>PHP</acronym>, please see the <ulink url="http://www.php.net">PHP</ulink> home page.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>phpMyAdmin</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>phpMyAdmin is a popular open-source program that is used to manage MySQL databases. When <abbrev>MODding</abbrev> phpBB or otherwise changing it, you may have to edit your database. phpMyAdmin is one such tool that will allow you to do so. For more information regarding phpMyAdmin, please see the <ulink url="http://www.phpmyadmin.net">phpMyAdmin project home page</ulink>.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Private beskeder</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Private beskeder are a way for registered members to communicate privately through your board without the need to fall back to e-mail or instant messaging. They can be sent between users (they can also be forwarded and have copies sent, in phpBB 3.0) that cannot be viewed by anyone other than the intended recipient. The user guide contains more information on <link linkend="user_pm">using phpBB3's private messaging system</link>.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Rang</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>En rang er en slags titel som kan tildeles en bruger. Rankgordner kan oprettes, ændres og slettes af administratorerne.</para>
					
					<note>
						<para>When assigning a special rank name to a user, remember that no permissions are associated. For example, if you create a &quot;Support Moderator&quot; rank and assign it to a user, that user will not automatically get moderator permissions. You must assign the user the special permissions separately.</para>
					</note>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Server-writable</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Anything on your server that is server-writable means that the file(s) or folder(s) in question have their permissions properly set so that the server can write to them. Some phpBB3 functions that may require some files and/or folders to be writable by the server include caching and the actual installation of phpBB3 (the config.php file needs to be written during the installation process). Making files or folders server-writable, however, depends on the operating system that the server is running under. On *nix-based servers, users can configure file and folder permissions via the <glossterm>CHMOD</glossterm> utility, while Windows-based servers offer their own permissions scheme. It is possible with some <glossterm>FTP</glossterm> clients to change file and folder permissions as well.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Session</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A session is a visit to your phpBB forums. For phpBB, a session is how long you spend on the forums. It is created when you login deleted when you log off. Session <acronym>IDs</acronym> are usually stored in a cookie, but if phpBB is unable to get cookie information from your computer, then a session <acronym>ID</acronym> is appended to the URL (e.g. index.php?sid=999). This session <acronym>ID</acronym> preserves the user's session without use of a cookie. If sessions were not preserved, then you would find yourself being logged out every time you clicked on a link in the forum.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Signature</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A signature is a message displayed at the end of a user's post. Signatures are set by the user. Whether or not a signature is displayed after a post is set by the user's profile settings.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>SMTP</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><acronym>SMTP</acronym> stands for &quot;Simple Mail Transfer Protocol&quot;. It is a protocol for sending email. By default, phpBB uses <acronym>PHP</acronym>'s built-in <ulink url="http://www.php.net/manual/en/function.mail.php">mail()</ulink> function to send email. However, phpBB will use <acronym>SMTP</acronym> to send emails if the required <acronym>SMTP</acronym> data is correctly set up.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Style</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A style is made up of a template set, image set, and stylesheet. A style controls the overall look of your forum.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Sub-forum</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Sub-forums are a new feature introduced in phpBB 3.0. Sub-forums are forums that are nested in, or located in, other forums.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Template</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>A template is what controls the layout of a style. phpBB 3.0 template files have the .html file extension. These template files contain mostly <acronym>HTML</acronym> (no <acronym>PHP</acronym>, however), with some variables that phpBB uses (contained in braces: { and }).</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>UCP</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>The <acronym>UCP</acronym>, or User Control Panel, is the central point from which users can manage all of the settings and features that pertain to their accounts.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>UNIX tidstempel</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>phpBB gemmer alle tider i formatet <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unix_time">UNIX tidstempel</ulink> for at lette omsætning til andre tidzoner og tidformater.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Brugergruppe</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Brugergrupper er en måde at gruppere brugere på. Det gør det meget nemt at indstille og ændre tilladelser for mange brugere samtidig (e.g. create a moderator group and give it moderating permissions to a certain forum instead of giving lots of individual people moderating permissions separately). A usergroup has a usergroup moderator (a leader, essentially), who has the ability to add or delete users from the group. Usergroups can be set to hidden, closed or open. If a usergroup is open, users can try requesting membership via the proper page i <link linkend="user_control_panel">brugerkontrolpanelet</link>. phpBB 3.0 er født med seks forudefinerede brugergrupper.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</section>
</chapter>
