<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
                         "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="moderator_guide">
	<?dbhtml dir="moderatorguide" filename="index.html" ?>
	<chapterinfo>
		<releaseinfo>$Id: moderator_guide.xml 140 2007-07-16 16:41:42Z mhobbit $</releaseinfo>
		<copyright>
			<year>2006</year>
			<holder>phpBB Group</holder>
		</copyright>
	</chapterinfo>
	<title>Redaktørguide</title>
	<abstract>
		<para>This chapter describes the phpBB 3.0 forum moderation controls.</para>
	</abstract>
	<section id="moderator_edit">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>camm15h</othername>
				</author>
				<author>
					<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Redigere indlæg</title>
		<para>Redaktører med tilladelser i relevante fora kan redigere i emner og indlæg. Normalt kan man se redaktører i forumbeskrivelserne på boardindekset. En bruger med redaktørstatus har adgang til knappen <guilabel>Redigér</guilabel> i alle indlæg. Herudover kan redaktørerne:</para>
	
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Slette indlæg</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Slette indlæg i emnet. Husk at slettede indlæg ikke kan gendannes.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Ændre eller fjerne emne- og indlægikoner</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Bestemme om et valgt ikon er i overenstemmelse med indlægget.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Ændre emnetitel og indlægstekst</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>En redaktør har mulighed for at ændre indholdet af et indlæg.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Ændre indlægsmuligheder - deaktivere BBkode/Smilies og behandling af URL'er osv.</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Bestemme hvilke muligheder der skal være aktiveret i indlægget.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Låse emnet eller indlægget</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>En redaktør kan låse indlægget eller hele emnet.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Tilføje, ændre og fjerne vedhæftede filer</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Hvis muligheden for at vedhæfte filer er aktiveret kan redaktøren vælge at fjerne eller ændre disse.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Ændre afstemningsindstillinger</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Er muligheden for at oprette afstemninger tilstede på boardet kan redaktøren ændre indstillinger i en oprettet afstemning.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
		
		<para>Er der grund til at et indlæg ikke skal kunne redigeres, kan et indlæg låses for at forhindre indlægsforfatteren i dette. Ved fremtidige forsøg på at redigere indlægget adviseres brugeren. Ønsker redaktøren at begrunde årsagen til den foretagede ændring, er der mulighed for at tilføje en bemærkning til det redigerede indlæg.</para>
		
		<!--TODO: screenshot of post and edit reason?-->
	</section>
	<section id="moderator_modtools">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>camm15h</othername>
				</author>
				<author>
					<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>Redaktørværktøjer</title>
		<para>For redaktøren er der, i hvert emne, en række værktøjer til rådighed. Det ønskede vælges fra dropdownmenuen. De tilgængelige værktøjer herfra er: låse, låse op, slette, flytte, dele, sammenlæg og kopiér emne. Desuden kan emnetype ændres herfra (opslag, bekendtgørelse og global) og emnets log hentes. Herunder beskrives redaktørmulighederne mere detaljeret.</para>
		
		<figure id="quick_mod_tools">
			<title>Redigeringsværktøjer</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata format="PNG" fileref="../images/moderator_guide/quick_mod_tools.png"/>
				</imageobject>
				<caption>
					<para>Redigeringsværktøjerne er tilgængelige via dropdownmenuen placeret under det sidste indlæg på hver side i emnet. Fold valgmulighederne ud ved at klikke på pilen til højre i feltet.</para>
				</caption>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		
		<section id="modtools_lock">
			<title>Lås et emne eller indlæg</title>
			<para>Der er flere måder at udføre denne handling på. Fra forumoversigten kan man vælge at bruge <link linkend="moderator_mcp">Redaktørkontrolpanel</link> øverst, herefter markere det emne der skal låses og vælge denne handling nederst. Når man som redaktør læser i selve emnet, er der desuden mulighed for at låse emnet fra redigeringsværktøjerne nederst på hver side, uden at skulle i redaktørkontrolpanelet. Et enkelt indlæg kan låses ved at redigere indlægget og vælge låse det nederst under indstillinger.</para>
			<para>Låses et emne kan ingen skrive indlæg i det. Låsning af inviduelle indlæg forhindrer at disse kan redigeres af forfatteren.</para>
		</section>
		
		<section id="modtools_delete">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>camm15h</othername>
					</author>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Slet et emne eller indlæg</title>
			<para>Hvis det er tilladt i <link linkend="admin_control_panel">administratorkontrolpanelets</link> tilladelsesystem kan brugerne slette egne indlæg, enten når et emne læses eller når indlægget redigeres. Emner og indlæg kan kun slettes af brugerne hvis der endnu ikke er svaret på disse.</para>
			<para>Administratorer og redaktører har samme muligheder, men kun administratorer kan fjerne et indlæg hvis der er efterfølgende indlæg i emnet. Ved at bruge redaktørværktøjerne nederst i emnet kan et indlæg hurtigt fjernes. I <link linkend="moderator_mcp">redaktørkontrolpanelet</link> kan flere indlæg udvælges og slettes.</para>
			<tip>
				<para>Bemærk venligst at slettede emner og indlæg ikke kan gendannes. Overvej eventuelt at oprette et skjult forum og i stedet flytte emner og indlæg hertil til brug for fremtidig reference.</para>
			</tip>
		</section>
		
		<section id="modtools_move">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>camm15h</othername>
					</author>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Flyt et emne til andet forum</title>
			<para>For at flytte et emne til et andet forum, benyttes <guilabel>Redaktørværktøjer</guilabel> underst i emnet og vælg værktøjet <guilabel>Flyt emne</guilabel> i dropdownmenuen. Ønsker du at efterlade et <link linkend="modtools_move_shadow">Skyggeemne</link> i det oprindelige forum, skal boksen herfor være afmærket. Herefter vælger du det forum emnet skal flyttes til, og klik på <guilabel>Ja</guilabel>.</para>
		
			<section id="modtools_move_shadow">
				<sectioninfo>
					<authorgroup>
						<author>
							<othername>camm15h</othername>
						</author>
						<author>
							<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
						</author>
					</authorgroup>
				</sectioninfo>
				<title>Skyggeemner</title>
				<para>Når et emne flyttes til et andet forum er det muligt at efterlade et skyggeemne i det oprindelige forum. Et skyggeemne er blot et link til emnets nye placering. Du kan selv vælge om der skal efterlades et skyggeemne i checkboksen som første valg når du har valgt <guilabel>Flyt emne</guilabel> i redaktørværktøjerne.</para>
				<para>For at slette et skyggeemne manøvres til det forum det er placeret i, og herefter vælges <link linkend="moderator_mcp">Redaktørkontrolpanel</link> næsten øverst. I kontrolpanelet finder du et linket &quot;Slet skyggeemne&quot; lige over emnet.</para>
				<note>
					<para>Når skyggeemnet slettes bliver det originale emne <emphasis>ikke</emphasis> slettet.</para>
				</note>
			</section>
		</section>
		
		<section id="modtools_copy">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>camm15h</othername>
					</author>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Kopiering af et emne</title>
			<para>Redaktører kan kopiere emner og hermed oprette en kopi af et emne i et andet forum. I det emne der skal kopieres, vælges nederst i <guilabel>Kopiér emne</guilabel> i redaktørværktøjerne. Fra forumindekset kan vælges <link linkend="moderator_mcp">Redaktørkontrolpanel</link>, her markeres det emne der skal kopieres og herefter destinationsforummet kopien skal placeres i. Klik på  <guilabel>Ja</guilabel> for at oprette kopien.</para>
		</section>
		
		<section id="modtools_type">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>camm15h</othername>
					</author>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Announcements and stickies</title>
			<para>There are various types of topics the forum administrators and moderators (if they have the appropriate permissions) can assign to specific topics. These special topic types are: <guilabel>Global Announcements</guilabel>, <guilabel>Announcements</guilabel>, and <guilabel>Stickies</guilabel>. The <link linkend="posting_special">Topic Type</link> can be chosen when posting a new topic or editing the first post of a previously posted topic. You may choose which type of topic you would prefer by selecting the relevant radio button. When viewing the forum, <guilabel>global announcements</guilabel> and basic <guilabel>announcements</guilabel> are displayed under a separate heading than that of <guilabel>stickies</guilabel> and normal topics.</para>
		</section>
		
		<section id="modtools_split">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>camm15h</othername>
					</author>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Splitting posts off a topic</title>
			<para>Moderators also have the ability to split posts from a topic. This can be useful if certain discussions have spawned a new idea worthy of its own thread, thus needing to be split from the original topic. Splitting posts involves moving individual posts from an existing topic to a new topic. You may do this by using the <guilabel>Quick MOD Tools</guilabel> area beneath the topic you want to split or from the <link linkend="moderator_mcp">Moderator Control Panel</link> within the topic.</para>
			<para>While splitting, you may choose a title for the new topic, a different forum for the new topic, and also a different icon. You may also override the default board settings for the amount of posts to be displayed per page. The <guilabel>Splitting from the selected post</guilabel> option will split all posts from the checked post, to the last post. The <guilabel>Splitting selected posts</guilabel> option will only split the current selected posts. </para>
		</section>
		
		<section id="modtools_mergetopics">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>camm15h</othername>
					</author>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Merge topics</title>
			<para>In phpBB3, it is now possible to merge topics together, in addition to splitting topics. This can be useful if, for example, two separate topics are related and involve the same discussion. The merging topics feature allows existing topics to be merged into one another.</para>
			<para>To merge topics together, start by locating selection menu beneath the topic in question, which brings you to the <link linkend="moderator_mcp">Moderator Control Panel</link>. From here, you need to enter the topic ID of the topic you want to move the posts to. You can click <guilabel>Select topic</guilabel> to see a list of the topics available and specify which. Checking the <guilabel>Mark all</guilabel> section will select all the posts in the current topic and allow moving to the existing topic. The posts merged into the new topic will retain their existing timestamp (e.g. they will not appear at the end of the topic they are being merged to, but will be sorted based on their timestamp).</para>
		</section>
		
		<section id="modtools_mergeposts">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>camm15h</othername>
					</author>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Merge posts into another topic</title>
			<para>Rather than just merging topics together, you can also merge specific posts into any other topic.</para>
			<para>To merge specific posts into another topic, start by locating the selection menu beneath the topic, and get to the <link linkend="moderator_mcp">Moderator Control Panel</link>. From here, you need to enter the topic ID of the topic you want to move the posts to. You can click <guilabel>Select topic</guilabel> to see a list of the topics available and specify which. Select the posts which you wish to merge from the current topic, into the existing topic. The posts merged into the new topic will retain their existing timestamp (e.g. they will not appear at the end of the topic they are being merged to, but will be sorted based on their timestamp).</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	
	<section id="moderator_queue">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>camm15h</othername>
				</author>
				<author>
					<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>What is the &#x201C;Moderation queue&#x201D;?</title>
		<para>The <guilabel>Moderation Queue</guilabel> is an area where topics and posts which need to be approved are listed. If a forum or user&#x2019;s permissions are set to <guilabel>moderator queue</guilabel> via the <link linkend="admin_control_panel">Administration Control Panel</link>, all posts made in that forum or by this user will need to be approved by an administrator or moderator before they are displayed to other users. Topics and posts which require approval can be viewed through the <link linkend="moderator_mcp">Moderator Control Panel</link>.</para>
		<para>When viewing a forum, topics which have not yet been approved will be marked with an icon, clicking on this icon will take you directly to the Moderator Control Panel where you may approve or disapprove the topic. Likewise, when viewing the topic itself, the post requiring approval will be accompanied with a message which also links to the post waiting approval.</para>
		<para>If you choose to approve a topic or post, you will be given the option to notify the user of its approval. If you choose to disapprove a topic or post, you will be given the option to notify the user of its disapproval and also specify why you have disapproved the post, and enter a description.</para>
		<para>For further information regarding the Moderator Control Panel, see <xref linkend="moderator_mcp" />.</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="moderator_reported">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>camm15h</othername>
				</author>
				<author>
					<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>What are &#x201C;Reported posts&#x201D;?</title>
		<para>Unlike phpBB2, phpBB3 now allows users to report a post, for reasons the board administrator can define within the <link linkend="admin_control_panel">Administration Control Panel</link>. If a user finds a post unsuitable for any reason, they may report it using the <guilabel>Report Post</guilabel> button beside the offending message. This report is then displayed within the Moderator Control Panel where the Administrator or Moderators can view, close, or delete the report.</para>
		<para>When viewing a forum with post reports within topics, the topic title will be accompanied by a red exclamation icon. This alerts the administrator(s) or moderators that there a post has been reported. When viewing topics, reported posts are accompanied by a red exclamation and text. Clicking this icon or text will bring them to the Reported Posts section of the Moderator Control Panel.</para>
		<para>For further information regarding the Moderator Control Panel, see <xref linkend="moderator_mcp" />.</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="moderator_mcp">
		<sectioninfo>
			<authorgroup>
				<author>
					<othername>camm15h</othername>
				</author>
				<author>
					<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
				</author>
			</authorgroup>
		</sectioninfo>
		<title>The Moderator Control Panel (MCP)</title>
		<para>Another new feature in phpBB3 is the <guilabel>Moderator Control Panel</guilabel>, where any moderator will feel at home. Similar to the Administration Control Panel, this area outlines any current moderator duties that need to be acted upon. After navigating to the MCP, the moderator will be greeted with any posts waiting for approval, any post reports and the five latest logged actions - performed by administrators, moderators, and users.</para>
		<para>On the left side is a menu containing all the relevant areas within the MCP. This guide outlines each individual section and what kind of information they each contain:
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Main</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>This contains pre-approved posts, reported posts and the five latest logged actions.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Moderation queue</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>This area lists any topics or posts waiting for approval.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Reported posts</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>A list of all open or closed reported posts.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				
				<varlistentry>
					<term>User notes</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>This is an area for administrators or moderators to leave feedback on certain users.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Warnings</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>The ability to warn a user, view current users with warnings and view the five latest warnings.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Moderator logs</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>This is an in-depth list of the five latest actions performed by administrators, moderators or users, as shown on the main page of the MCP.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Banning</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>The option to ban users by username, IP address or email address.</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
		</para>
		
		<section id="mcp_queue">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>camm15h</othername>
					</author>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Moderation queue</title>
			<para>The moderation queue lists topics or posts which require moderator action. The moderation queue is accessible from the <link linkend="moderator_mcp">Moderator Control Panel</link>. For more information regarding the moderation queue, see <xref linkend="moderator_queue" />.</para>
		</section>
		
		<section id="mcp_reported">
			<sectioninfo>
				<authorgroup>
					<author>
						<othername>camm15h</othername>
					</author>
					<author>
						<othername>MennoniteHobbit</othername>
					</author>
				</authorgroup>
			</sectioninfo>
			<title>Reported posts</title>
			<para>Reported posts are reports submitted by users regarding problematic posts. Any current reported posts are accessible from the <link linkend="moderator_mcp">Moderator Control Panel</link>. For more information regarding reported posts, see <xref linkend="moderator_reported" />.</para>
		</section>
		
		<section id="mcp_forum">
			<title>Forum moderation</title>
			<para>When viewing any particular forum, clicking <guilabel>Moderator Control Panel</guilabel> will take you to the forum moderation area. Here, you are able to mass moderate topics within that forum via the dropdown box. The available actions are:
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Delete</guilabel>: Deletes the selected topic(s).</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Move</guilabel>: Moves the selected topic(s) to another forum of your preference.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Fork</guilabel>: Creates a duplicate of the selected topic(s) in another forum of your preference.</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Lock</guilabel>: Locks the selected topic(s).</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Unlock</guilabel>: Unlocks the selected topic(s).</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Resync</guilabel>: Resynchronise the selected topic(s).</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para><guilabel>Change topic type</guilabel>: Change the topic type to either <guilabel>Global Announcement</guilabel>, <guilabel>Announcement</guilabel>, <guilabel>Sticky</guilabel>, or <guilabel>Regular Topic</guilabel>.</para></listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</para>
			
			<para>You can also mass-moderate posts within topics. This can be done by navigating through the MCP when viewing the forum, and clicking on the topic itself. Another way to accomplish this is to click the MCP link whilst viewing the particular topic you wish to moderate.</para>
			<para>When moderating inside a topic, you can: rename the topic title, move the topic to a different forum, alter the topic icon, merge the topic with another topic, or define how many posts per page will be displayed (this will override the board setting).</para>
			<para>From the selection menu, you may also: lock and unlock individual posts, delete the selected post(s), merge the selected post(s), or split or split from the selected post(s).</para>
			<para>The <guilabel>Post Details</guilabel> link next to posts also entitle you to alter other settings. As well as viewing the poster&#x2019;s <glossterm>IP address</glossterm>, profile and notes, and the ability to warn the poster, you also have the option to change the poster ID assigned to the post. You can also lock or delete the post from this page.</para>
		
			<note>
				<para>Depending on the specific permissions set to your user account, some of the aforementioned options and abilities may not be available to you.</para>
			</note>
			
			<para>For further information regarding the Moderator Control Panel, see <xref linkend="moderator_mcp" />.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
